<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-04T17:23:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My new photography YouTube channel]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-11T11:23:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello friends!  It’s been a while without an update.</p>

<p>I’ve been working more and more on my photography endeavors, which includes building up a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCg5jVvaChTjkL74IQ334FzQ">YouTube channel</a> to document my travels and also my learnings.  I’m hoping it’s interesting and useful enough, especially for other aspiring photographers.</p>

<p>This year is definitely shaping up to be a year of travelling, and I’d also like to keep a blog of photos and such, so I’m working to get a separate photography blog setup at <a href="https://davidcalhounphotography.com">my photography website</a>.  I’m hoping to get that up soon, as I’m already falling behind!  And I have a trip to Japan coming up next week already!</p>

<p>Anyhow, here’s a few recent videos you can check out.</p>

<p>From my recent trip to Edinburgh.  I didn’t take much video footage, but was able to put together a quick video with what I had.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2lUHx6l4DvQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Big Bear Lake in the snow.  Just the tail end of the winter season, so I had to take advantage and get out a bit!</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i40R_zkPjg8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>A lazy winter photography test run in my backyard.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ItT7Z3ozmRM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Right now my channel is in its very humble beginnings, but I’m still working on getting good content there, and learning to edit my videos better and better as I progress.  Turns out I’m learning photography and a bit of videography and editing as well!</p>

<p>Please check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCg5jVvaChTjkL74IQ334FzQ">my channel</a> and subscribe!  I promise a TON more adventures just in the coming year.  Here’s what’s already booked:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Japan (March)</li>
  <li>Atlanta (April)</li>
  <li>Yosemite, Sequoia, Crater Lake road trip with Mark (May)</li>
  <li>Copenhagen and Norway (May/June)</li>
  <li>New Orleans (July)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My year in photos (2016)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T23:17:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014/">part one</a> and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014-part-2/">part two</a>).  I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!</p>

<p>Onto the pics!</p>

<h2 id="february">February</h2>

<p>I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-01-feb-yosemite-night-sky.jpg 1000 666 Night sky from Yosemite %}</p>

<p>For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.  I was super happy with the way this turned out.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-02-feb-pinecrest-lake-in-snow.jpg 1000 666 Pinecrest Lake in the snow (California, near Yosemite) %}</p>

<p>Interesting tree stumps around Pinecrest Lake area, in the snow.</p>

<h2 id="march">March</h2>

<p>At the end of March, I quit my job and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again/">ended up in Japan again</a> for the next few months!</p>

<p>One of my favorite photos from the entire several months was taken from the first night at the hotel.  I had a corner room in the Star Gate hotel, which towers over south Osaka and has a great view of the Kansai International Airport.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-03-march-kansai-international-airport.jpg 666 1000 Kansai International Airport seen from the Star Gate Hotel in Osaka, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-04-march-kyoto-sparrow-and-cherry-blossoms.jpg 666 1000 Sparrow and cherry blossoms on the Path of Philosophy in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<h2 id="april">April</h2>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-05-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-06-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-07-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-08-april-kyoto-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto backstreets at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-09-april-nara-monju-e-ceremony.jpg 1000 666 Nara Monju-e Ceremony %}</p>

<p>(<a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara/">see more photos and video from the Nara Monju-e Ceremony</a>)</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-10-april-nara-deer-and-lantern.jpg 666 1000 Nara deer and traditional lantern %}</p>

<p>I’ve always wanted to ride the shinkansen (bullet train) as far north as I could, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/">I finally did it</a>.  I boarded the bullet train in Kyoto and ended up at its terminus in Hakodate.  The final stretch of bullet train to Hakodate had only opened days before, and they were still celebrating its completion.</p>

<p>They’re currently building the final stretch from Hakodate to Sapporo, but it’s not due to be complete until sometime in the 2030s or so.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-11-april-rainy-shinkansen.jpg 1000 666 Rainy day on the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-12-april-northern-japan-coast.jpg 1000 666 The coast of northern Japan, seen from the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>This isn’t a super great photo, but I thought it was interesting for a few reasons.  There were these stone markers occassionally by the tracks.  And there was also a whole lot of trash, mostly fisherman trash like baubles.</p>

<p>Kind of surprising how much trash was along the coast here, especially for Japan’s reputation for cleanliness.  Was this remants of the 2011 tsunami?  Well, it’s five years later and this stuff is still here…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-13-april-hakodate-sunset.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate sunset %}</p>

<p>Hakodate is a fun little town.  Of course I had to take the tram up to the top of Mount Hakodate, then watch the sunset with all the other tourists…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-14-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-15-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view - the reality of the crowds.  Absolutely packed. %}</p>

<p>Mount Hakodate at sunset was swarming with tourists.  I’m glad I did it once, but I wouldn’t do it again.</p>

<p>Around Hakodate there was this trendy hamburger place called Lucky Pierrot, which looked more like a carnival.  They had some interesting vending machines propped up outside their shop.  Looked like something out of a video game:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-16-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-17-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>Sapporo was still a bit snowy in April!</p>

<p>…And I was totally unprepared.  I took some photos, then had to duck inside somewhere to warm up.  I found a mall with some ramen restaurants and a Uniqlo - both of which had things that could help me warm up.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-18-april-sapporo-ramen.jpg 666 1000 Delicious Sapporo ramen %}</p>

<h2 id="may">May</h2>

<p>In May I visited Indonesia with Yuka, but I was too afraid to bring my DSLR, which was a stupid idea in retrospect.  I took some video there, and took lots of photos with my phone, which I guess I’ll have to post eventually.</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/the-roads-of-indonesia/">Here you can watch a Muslim parade</a>, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/indonesia-trip-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/">here you can listen to me ramble on about my experience in Indonesia</a>.</p>

<p>When I came back to Japan, it was time to explore some more!</p>

<p>I returned to Byodoin Temple in Nara, which had been restored to its original vermillion colors since my last visit a few years back:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-19-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-20-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-21-may-kyoto-aqua-marine-diving-school.jpg 1000 666 Aqua Marine Diving School (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>This probably isn’t a super interesting photo for you, but I actually walked past this, then thought better of it and walked back to snap a photo, because I thought it was just interesting.  It jumped out again for me when going through my photos, so I had to include it among my favorites just for the subject matter.  The hiragana reads “Diving School”.</p>

<p>Yuka had been wanting to take me up to Mount Rokko for a while.  It was a fun experience riding the cable car to the top, then eating some good food at the top.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-22-may-mount-rokko-cable-car.jpg 666 1000 Accidental self-portrait, and a view from the Mount Rokko cable car (Osaka, Japan) %}</p>

<h2 id="june">June</h2>

<p>In June I tried something new: I gave myself a photo assignment.  Just to go out on a mission, and come back with some tangible decent photos.</p>

<p>I know Kyoto is amazing at night, with lots of things to discover in the nooks and crannies of the city I’ve spent the last few years exploring.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-23-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-24-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 1000 666 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>I posted a few more photos from my Kyoto photo assignment <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/">here</a>.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-25-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>I had mixed emotions about visiting Shirakawago, a UNESCO World Heritage site with a bunch of interesting old thatched houses.  The place was incredibly touristy, and I had a run-in with some pushy Japanese grandmas who unabashedly cut in line in front of me at a gift shop.</p>

<p>It was an interesting place - I may be back eventually in the winter, which is the more common time to take photos of the truly interesting old-fashioned houses.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-26-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-27-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-28-june-kamogawa-sparrows.jpg 1000 666 Sparrows playing beside the Kamogawa (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>I brought my DSLR to a short weekend trip to Busan with Yuka, but didn’t take many good photos there.  I did like this one shot of a cute dog in a traditional market though:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-29-june-dog-in-korea.jpg 666 1000 Cute dog (Busan, Korea) %}</p>

<h2 id="october">October</h2>

<p>Back in the US!</p>

<p>I took a few road trips, especially to capture the changing seasons in California.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-30-oct-june-lake-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains seen from June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-31-oct-june-lake.jpg 1000 666 Boat docked at June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32-oct-mono-lake-alien-moonrise.jpg 1000 666 Alien moonrise on the shores of Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32b-oct-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Mono Lake at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-33-oct-mountains-view-from-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowy mountains at night, seen from Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-34-oct-lake-sabrina-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains at Lake Sabrina %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-35-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Lundy Lake sunrise %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-36-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowcapped mountains seen from Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-37-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors along Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-38-oct-road-to-lobdell-lake-fall-colors.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors on the road to Lobdell Lake (California) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-39-oct-drive-back-to-san-bernardino-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Intense storm clouds seen on the drive back to the San Bernardino mountains %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-40-oct-fall-leaves-in-big-bear.jpg 1000 666 Fall leaves on a brick walkway, at home in Big Bear %}</p>

<h2 id="november">November</h2>

<p>My mom spontaneously booked a trip to New Orleans, and I agreed to tag along.  It was a nice return to a truly interesting city.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-41-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 The lobby of the W Hotel French Quarter (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-42-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square seen from the steamboat Natchez, on the Missisippi River %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-43-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Chartres %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-44-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 “At Rest” gravestone in a New Orleans cemetery %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-45-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Statue near the French Market: Michelle by sculptor Paul Perret (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-46-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square at night with the largest supermoon in decades (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-47-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 S. Andral Kilmer, M.D. Swamp Root medicine at the LSU Rural Life Museum  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-48-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Swamp trees in Louisiana %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-49-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Turtle sunbathing on the swamp %}</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/">See more photos from my New Orleans trip</a>.</p>

<h2 id="december">December</h2>

<p>One last road trip of the year!  Just before Christmas, I took a drive to Zion National Park.  I am definitely returning to this beautiful place, and I’m already planning future hikes and photo shoots here.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-50-dec-desert-near-baker.jpg 1000 666 Desert sunset, near Baker, Nevada %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-51-dec-zion.jpg 666 1000 Sandstone and ice (Zion National Park) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-52-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-53-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty Towers of the Virgin mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-54-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Orleans trip (November 2016)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-21T11:51:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I had the opportunity to visit New Orleans in the spring with my friend.  Now I’ve returned with my parents to visit in the fall!</p>

<p>My mom had recently expressed a desire to do more travelling while still physically able, which kicked off creating a list of places to visit, and ultimately booking this first trip.  Hopefully the first of many to come.  She asked if I wanted to tag along, and I couldn’t pass up another visit to the city.  I also thought I could help out a bit, since I’d already visited the city before.</p>

<p>On to the photos!</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-01.jpg 666 1000 No visit is complete without trying out some beignets!  From Cafe Beignet on Bourbon Street. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-02.jpg 1000 666 Al “Jumbo” Hirt Jazz statue at Cafe Beignet. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-03.jpg 666 1000 Grave of Marie Laveau, Queen of Voodoo.  Note the barely visible “XXX” marks. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-04.jpg 666 1000 Unique vertical tomb style, stacked five caskets high. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-05.jpg 1000 666 Nicholas Cage’s future resting place.  Not joking. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-06.jpg 1000 666 Cemetery %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-07.jpg 1000 666 Angel statue, melted by time (and acid rain) %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-08.jpg 1000 666 Statue near the French Market: Michelle by sculptor Paul Perret %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-09.jpg 666 1000 Joan of Arc statue %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-10.jpg 666 1000 “At Rest” from Cypress Grove Cemetery %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-11.jpg 1000 666 Swamp tree %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-12.jpg 1000 666 Turtles sunbathing in a swamp %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-13.jpg 1000 666 Alligator in a swamp %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-14.jpg 1000 666 Spider in a swamp.  The tour guide got close to this one and rubbed its belly with his bare hands.  “You know you’re in Louisiana when they tickle the spiders” said one fellow tourist. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-15.jpg 1000 666 Great Blue Heron %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-16.jpg 1000 666 Swamp trees %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-17.jpg 1000 666 The bayou with another tourist riverboat in view. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-18.jpg 1000 666 Alligators %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-19.jpg 1000 666 Alligator hiding underwater %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-20.jpg 1000 666 New Orleans skyline at sunset. %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-21.jpg 666 1000 Benito Juarez statue %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-22.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad on Bourbon Street.  My mom was on the phone with my sister, who was trying to get a screen grab of us on a street webcam. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-23.jpg 1000 666 Segway tours trailing a horse and carriage %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-24.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-25.jpg 1000 666 Aboard the Natchez Steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-26.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square seen from the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-27.jpg 1000 666 Speed control on the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-28.jpg 1000 666 Closeup from the engine room of the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-29.jpg 1000 666 Closeup from the engine room of the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-30.jpg 1000 666 View down the street %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-31.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Santa Ana %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-32.jpg 1000 666 Balcony in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-33.jpg 666 1000 Hot sauce paradise %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-34.jpg 666 1000 Building in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-35.jpg 1000 666 Balcony in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-36.jpg 1000 666 Acme Oyster House %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-37.jpg 1000 666 Chargrileld Oysters from Acme Oyster House %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-38.jpg 1000 666 Jazz band in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-39.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad in front of some shady establishments on Bourbon Street %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-40.jpg 1000 666 Great colors in the driveway of our hotel (The W Hotel) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-41.jpg 666 1000 W Hotel courtyard at night %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-42.jpg 1000 666 Andrew Jackson statue at night %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-43.jpg 1000 666 Steamboat Natchez at sunrise %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-44.jpg 1000 666 Sunrise on the Mississipi River - taken standing on the levee %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-45.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Chartres.  This was the street our hotel was on, so we got to know its name well! %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-46.jpg 666 1000 Spanish moss %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-47.jpg 1000 666 Slave prison, from the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-48.jpg 1000 666 Teche Mamou Genuine Mentholated Cough Syrup %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-49.jpg 1000 666 S. Andral Kilmer, M.D. Swamp Root %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-50.jpg 1000 666 Poor folks’ church in the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-51.jpg 1000 666 Painted windows instead of stained windows at the poor folks’ church in the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-52.jpg 1000 666 Creepy statue in the cemetery at the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-53.jpg 1000 666 Crab and Crawfish Au Gratin from Parrain’s Seafood Restaurant in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-54.jpg 1000 666 Andouille Encrusted Fresh Fish from Parrain’s Seafood Restaurant in Baton Rouge %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photo assignment: Kyoto alleyways at night]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-14T06:15:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before setting off on my current trip, I wanted to give myself at least one “photo assignment”: some goal I could aim to accomplish by pretending like I’d been given an assignment by some employer.</p>

<p>This is the first of what I hope will be many.  The assignment here is to try to capture the atmosphere of eastern Kyoto’s traditional streets at night.</p>

<p>A couple of things I had to plan for: Kyoto is a bit far from my hostel in Osaka, so I made sure to make a day trip out of it.  Also, I wanted preferably a somewhat rainy day, which would make the ground more reflective.</p>

<p>One more thing: the more shots during magic hour, the better.  The sky ends up a lot more beautiful that way.</p>

<p>Ok go, let’s have a look at what I ended up with!</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-1.jpg 666 1000 Walking up the path towards Hokan-ji Temple (Yasaka-no-to, Yasaka Pagoda) (法観寺五重塔)  %}</p>

<p>Walking uphill through the shops that are just closing, approaching the pagoda.  Not quite magic hour yet.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-2.jpg 1000 666 Vending machines lighting up the path  %}</p>

<p>The light the the vending machines is completely blown out.  I took some bracketed shots of this, but I don’t want to deal with the HDR right now… maybe later.</p>

<p>Just a funny note: instead of the RAW file, I actually ended up postprocessing the HDR JPG for this one accidentally.  Took me a while, but I finally corrected my mistake when I was seeing weird artifacts appearing.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-3.jpg 666 981 Looking down on Ninenzaka Street (二年坂)  %}</p>

<p>I had a tough time trying to crop this one.  The posters on the right side are interesting and I wanted to zoom in more on them, but couldn’t find a way to make it work.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-4.jpg 1000 666 Hydrangeas on Ninenzaka Street (二年坂)  %}</p>

<p>Some hydrangeas on a wet street.  This is more like it, this is the kinda shot I came here to take!  There really was no one around at this time.  Most of the folks in the area were camped out with tripods to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/4mq25f/i_took_a_picture_of_a_quiet_street_at_night_in/">duplicate a shot they had seen on reddit</a> (which I ended up doing later…).</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-5.jpg 666 1000 Street near Hokan-ji Temple (Yasaka-no-to, Yasaka Pagoda) (法観寺五重塔)  %}</p>

<p>Not sure about the composition here, in terms of the balance.  But I liked the design of the window on the left.  Reminded me of something elven, like it came out of the Lord of the Rings.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-6.jpg 1000 666 Bar Main Higashiyama Kyoto  %}</p>

<p>Before I took the following shot, a bartender dressed in fancy clothes skurried past to return after his break.  Actually wasn’t so sure about this photo was worth taking when I was here, but it ended up turning out pretty well!</p>

<p>The bluish light cast a nice reflection on the still-wet ground.  Quick, keep snapping pictures before it dries up!</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-06-15-photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night-7.jpg 1000 666 Shōren-in gate （青蓮院門跡） %}</p>

<p>The ground dried up by the time I made it here…</p>

<p>I remember crowds up people lined up around here at New Year’s 2013, waiting to ring in the New Year by ringing the bell at the nearby Chion-in temple (知恩院).  It was a cold night, and I ended up bailing out of the line after more than an hour of waiting.</p>

<p>This time I revisited on a warm night, with kind of a creepy atmosphere with no one around.  There was just this imposing gate dimly lit, with signs explaining that it’s closed for the day.  If you look closely, you can even see a little security camera up there.</p>

<p>I ended up walking through a LOT of Kyoto late at night this night.  I walked up to the Path of Philosophy and saw a few fireflies on the way.</p>

<p>I eventually went up to Hyakumanben neighborhood, to the delicious Tenkaippin ramen place near where I used to live and go to school..  had delicious “stamina ramen” with kotteri broth with a ton of other folks around 11:30pm, then ended up walking back towards the Kamogawa only to realize that the trains were out of service for the night.</p>

<p>Ended up walking back to my hotel near Kyoto station, but not before passing even more fireflies by the Kamogawa.  Returned to my hotel around 2am or so… this was a fun night, really reminiscint of that first time I quit my job to come live here for the summer.</p>

<p>Where I sometimes wandered around aimlessly at night, thinking what in the world I was doing here.  Never imagined I’d return here five years later to do the exact same thing, to be at the exact same point in life with seemingly no progress made whatsoever.</p>

<p>I came here not without a purpose this time, but it looks like my time here is almost at an end, and I still have no answer.</p>

<p>For better or worse, it’s time to keep wandering.  I will try to take pictures while I keep wandering!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shinkansen trip from Kyoto to Sapporo]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-17T19:25:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-rinku-town-kansai-airport-kix-at-night.jpg 1000 666 Rinku town and Kansai Airport at night %}</p>

<p>(I wrote this one a few weeks back but didn’t post the pics until now, so here it is in its complete form!).</p>

<p>I’ve been here in Japan for a month and in true form haven’t provided much in the way of updates since then.  Doh.</p>

<p>Here’s a catch-up post, with plenty of pictures and videos to keep things interesting.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-cherry-blossom-1.jpg 1000 666 Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-cherry-blossom-2.jpg 1000 666 Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy %}</p>

<p>Spring in Japan again!  I was really happy to use jetlag to my advantage and wake up super early while staying in Kyoto, where I was able to walk over to a few areas that turned out to be almost empty, but were sure to get crowded later.  I’ve found that this trick always works if you’re willing to wake up early enough - this also worked for Yosemite, a place as crowded as Disneyland.  Except the trick there was to wake up before dawn…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-path-of-philosophy-cherry-blossoms-1.jpg 666 1000 Cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-path-of-philosophy-cherry-blossoms-2.jpg 666 1000 Cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-path-of-philosophy-cherry-blossoms-and-sparrow.jpg 666 1000 Sparrow eating cherry blossoms at the Path of Philosophy %}</p>

<p>Anyhow, I really felt that one stroll through the fairly empty Path of Philosophy early in the morning was enough to satisfy me for the entire trip.  I felt super happy, and was lucky to get some video of a fairly empty Path of Philosophy, around 7am or so.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jtq7pfeXhh0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>With every passing hour it was noticeably getting more crowded, so my plan from there was to escape and head down for a walk along the Kamo river (Kamogawa), which is big enough that it never feels super crowded.  It was also a good chance to revisit old favorite cafes like efish.  Can’t beat Kyoto coffee culture!</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-kamogawa-cherry-blossoms-1.jpg 666 1000 Cherry blossom along the Kamogawa %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-kamogawa-cherry-blossoms-2.jpg 1000 666 Cherry blossom along the Kamogawa, with Kyoto Tower in the background %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-kyoto-bridge-bus.jpg 1000 666 Kamogawa river near Kyoto station, with a bus in the middle of a bridge %}</p>

<p>After this I realized that I was pretty satisfied, and maybe even burnt out on crowds.  I really felt like getting out if Kyoto, so I cancelled some hotels (with 100% refund, really easy to do when you book through Expedia).  I realized that I got really burned out on tourists a lot sooner than I hoped.  Knowing full well that I myself am a tourist of course, and that I’m contributing to the problem…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-shinkansen-route.png 455 303 The planned crazy Shinkansen route, to fully take advantage of my JR Pass like never before %}</p>

<p>But this burnout happened to have good timing.  I found out that Yuka was briefly headed to China for work, so it was a good time to activate my weeklong JR Pass and do something I’ve always wanted to do: abuse it as much as possible, traveling as far in one direction as I could.  I always thought it would be fun to travel north to Hokkaido by shinkansen, and by good coincidence it turns out this wasn’t possible until the end of this March this year, when a stretch of track was just opened that went all the way to Hakodate.  My eventual goal was to arrive at Sapporo by shinkansen, but that final stretch is still being constructed.  But no worries, there was an express train there instead.</p>

<p>On the first day of my JR Pass adventure, I made an escape from Kyoto and headed northeast.  I only stopped briefly in Tokyo to change shinkansen trains, then I was off again to Furukawa, a sleepy town just north of Sendai.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lff7ZQff8uE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I’d randomly chosen to stop here before on a previous trip and enjoyed the slower pace.  The town itself doesn’t really have much to offer, but that’s ok.  I also knew that hotels were super cheap all around northern Japan - about 5000 yen ($45) for a decent business hotel with a good breakfast included.  I could definitely stretch my money a lot further compared to more expensive and touristy places like Kyoto.  I discovered a good business hotel chain there: Hotel Route Inn, which seems to serve all of northern Japan.</p>

<p>The next leg of the trip was from Furukawa to Hakodate, a small town in Hokkaido.  Being in Hokkaido, this means the shinkansen ran out of land and would either have to go over or under the water to get to the island of Hokkaido.  Disappointingly, it turned out to be under water: vast stretches of the trip that were in boring tunnels.  I suppose the option to build a bridge would’ve provided a beautiful sight for passengers, at the expense of a maintenance nightmare, as this would mean repair crews would have to battle the harsh winters, exposed out on a bridge over the ocean.  I wouldn’t be surprised if most of the eventual Hakodate to Sapporo track will be underground for the same reason.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-hakodate-manhole-cover.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate manhole cover in black and white.  There are more colorful versions through the city, but I didn’t see them on this trip. %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-hakodate-street-at-dusk.jpg 1000 660 Hakodate streetcars at dusk %}</p>

<p>Hakodate was nice, although the touted night view from Mt. Hakodate was overcrowded with tourists.  Especially Chinese tourists for some reason.  I think the night view of city by the sea, with mountains in the background, is hard to beat.  It’s worth seeing once though.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BnVWKKG6H78" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-hakodate-sunset.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate beautiful sunset behind mountains, almost looks like a Hawaiian sunset %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-hakodate-night-view-1.jpg 1000 666 The famed Hakodate night view %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-hakodate-night-view-2.jpg 1000 666 What it’s really like trying to get a picture of the Hakodate night view.  Way too many people for comfort. %}</p>

<p>The last leg of the journey was from Hakodate to Sapporo on an express train.  Not quite a shinkansen, so the trip covered comparatively little ground, but the train was nice and was setup nicely inside with assigned seats, tray tables for food, nice storage areas.  It was an express train trying its hardest to be a shinkansen.</p>

<p>I didn’t mind the comparative slowness of this express train actually: the countryside here was probably the most beautiful part of the trainride, with ocean views and interesting forests and mountains with interesting shapes in the distance.</p>

<p>One thing that did surprise me about this stretch was that although the view of the ocean water very near the track was beautiful, there were vast stretches where pieces of trash had washed up on shore.  There must’ve been thousands of fishing baubles and other random debris washed up there.  I wondered to myself if it had always been like that, or if it was lingering trash from the tsunami five years before?  Maybe no one cared about cleaning it up because these towns were out in the middle of nowhere.  It is a shame though, since so much trash could be seen from the train.  I would think even JR (the train company) might have an incentive to sponsor a beachside cleanup, to beautify the view for its passengers along this stretch?</p>

<p>I finally made it to Sapporo and stayed for two nights.  It’s a big city but doesn’t feel overcrowded like other Japanese cities.  Maybe because it was freezing outside - literally.  There was sleet and snow while I was walking around - very strong bursts at times.  I didn’t plan well for this - all I had packed that would help against this was a windbreaker.</p>

<p>It became too cold and soon it became clear I needed to take a building-by-building strategy, from heated building to another heated building.</p>

<p>Canon photo gallery?  Ok why not, I like Canon.  And it’s warm.  When I eventually left, I made it a block or two until I got too cold, and saw the next building to go into.</p>

<p>A bookstore?  Oh sure, I like books.  And it’s warm.  Oh, I forget that I’m illiterate here.  English books are hard to find…</p>

<p>Ok, exit and walk another block through the sleet.  7-11?  Hmm sure, I’m sure I could buy some random junkfood or something there.  And it’s warm there.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-sapporo-711-snow.jpg 666 892 A Sapporo 7-11 while it started snowing.  I definitely stepped into this 7-11 for some warm comfort. %}</p>

<p>Walk a little further and see a Tully’s Coffee. Ok why not, I like coffee.  And it’s warm.</p>

<p>Eventually I realized that having some insulation would be nice, if even for the day or two I was up there.  I found some department stores, but the clothes were either too strange and peculiarly Japanese (and too small), or too foreign and therefore expensive.  $700 jacket from Henry Cottens Italy?  No thanks, that’s more than I’m paying for rent here in Osaka (my rent is 50000 yen, less than $500).</p>

<p>I settled for some long underwear and undershirt from Uniqlo, then put them on in a bathroom.  Now I could go out and take pictures in the snow!</p>

<p>But unfortunately I kind of squandered my opportunity to take interesting snowy city pictures of Sapporo.  I was walking around all day with my 24mm lens, which is a difficult focal length to work with.  Should’ve probably stuck with my trusty 50mm.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-04-26-sapporo-ramen.jpg 666 1000  Delicious Sapporo ramen %}</p>

<p>On this trip I also learned to pack a bit smarter.  On previous trips I’d brought a massive suitcase and packed way too much stuff.  I remember one longterm trip where I’d packed a flatbed photo scanner, just because I could really.  And I thought I needed it, to scan forms that I needed to sign or something.  I’m still not entirely sure what I was thinking.</p>

<p>I guess way back then I learned that packing a massive suitcase was somewhat doable but a real hassle, especially when transporting it from place to place.  For instance, when traveling on the shinkansen you can only hope that there’s space at the back of the traincar to store the suitcase.  There’s some limited space there, and it turns out not to be an issue, but it’s far more convenient to have multiple bags which can be broken down and stored in the overhead compartment (kinda like an airplane, but uncovered), which is what I did this trip.</p>

<p>Another hassle of super large bags is that they can only be stored in super large coin lockers, which are hard to find and more limited.  Also, good luck trying to find one during this time of year, which is the most popular time to visit…</p>

<p>Anyhow, the moral of the story is that on this trip I traveled smarter.  Of course the less the better, so I think I could definitely improve it still.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
