<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-09T11:43:05-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick style comparison of mobile image search sites]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/comparison-of-mobile-image-search-sites"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/comparison-of-mobile-image-search-sites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I glanced at a classmate using <a href="http://www.baidu.com/">Baidu</a> to perform an image search and was impressed with their presentation:</p>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/baidu-mobile-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/baidu-mobile-image-search.jpg" alt="Baidu mobile image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1163" /></a></p>

<p>Note the nice big images and the lack of margins around images. After seeing this presentation, I realized that the common approach of adding margins around images is pretty unnecessary.</p>

<p>I also noticed that the images are a variety of sizes, leading to a less sterile experience. There’s surely some clever math going on behind the scenes here to make sure the images appear “justified” (to use a word from the recent Flickr redesign).</p>

<h3 id="google">Google</h3>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/google-mobile-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/google-mobile-image-search.jpg" alt="Google mobile image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1166" /></a></p>

<p>Note the smaller photos, which sometimes causes features on images to be indiscernable.</p>

<p>Also note the more common approach of adding margins around the images. This seems to remove a lot of space which could otherwise be used to show more details of images, which is the approach Baidu takes.</p>

<h3 id="bing">Bing</h3>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/bing-mobile-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/bing-mobile-image-search.jpg" alt="Bing mobile image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1169" /></a></p>

<p>Bing uses a nicely-designed slick interface with a black background, which I tend to like a bit better.</p>

<p>However, all its images are cropped or resized to be exactly the same size, leading to a more sterile gridlike experience.</p>

<p>Also, just a minor complaint, but the search magnifying glass appears to be a tiny bit blurry, especially compared to the sharpness of the Bing logo. But it’s barely noticeable, especially compared to Yahoo (below).</p>

<h3 id="yahoo">Yahoo!</h3>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/yahoo-mobile-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/yahoo-mobile-image-search.jpg" alt="Yahoo mobile image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1167" /></a></p>

<p>Yahoo has nice big images, actually a bit too big. Bit it also appears to suffer from the approach Bing uses to resize photos to make their dimensions exactly the same.</p>

<p>Again note the common white margins around the images.</p>

<p>The non-retina top graphics (logo and search button) are so blurry and distracting that I have to at least mention them here. These images look blurry on every modern phone on the market today, and it’s sad to me that neither developers nor QA cared enough about this to do something about it.</p>

<p>Strangely, these images look fine on the main “Web” tab, but they are distractingly blurry on this Images view as well as others.</p>

<h3 id="flickr-mobile-app-ios">Flickr mobile app (iOS)</h3>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/flickr-mobile-app-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/flickr-mobile-app-image-search.jpg" alt="Flickr mobile app image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1164" /></a></p>

<p>The Flickr app itself has some decently-sized images, but here again we see the image margins at work. This is also present on the “justified view” on the desktop site, so I suppose they wanted to be consistent.</p>

<h3 id="flickr-mobile-web">Flickr mobile web</h3>

<p><a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/flickr-mobile-web-image-search.jpg"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/flickr-mobile-web-image-search.jpg" alt="Flickr mobile web image search" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1165" /></a></p>

<p>This is certainly the worst out of the bunch. It’s a real waste of space, with small images sacrificed for textual information that’s a little excessive for this screen.</p>

<p>I think this is just due to the website’s age. Flickr’s mobile website is much neglected and is showing its age. I would be really nice to see updates to match the nice progress they’ve made with the “justified layout” that you can see on their desktop site and mobile app.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Response to &#8220;What’s next for mobile now that adaptive design has failed?&#8221;]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/response-to-whats-next-for-mobile-now-that-adaptive-design-has-failed"/>
    <updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/response-to-whats-next-for-mobile-now-that-adaptive-design-has-failed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There’s been a flurry of response to <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/22/adaptive-design-has-failed/">this article, entitled “What’s next for mobile now that adaptive design has failed?”</a>.</p>

<p>There’s many problems with this article, so it’s hard to know where to start.</p>

<p>I will admit that defenders of responsive design have come out of the woodwork in trashing this article, but I suppose I count myself among them, being a proponent of responsive design. I still see the web heading that direction, and I definitely don’t see it heading in the direction the author of the article has described.</p>

<h3 id="adaptive--responsive">Adaptive != Responsive</h3>

<p>Like others have said, adaptive isn’t the same as responsive. I hate that both have become buzzwords to be thrown around by execs, but they should at least be used appropriately. (see <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/answers/technology/web-development/TCH_WDD/961492-23942997">this page</a> for a good discussion of the differences). This article conflates the two.</p>

<p>I’ll assume for the purpose of this argument that we’re referring to responsive design.</p>

<h3 id="unproven-assumption-responsive-design-has-failed">Unproven assumption: responsive design has failed</h3>

<p>There’s an assumption that responsive design has failed, but no argument for it, which means by the end of the article it remains an assumption. I’ll assume its purpose was solely as an attention-seeking headline. Not much more to be said there, so let’s pass over it.</p>

<h3 id="tablets--magazines-vertical-scroll--bad-pagination--good">Tablets = Magazines?, Vertical Scroll = Bad?, Pagination = Good?</h3>

<p>There’s an assumption that users equate tablets to magazines, and therefore expect to swipe through pages. I believe there’s some sort of interaction or deal the author has with Pressly (which he mentions and has retweeted on Twitter), so I can understand why they’d be pushing their agenda and usage model, which is very much of the “iPad-magazine-page-flip” sort.</p>

<p>But there’s a reason pagination is still an optional feature not turned on by default in apps such as Instapaper: it’s because users are very familiar and comfortable with vertical scrolling of content on the web, and possibly in some cases more comfortable than a page-based format. They are as comfortable with vertical scrolling as the author would say they are with turning the pages of a magazine.</p>

<p>I’m the age where I’ve seen the decline of newspapers and magazines and am actually more comfortable with a vertical-scrolling interface as opposed to a page-flipping interface as older folks might be used to in magazines.</p>

<p>Just because the interaction model worked for an older medium doesn’t mean it’ll work or is even the best for new mediums. If that were true, we’d still have rotary dial inputs on our touchscreen phones, simply because some phone exec insisted that users were more familiar and comfortable with the rotary dial interaction model.</p>

<h3 id="users-love-those-full-screen-ads">Users Love Those Full-Screen Ads</h3>

<p>Users do NOT like full-screen ads. To think otherwise can be very rightly said to be a delusion of grandeur. Go to the app store, look at the iPad CNET app reviews, and tell me that users are thrilled about seeing a full-screen ad pop over their content when they open the app. Quite the opposite, that turns out to be the main complaint by a long shot, or at least it was for a long while after the app was released. I know. I was there to see it happen, and to see a blind eye turned toward the problem.</p>

<h3 id="successful-advertising--successful-user-experience">Successful advertising != Successful User Experience</h3>

<p>Advertising isn’t a gauge of user experience. This is the hubris and the downfall of CBS and anyone who believes otherwise. More ad revenue means more aggressive ads, more fullscreen ads, and more ways to trick the user into clicking ads. This is the opposite of a good user experience. The real user base isn’t there to click on ads – they’re there to read content, and everything else is a distraction. This is the catch-22 of this model, and those that don’t see that will never know they need to toe the line and maintain a delicate balance. Worst of all, those who completely miss the point will mistake successful advertising with a successful user experience (which here is as easily conflated as adaptive and responsive design have been).</p>

<p>Sometimes companies don’t realize there’s a point of no return when ads (which are necessary in some minimal form) become too distracting and actually make it more difficult to get to content, resulting in users abandoning the site in the long term, or taking measures to churn the site through AdBlock or Instapaper or other measures that preserve the content, while discarding the distracting bits (usually ads and other tricks to get the user to stay on the site longer by showing “related content”, which is ultimately a way to trick the user into staying to view more ads).</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes: Mobile Web Design (Cameron Moll, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/notes-mobile-web-design-cameron-moll-200"/>
    <updated>2011-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/notes-mobile-web-design-cameron-moll-200</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="what8217s-this">What’s this?</h3>

<p>These are some notes I collect as I read through Cameron Moll’s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mobile-Web-Design-Cameron-Moll/dp/0615185916">Mobile Web Design</a>.</p>

<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Further info:</li>
</ol>

<p>Designing the Mobile User Experience (Barbara Ballard)  <br />
dotMobi Web Developer’s Guide (dev.mobi)  <br />
Global Authoring Practices for the Mobile Web (Luca Passani) (passani.it/gap)  <br />
Constant Touch: A Global History of the Mobile Web (Jon Agar)  <br />
Personal, Portable, Pedestrian: Mobile Phones in Japanese Life (Mizuko Ito)  <br />
Mobile Interaction Design (Matt Jones)</p>

<ol>
  <li>iPhone released just before publication</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="mobile-web-fundamentals">Mobile Web Fundamentals</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://communities-dominate.blogs.com/brands/2007/01/putting_27_bill.html">Putting 2.7 Billion in Context: Mobile Phone Users</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Phone is smaller. Different input methods. Searching for specific data (directions or a phone number) rather than a truckload of data available via the desktop. One handed interaction.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Limitations: small screen size, difficulty of data input, user agent inconsistency</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Opportunities: location-specific data, on-the-go-messaging, voice communication.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Weather Channel – greater reach on mobile web compared to desktop (<a href="http://www.comscore.com/Press_Events/Press_Releases/2007/05/Mobile_Web_Usage_Grows_in_UK">source</a>)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rollable display – Polymer Vision Readius (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uQMBzXaCmqY">video</a>)</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Many devices and user agents, making testing expensive and impractical. Emulators and testing on multiple devices will lead to successful deployment.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Opera Mini – far better UI than most native browsers</li>
</ol>

<p>Mostly must be installed manually, except for T-Mobile shipping hundreds of thousands with it pre-installed</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>“…the mobile web experience is often a small screen, intermittent, one-handed experience”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>understanding of target audience, their usage and what they want, and the contextual relevance (phone numbers, etc.) of data</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Initiate a phone call: wtai scheme for WML, tel scheme for HTML.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Some browsers (Opera Mini, Safari Mobile) automatically convert links to phone numbers</p>

<p>WML scheme to add a number to the address book: wtai://wp/ap;+5555555;Amy%20Miller</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>carrier myopia: devs thinking the only way to reach the audience is by landing on the carrier deck. Mobile User Experience Conference (MEX) 2007: “Tearing down the walled garden will enhance the mobile content experience and release value for the industry. The objective should be a free market for content and applications, based on open standards and accessible to all. We think the current fragmentation of formats and channels to market is holding back growth.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>“cell phone” is an outdated term. Use “mobile” or “device”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Japanese market: “keitai” (=”something you carry with you”)</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="four-methods-revisited">Four Methods, Revisited</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.cameronmoll.com/archives/000398.html">Mobile Web Design ~ The Series</a> (Cameron Moll, 2005)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Method 1: Do nothing. If the markup is meaningful and standards-based, the better mobile browsers can adapt.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Good browsers such as the iPhone’s allow the viewing of the full site (with zooming).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Advantages: mobile browsers shoulder the burden of reformatting content, no additional effort needed, users have same content and possibly the same experience as on a PC</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Disadvantages: doesn’t address contextual relevance or exploit device capabilities, users with zoom-enabled devices are a small market share</p>

<ol>
  <li>Method 2: Reduce images and styling</li>
</ol>

<p>-presentation styling and images reduced on the fly</p>

<p>mowser.com (Russell Beattie, formerly Yahoo! Mobile)  <br />
skweezer.net – an older service dating back to 2001</p>

<p>2-minute mobile mod: <a href="http://www.mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2005/07/make-your-site-mobile-friendly">http://www.mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2005/07/make-your-site-mobile-friendly</a></p>

<ol>
  <li>Advantages: relies on implied hierarchy in HTML markup, viewable by a variety of devices, faster download, many browsers override CSS anyway, so why bother?</li>
</ol>

<p>Disadvantages: ignores contextual relevance of mobility, file size may still be excessive</p>

<p>Method 3: Use Handheld Style Sheets</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>media=”handheld” style sheet</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Not widely supported.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Advantages: handheld style sheet is built into CSS, at most one extra style sheet, one web address  <br />
Disadvantages: ignores contextual relevance of mobility, media=”handheld” support is inconsistent and nearly unreliable</p>

<p>Method 4: Create Mobile-Optimized Content</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Kayak.com/moby</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Advantages: contextually relevant (addresses first how the content is consumed, and presentation secondly), pages are leaner</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Disadvantages: denies access to content by making assumptions about the user and device, two sets of files, alternate web addresses</p>

<ol>
  <li>Author’s opinion: doing nothing and mobile-optimized content are the two viable approaches</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="xhtmlcss-development">XHTML/CSS Development</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>WML deck and card metaphor. Decline giving way to XHTML. WAP protocol, WML language.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>With WAP 2.0, XHTML-MP is the preferred markup language</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.cameronmoll.com/mobile/mkp">Markup Test Pages</a>, <a href="http://www.cameronmoll.com/archives/000577.html">Mobile Web Design: Tips &#038; Techniques (2005)</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>No need to define new standards just for the web. Same regardless of device: “The underlying standards for the greater web, regardless of device, person, or place, are the same: semantic markup, separation of structure and presentation, accessibility, and so on.”</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/mobile-bp/">W3C Mobile Web Best Practices 1.0</a></p>

<p><a href="http://passani.it/gap">Global Authoring Practices for the Mobile Web (Luca Passani)</a></p>

<ol>
  <li>XHTML-MP template</li>
</ol>

<pre name="code" class="HTML">&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?&gt;
&lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//WAPFORUM//DTD XHTML Mobile 1.0//EN" "http://www.wapforum.org/DTD/xhtml-mobile10.dtd"&gt;
&lt;html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;Site Title&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="mobile.css"/&gt;
  &lt;meta http-equiv="Cache-Control" content="max-age=600" /&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
  &lt;h1&gt;Page Heading&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</pre>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.developershome.com/wap/xhtmlmp">DeveloperHome.com’s XHTML-MP Tutorial</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://htmllint.itc.keio.ac.jp/htmllink/tagslist.cgi?HTMLVersion=XHTML-MP">XHTML-MP Tags List</a></p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Good case examples:  <br />
<a href="http://flickr.com/mob">Flickr Mobile</a>  <br />
<a href="http://mobile.fandango.com">Fandango Mobile</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile First: Luke Wroblewski on mobile design]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-first-luke-wroblewski-on-mobile-design"/>
    <updated>2010-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-first-luke-wroblewski-on-mobile-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://5by5.tv/bigwebshow/6"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/luke-wroblewski-mobile-first1.png" alt="Click to play Luke Wroblewski: Mobile First" title="Click to play Luke Wroblewski: Mobile First" width="474" height="285" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-271" /></a></p>

<p>In <a href="http://5by5.tv/bigwebshow/6">episode 6 of The Big Web Show</a>, <a href="//lukew.com/">Luke Wroblewski</a> gives his “Mobile First” talk, explaining his philosophy for designing for mobile, the challenges, and a look at the road ahead. Luke explains that because of the limitations on mobile, developers are forced to really optimize the user experience for mobile. Often times this mobile experience turns out much better than on the desktop, where the “gluttony of resources” results in distracting and excessive webpages.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
