<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>night on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/night/</link>
    <description>Recent content in night on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:15:52 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/night/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo assignment: Kyoto alleyways at night</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:15:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Before setting off on my current trip, I wanted to give myself at least one &amp;ldquo;photo assignment&amp;rdquo;: some goal I could aim to accomplish by pretending like I&#39;d been given an assignment by some employer.
This is the first of what I hope will be many. The assignment here is to try to capture the atmosphere of eastern Kyoto&#39;s traditional streets at night.
A couple of things I had to plan for: Kyoto is a bit far from my hostel in Osaka, so I made sure to make a day trip out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick failed trip to Pinnacles National Park</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:40:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;d been looking for a night like tonight for a long time, when the new moon fell squarely on the weekend. The only problem: unpredictable weather!
I drive about an hour and a half south on the 101 and then the 25 to head towards the east Pinnacles entrance, which I&#39;d never been at before. I also chatted with Yuka over LINE for a bit of it, at least until the reception got bad and dropped the call about ten minutes beofre getting to the park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 19:05:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am  Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total. The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.
While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky. It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>