<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on David Calhoun's blog</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on David Calhoun's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:32:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:32:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</guid><description>&lt;figure itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject" class="center">
 &lt;meta itemprop="width" content="1000" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="height" content="666" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="url" content="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg" />
 &lt;a href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg">
 &lt;img itemprop="contentUrl" src="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg" title="Haleakala sunset" />
 &lt;/a>
 &lt;figcaption itemprop="caption">Haleakala sunset&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We&amp;rsquo;re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks? And it&amp;rsquo;s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who&amp;rsquo;s bored is asleep, and somebody who&amp;rsquo;s asleep will not say no?&lt;br>From &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRBZDmf1jSw">My Dinner With Andre&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Existential nights</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:05:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</guid><description>&lt;p>These damn existential nights are the worst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m tired of wasting my nights distracting myself, so I stayed at work late and went to the gym even later, then left around 10:45pm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even while exercising I could feel me asking myself nagging questions. Why am I working out? What&amp;rsquo;s the goal? What&amp;rsquo;s the point of keeping your body healthy if you don&amp;rsquo;t even know where you&amp;rsquo;re going?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are important questions, but not the right questions when I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood. I thought exercise could keep some depression at bay, but it&amp;rsquo;s still there, and there it reappears at the most inconvenient times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A theory of leisure time, choice, and happiness</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is finally the end of my first week in Japanese language school here in Kyoto. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a long week, with the most studying I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done in my life. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone through nine chapters in a week, and just Friday received two more books for learning Kanji. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn our first 50 Kanji in a week, alongside the rest of our classes. I already know some words here and there, but for the most part, much of what we&amp;rsquo;ve just learned is a blur, which is forcing me to use almost all of my free time in running to catch up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The life of your parents' choosing</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several times I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;the religion of your parents&amp;rsquo; choosing&amp;rdquo;, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New direction (Developer Blog to Blog)</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve come to terms with the fact I need to try something new in my life - a true change in direction. I anticipate that this blog will take the same direction, so there will likely be less and less &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; posts and more and more posts of me living this new path. (TLDR: unsubscribe now, probably!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why the change in direction? I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived a comfortable life where I really haven&amp;rsquo;t had to worry about money (yet), but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned the hard way that buying &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t buy happiness. It&amp;rsquo;s trite and it&amp;rsquo;s something you always hear, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s something you have to figure out for yourself, the hard way. I read Walden in high school and thought I&amp;rsquo;d learned from its lessons. But I re-read it recently and came away completely changed. I can get by with a lot less, and most importantly - with a more meaningful job that pays much less.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>