<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pinnacles National Park on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/pinnacles-national-park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pinnacles National Park on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/pinnacles-national-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the year&amp;rsquo;s days shorten and their number dwindles, I have liked to sometimes take the initiative to sort through all the photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken (with my &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; camera).  The eventual goal: to put together a sampling of the photos that stand out, sometimes for technical reasons, and sometimes for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year I sadly didn&amp;rsquo;t get out with the camera as much as I have in previous years, which made this post much easier (no excuses this year!).  Less photos to sort through!  And much easier to pick out a small representative sampling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick failed trip to Pinnacles National Park</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:40:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been looking for a night like tonight for a long time, when the new moon fell squarely on the weekend.  The only problem: unpredictable weather!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I drive about an hour and a half south on the 101 and then the 25 to head towards the east Pinnacles entrance, which I&amp;rsquo;d never been at before.  I also chatted with Yuka over LINE for a bit of it, at least until the reception got bad and dropped the call about ten minutes beofre getting to the park.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
