<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>year in photos on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/year-in-photos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in year in photos on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/year-in-photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2022)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2022/my-year-in-photos-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2022/my-year-in-photos-2022/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another year in photos! I&amp;rsquo;m thankful for things almost returning to normal now after the pandemic. I was able to travel to Ireland with my buddy Mark, and I was also able to get in a few domestic trips as well!
I didn&amp;rsquo;t get my camera out and about as much as I wanted, but I still have a few picks. Seems I&amp;rsquo;m getting more interested in bird and butterfly photography&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2021)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/my-year-in-photos-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/my-year-in-photos-2021/</guid>
      <description>Intro Despite the continuing COVID-19 pandemic this year, I am grateful I was able to travel a bit. Two separate flights to California and a few road trips. While trying to keep as safe as possible, and being lucky so far not to have symptoms of COVID over this two year period (at the moment anyway&amp;hellip;).
One of my favorite hiking spots this year was the Williamson Preserve, which is a long path of hiking and biking trails that was recently converted from farmland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2020)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/my-year-in-photos-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/my-year-in-photos-2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro 2020 is a year that had a nice ring to it, conjuring up images of &amp;ldquo;20/20 vision&amp;rdquo; and whatnot, but it turned out to be a bit misleading&amp;hellip; And for some of us it has been much harder. Much has been said and much will continue to be written about this year, but despite circumstances we have tried to pull through.
For me, this year was a year of finally moving the last of my things out of California, and new beginnings: starting a new job working remotely from a new apartment in North Carolina, a place I have been interested in living in for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2019)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</guid>
      <description>In many ways this has been a strange and wonderful year, probably my most favorite year of my life to date. I traveled to Japan on a great flight deal, I hiked more than 1100 miles of the Appalachian Trail, and I drove across the USA on two (!) cross-country road trips, the latter a wonderful solo trip where I took my time photographing and visiting wonderful parks and museums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</guid>
      <description>When the year&amp;rsquo;s days shorten and their number dwindles, I have liked to sometimes take the initiative to sort through all the photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken (with my &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; camera). The eventual goal: to put together a sampling of the photos that stand out, sometimes for technical reasons, and sometimes for other reasons.
This year I sadly didn&amp;rsquo;t get out with the camera as much as I have in previous years, which made this post much easier (no excuses this year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 2 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>I was just putting together this article and these photos on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve when I glanced and the clock and noticed I was already four minutes into 2015. Oops!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the second-parter for my favorite photo from 2014. Also be sure to check out the first part.
July Yuka was still here in early July, just in time to see Fourth of July fireworks at Big Bear Lake, California, before she had to go back to Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 1 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s nearing the year&amp;rsquo;s end, so of course this means a somewhat sentimental blog post from me. I was thinking of a &amp;ldquo;resolutions/goals&amp;rdquo; type post, but I decided against it. Instead here&amp;rsquo;s something more entertaining: my favorite photos from the past year! Note that these aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily my best, just my favorites.
Finding these is also a little bit of housekeeping for me and my photos. It forces me to sort the gigabytes and gigabytes of RAW photos I was casually dumping onto drives the entire year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
