<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy on David Calhoun's blog</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy on David Calhoun's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fourth of July letter to my government</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</guid><description>&lt;p>(this is a copy of a letter which I&amp;rsquo;ve sent to various representatives in government)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a concerned citizen, I know you understand that I must occasionally voice my concern through letters such as this. My hope is that you will honestly consider my claims and take action on my part. I honestly appreciate you taking your time to seriously consider this letter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m writing to you today specifically in response to abuses by the NSA overstepping its bounds. Citizens of the United States and citizens of the world now know its private data is being indiscriminately collected, sifted through, and intruded upon by the NSA. These actions are clearly antithetical to our own Constitution and set a terrible precedent for the future of this country and the rest of the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NSA's PRISM: from the minds of conspiracy nuts, turns out to be reality</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</guid><description>&lt;p>The real shame about NSA/PRISM is that everyone will forget about it next week or next month. Just like we forgot about Trapwire and other endless abuses in the name of protecting society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The US is now a nation too mentally castrated to do anything about these obvious constitutional abuses. Why are we only capable of short-lived and impotent protest attempts like Occupy? How did we get to be so sedated through this anesthesia of modern consumerism and entertainment?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on TrapWire</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</guid><description>&lt;figure itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject" class="center">
 &lt;meta itemprop="width" content="817" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="height" content="1000" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="url" content="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg" />
 &lt;a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg">
 &lt;img itemprop="contentUrl" src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg" alt="Stratfor CEO George Friedman" />
 &lt;/a>
 &lt;figcaption itemprop="caption">Stratfor CEO George Friedman&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;quot;&amp;hellip;but the hackers will not find intelligence of corporations and governments, or signs of a vast conspiracy&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; -Stratfor CEO George Friedman, January 2012&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;eight months later&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;WIKILEAKS: Surveillance Cameras Around The Country Are Being Used In A Huge Spy Network&amp;rdquo; -Business Insider, August 2012&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, there been some big news released recently as a result of another release of documents by Wikileaks on August 9, 2012. The documents are &lt;a href="http://mirror2.wikileaks-press.org/gifiles/releasedate/2012-08-09.html">emails from the global intelligence company Stratfor&lt;/a>. The most recent release has confirmed what many conspiracy theorists have feared for years: that the government is operating a vast secret surveillance network that is collecting data on citizens and their movements.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>