<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: philosophy | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/philosophy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-18T14:00:33-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-04T00:32:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><figure class='center'><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg" width="1000" height="666" title="Haleakala sunset" ><figcaption>Haleakala sunset</figcaption></figure></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We’re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks?  And it’s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who’s bored is asleep, and somebody who’s asleep will not say no?<br />From <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRBZDmf1jSw">My Dinner With Andre</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unless I die young, I haven’t quite made it to my midlife crisis yet.  But it does seem to me that I’ve heard more and more about people experiencing their “quarter-life” crises.  Is this something new?  Or have people always had so many of these doubting periods?  Or maybe we’re at a time where so many of us have the freedom and luxury to even contemplate such a thing, a freedom that leads to our own detriment.</p>

<p>I’m admittedly not great at math, but it does seem to me these quarter-life crises should occur in someone’s early 20’s.  Is that crisis somehow supposed to eventually pass, or just it just get quietly ignored while we distract ourselves with other concerns?  Then we learn to get comfortably numb and sleepy and learn to accept life for how mundane it really is?  Can a midlife crisis still re-emerge later on in life, after a person wakes up again?</p>

<p>I’m fairly certain I’ve been asleep these past few years.  I wouldn’t be surprised, since I do like to sleep (I sometimes waste entire weekends on the couch or in bed, but that’s another story).</p>

<p>I’m too old for these childish quarter-life crises.  The only explanation for this current one is that I must’ve graduated to the rarely-if-ever-mentioned third-life crisis.  A relevant question to ask myself here: just how many damn life crises is it normal for someone to have, and do they ever stop?</p>

<p>In my 20’s I graduated college, had a choice of career paths and started to float and drift a bit, getting a job testing cellphone games.  There I made some friends, but it didn’t really advance my career or my personal life outside of that.</p>

<p>I got older, I worked more, I got a job at a big corporate job, doing what I thought was a decent career.  But I learned that big corporate jobs are soul-numbing.  I quit my big corporate job and did the inevitable clichéd trip to Asia.  Particularly in my field, folks seem to get the same idea.  (Not unlike other things I suppose: Everyone wants to travel to Asia, everyone wants to move to Portland or Austin, everyone wants to save up for a house, everyone wants a Tesla).</p>

<p>That experience traveling helped me grow as a person more than any job ever did, but apparently I didn’t grow or learn enough, because I found myself falling into the same pattern as before.  Get the comfortable corporate job, dance like a monkey if I wanted to advance and get promoted, then try to save up for a house like everyone else.</p>

<p>The idiotic Silicon Valley version: save up for a down payment on a ridiculously overpriced house that’s in the bad part of town and also falling apart (because that’s the only one you can afford making comparative chump change to everyone else).  Maybe also save up for a Tesla, so at the very least you can brag to your coworkers that you bought a Tesla.  Because Tesla.</p>

<p>Then you get a job at what’s supposed to be the Best Place To Work In The Universe, according to a survey of all known workers in the universe.  You find that it’s not too much different than your previous Big Corporate Job.  Is this really all there is to look forward to?  So I can buy a house and a Tesla?  What next after that even?  Work the rest of the best years of my life paying off the house?</p>

<p>What if I don’t want a house (though not sharing walls would be nice)?  What if I don’t want a Tesla?  I don’t think I’m the only one.  I think all those folks who quit their jobs to travel the world likely have the same feelings.  They’re trying to escape from something.  Their inner selves seem to have woken up from a nightmare in the night, and are restlessly awake, pacing back and forth.  Except they’re pacing through the world, not just their bedrooms.</p>

<p>Some of these folks even get the idea that the ideal lifestyle is being a traveling nomad, hopping from country to country, somehow earning enough money to get by.  If they can make it work, I think they do tend to be happier, or at least more alive and more childlike and inquisitive.  Is it just the permanent change in scenery?  I’m not sure I’d be comfortable in that sort of lifestyle myself.  It is always nice to come back home eventually, and to spend time with familiar friends and family, and familiar things in general.  Sometimes it’s nice to be a little hobbit-like.</p>

<p>Is all this travelling and escaping just a delaying of inevitable adulthood?  What if I’m already an adult - does it mean I’m just deceiving myself?  Am I running away from myself?  Is adulthood really just the acceptance that you’re not special, that this really is the only thing life is about?  That your life is the thing that happens for a few brief hours after work, and entire weekends that you may end up wasting on stupid pursuits?</p>

<p>As much as philosophy has helped me, in cases like this I think it’s kind of made me dissatisfied with everything.</p>

<p>Maybe I can still somehow play and enjoy the game of life, even if I realize it’s only some silly game we’ve concocted to keep ourselves busy?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary of Aurelius Augustinus and Seng Zhao on 'Time': An Interpretation of the Confessions and the Zhao Lun]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/summary-of-aurelius-augustinus-and-seng-zhao-on-time-an-interpretation-of-the-confessions-and-the-zhao-lun/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-07T11:15:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/summary-of-aurelius-augustinus-and-seng-zhao-on-time-an-interpretation-of-the-confessions-and-the-zhao-lun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Note: partial notes)</p>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>I’ve been trying to get more into Eastern/Western Philosophy comparisons lately, and I’ve subscribed to an interesting journal out of the University of Hawaii called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophy_East_and_West/">Philosophy East and West</a>.</p>

<p>This is however somewhat of a challenge.</p>

<p>This spirit of comparative philosophy seems to be more popular for so-called “Continental Philosophy” rather than “Analytic Philosophy”, which makes the style and occassional references to German words somewhat unfamiliar to me.  I’m more familiar with the Western Analytic tradition, so this is a challenge trying to access something that falls into a different tradition, in more ways than one.  Western and Eastern, Analytic and Continental, and yet I’m convinced we all can learn something about everything.  (apparently Rorty tried to bridge some of these differences, but anyhow I guess I’ll have to look into that later)</p>

<p>This comparative piece from Man Li and Bart Dessein (both from Belgium’s Ghent University) is an interesting look at Eastern and Western conceptions of time as viewed by two contemporaries:</p>

<p>-<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augustine_of_Hippo">Aurelius Augustinus</a> (354-430), better known as Saint Augustine.<br />
-<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sengzhao">Sengzhao (僧肇)</a> (384–414), referred to in the text as Seng Zhao</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>The scope of this article is to examine the conception of time in Augustine’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confessions_(Augustine)">Confessions</a> and contemporary Buddhist Sengzhao’s conception in Zhao Lun (The Treatises of [Seng]zhao).</p>

<p>The question “what is time?” is a part of every philosophical tradition, and it is a question that concerns all people, from the layman to the scholar.  The question brings our mortality into question, as we ask ourselves “do our lives pass through some objective time, or is time some subjective thing that is somehow part of our bodies?”</p>

<p>For the authors of this article, the answer to this objective/subjective question also leads to bigger questions about whether humans are creators and controllers of their own lives, or rather if they are constrained by time, some outside objective thing which they cannot themselves control.</p>

<h2 id="augustines-conception-of-time">Augustine’s Conception of Time</h2>
<p>The backdrop of Augustine’s philosophy is Greek philosophy, which had viewed the mythological cosmos as an eternal cycle, and consequently a view of time as a cyclical process.  Herodotos, Thukydides (Thucydides), and even Plato were responsible for shifting focus from this cyclical mythological view of time to a more human view.</p>

<p>Human life, and human history, is inevitably interlaced with time.  And since the (cyclical) divine withdrew from (temporal) human life, humans now have the  creative freedom to create meaning for themselves and society, in a sort of existentialist way.  For these thinkers, to understand it’s crucial to understand temporal human life constrasted with the permanent cosmos, and that human life (and “human time”) is somewhat unique in the way it breaks free of the eternal cycle.</p>

<p>With Augustine, Christianity’s introduction into this sort of world necessarily has an effect and changes the way these things are perceived, including our conception of time.</p>

<p>For Augustine, there are two senses time: an objective and subjective time.</p>

<h3 id="augustines-objective-time">Augustine’s Objective Time</h3>
<p>An old Manichean question helps us understand here: “What was God doing before He created heaven and earth?”.  The answer is that this question is essentially nonsensical, because time is also a created thing, like heaven and earth.  Time was created simulatanously with all other created things.  Essentially, there was no “before” or “after” without the existence of other created things.</p>

<p>There are a few key relationships here in this objective sense of time.  In regards to God and time, God is independent of time.  In regards to Heaven/Earth and their relationship to time, they are all created things, and in a sense are all equally infinite.  Regarding created things and time, this is a question of time and all finite things - that is, all that is non-God, non-Heaven, and non-Earth.  All these things are subject to time, including Heaven and Earth.</p>

<h3 id="augustines-subjective-time">Augustine’s Subjective Time</h3>
<p>In Augustine’s subjective definition, time is an extension of the mind - that is to say, when we measure time we are measuring our <em>impression</em> of time.  There is no way for us to get ahold of the objective essence of time.  That is to say, time in itself.  “Either this impression is time, otherwise I do not measure time”.</p>

<p>(my note: there’s a much larger related discussion behind this, of phenomenology)</p>

<p>We have an idea of past, present, and future, but really we are speaking of our “present impression” of all three.  When we speak of the past, we do not have direct access to it, only to a present impression of the past.  Likewise when we speak of the future: what we’re really grasping at is our present impression of the future.  Past, present, and future, all three concepts are present impressions in the mind.</p>

<h2 id="sengzhaos-conception-of-time">Sengzhao’s Conception of Time</h2>
<p>Sengzhao’s philosophy of time is influenced by Buddhist philosophy of his day, which viewed time as a mechanical process, not influenced by the divine as in Augustine’s conception.</p>

<p>In this karmic mechanical time model, time is the infinite cycle of rebirths (samsara), a process of exchanging one life for another.</p>

<p>According to the Vaibhāṣika school, all three time periods must exist, for if they didn’t then there would be no karmic chain, or chain of causality of past influencing present, and present influencing the future.</p>

<p>In this view there is also somewhat of a subjective notion of time, in the sense that an individual has their own alottment of time.  This time can be controlled if the individual can stop the karmic process, and in a sense “stop time”.</p>

<h3 id="voidness-and-time">Voidness and “Time”</h3>
<p>The Madhyamaka school’s (Mahayana Buddhism) criticism of the Vaibhāṣika school is that the following premises cannot be held simulateneously:</p>

<ol>
  <li>A human being is composed of five constituents</li>
  <li>A human being has no self-nature</li>
</ol>

<p>The flow of reasoning here becomes tricky.</p>

<p>For Madhyamikas, the nature of the contituents (dharma) must be the same as the nature of things formed by them (since like comes from like).  If there is a self-nature, the constituents must also have the same self-nature, but they cannot.  Therefore they are as void (sunya) as the things formed by them are.  But time cannot be “in” things that are void, so time must not be “in” things.</p>

<p>If time is not a part of things, then we have two possibilities left:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Either time exists independently of things</li>
  <li>Things pass through an independently-existing time</li>
</ol>

<p>This is where Seng Zhao comes into play.</p>

<p>In Zhao’s texts, there is no direct discussion of the word that translates as “time”, but he does present dual concepts:</p>

<p>-past and present<br />
-going and coming<br />
-shifting and abiding<br />
-motion and quietude (the key pair, as they are the most used in the texts)</p>

<p>According to Zhao, there are two ways of perceiving time (or the moving of things):</p>

<ol>
  <li>The ordinary way, a sort of conventional truth</li>
  <li>The superior way, in the domain of absolute truth</li>
</ol>

<p>According to the ordinary way of thinking about things, if there is no motion then there is quietude (these are the pairs of concepts mentioned above).  But according to Zhao, motion and quietude have never been different - one is not the absence of another, for it’s possible to have quietude even despite motion.</p>

<p>There’s a key thought behind this into the nature of things.  Zhao’s thought is that quietude cannot be the result of abandoning motion, because this would mean the fundamental nature of the thing changed.  Things must fundamentally remain the same, or else they would be different.  That is to say, something in motion should also have a nature of quietude, even while in motion.</p>

<p>There is therefore a co-existence of motion (dong) and quietude (jing).</p>

<p>These concepts of dong and jing turn out to be roughly analogous to past (xi) and present (jin).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Existential nights]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-30T00:05:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These damn existential nights are the worst.</p>

<p>I’m tired of wasting my nights distracting myself, so I stayed at work late and went to the gym even later, then left around 10:45pm.</p>

<p>Even while exercising I could feel me asking myself nagging questions.  Why am I working out?  What’s the goal?  What’s the point of keeping your body healthy if you don’t even know where you’re going?</p>

<p>These are important questions, but not the right questions when I’m not in the mood.  I thought exercise could keep some depression at bay, but it’s still there, and there it reappears at the most inconvenient times.</p>

<p>I’m fighting it.</p>

<p>My body is getting healthier and my mind is getting stronger, and I’m slowly figuring out the path I’m going to take.</p>

<p>Sleep is the best medicine for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Beatitudes]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-09T00:29:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>

<p>Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted.</p>

<p>Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth.</p>

<p>Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied.</p>

<p>Blessed are the merciful, for they shall obtain mercy.</p>

<p>Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.</p>

<p>Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God.</p>

<p>Blessed are those who are persecuted for righteousness’ sake, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>

<p>Blessed are you when men revile you and persecute you and utter all kinds of evil against you falsely on my account. Rejoice and be glad, for your reward is great in heaven, for so men persecuted the prophets who were before you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living as driftwood]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T21:52:23-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the previous two photo posts I wanted to avoid this sort of heavy reflection New Year post.  But its time has finally come and it should be said, no matter how cheesy it may sound.</p>

<p>I have been living these last few years of my life as driftwood.  At least professionally.  I have all the makings of what should make me happy and successfully in my career, but it’s an illusion.  I am an imposter.  I am living a life as professional driftwood.</p>

<p>What I mean is this: previously I was very active in trying to establish my career as a web developer.  I read as much as I could, practiced as much as I could, and constantly tried to learn new things that would make me better.</p>

<p>I am living what society calls a good life, but I don’t know myself what a good life really is.  I’m sure it’s not this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
