<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: philosophy | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/philosophy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-11T23:41:00-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning thoughts on the idea of a Great American Road Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-11T22:35:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea of a trip across the United States has become somewhat of an American institution.  Something like a New American Dream, this one maybe a bit more accessible than that house, happy life, and nuclear family with 2.5 kids.  It’s something that is undertaken by both the young and the old, with the former perhaps hitchhiking or sleeping in their cars while the latter leapfrog between National Parks in their expensive and comfortable motor homes.</p>

<p>It’s something that can be undertaken alone, along a lonely journey which becomes a sort of vision quest to find one’s purpose.  Or it can be undertaken with friends and family, and turned into more of a quest to check off bucket list destinations and to experience America.</p>

<p>Whatever the circumstance, the thought of the American Road Trip hangs in the back of every American’s mind in some way.  I can’t help think that there is daily at least one person stuck in a cubicle or trapped in a job behind a computer screen that isn’t tempted in some way to recklessly abandon their current situation and make plans to hit the road.  Even if the trip amounts to nothing, and no progress on a sense of life purpose, at the very least there is a thrill of escape, of running away from the daily struggle.  What a thrill, like escaping a prison - a prison we’ve willingly signed up for.</p>

<p>And why not take a chance?  It’s like the escape of running off to travel the world, except much less expensive and with far less communication barriers along the way.</p>

<p>Of course I should say that anyone lucky enough to be in circumstances to even entertain these thoughts is privileged.  I’m sure some shake their heads in disgust that such spoiled people aren’t content, and feel the need to escape from their comfortable life.</p>

<p>Maybe the person wanting to make a jailbreak is a millenial such as myself, somewho is spoiled, never had to truly struggle as generations past, and all through life lead along nowhere-in-particular with a carrot-on-a-stick, a buildup to the glorious present.  The present, which turned out to be the mundane grind of a meaningless job that happens to pay well, and maybe continues to spoil you with free food and other perks, in the hopes to stifle those existential pains.</p>

<p>We have all this and then still complain?  I know why folks are outraged at the thought, but this struggle isn’t new, and the American Road Trip has always been a cross-generational outlet to find one’s purpose in the face of mundane reality.  I’m not sure how far back you have to go to be considered a “millenial”, but stretching it back to Jack Kerouac’s <em>On The Road</em> would be reaching.</p>

<p>A bit of a side note: but I thought I was Generation Y, not Millenial?  Or are they the same?  I never really liked being lumped into a category, especially one based on a time period in which I was born.  Next thing you know, folks will be analyzing personalities based on their birth month.  But I guess we’ll leave that to astrology and other bunk.</p>

<p>In any case, why not explore the possibilities?</p>

<p>If I stayed in a good but meaningless job where my ego was stroked and my belly and wallet fattened, that would be a sure way to come out in ten years as a bored, unfulfilled, fat, entitled individual.  And ten years older at that, probably with debts and a mortgage to pay off for life (the terms of the sentence).  Perhaps I’d become lazy and never challenged myself to get out and explore different possibilities, different ways of making a living.  Perhaps I’d never considered that I could make money doing other things, that I could seriously consider and try other modes of living, or at least observe them in others as I sped by their world in my car.</p>

<p>What better way of doing all that, than on a trip across the country?  Where you could get out and see how different folks existing and living in various ways?  What a taste of all the options, all the possibilities.  At the very least you could figure out if the air smelled differently in different parts, if people talked differently, if folks were kinder in some parts or had different attitudes.  What a shame never to experience it.</p>

<p>Many folks may be comparatively well-off to be able to undertake such an adventure.  But what a truly great adventure it must be!  What a truly great opportunity, and what a privilege to have the option to look at these possibilities and to turn them over in one’s mind for days on end, to take them seriously and try to understand them.</p>

<p>Socrates once said:</p>

<blockquote>
Besides, it is a disgrace to grow old through sheer carelessness before seeing what manner of man you may become by developing your bodily strength and beauty to their highest limit.
<br /><br />
αἰσχρὸν δὲ καὶ τὸ διὰ τὴν ἀμέλειαν γηρᾶναι, πρὶν ἰδεῖν ἑαυτὸν ποῖος ἂν κάλλιστος καὶ κράτιστος τῷ σώματι γένοιτο
<br /><br />
(from Xenophon's Memorabilia)
</blockquote>

<p>This can also be applied to our mental life, and our way of living.  We have the opportunity to push our bodies to its limits to test it and know how much we are possible of.</p>

<p>How much can we push our comfort zone and know other ways of living, and to explore those possibilities?  What a shame to grow old and never have experienced those limits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe it's healthier to embrace discomfort]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-09T09:35:44-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many folks, including yours truly, have had an unpleasant night, and this morning a bitter awakening at the announcement that our new President will be Trump.  For most folks this comes as a shock, as we have all thought the chances of this happening were slim.  Comedians chided him on and dared him to run.  Even President Obama who continually roasted him <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n9mzJhvC-8E">at the White House Correspondents’ Dinner in 2011</a>, arguably the defining moment when Trump became driven to run for President (“He certainly would bring some change to the White House”).</p>

<p>The whole experience has been surreal, and I suppose many folks took it for granted that last night we would finally would wake from such a crazy nightmare.  But we haven’t waken up.  This is America for the next four years.  And now, as rational people, we need to come to terms with this and figure out how to deal with this.  Rationally.</p>

<p>Just as Michael Moore did before the election, when he articulated a very personal understanding of Trump’s base of support:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YKeYbEOSqYc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Trump the person of course has always been shocking, and that he’s progressed this far is more shocking.  It will be so hard to think of him ever being “presidential”.  The thing is, he can only have made it so far by being backed by MANY supporters, the viewpoints of which clearly so many of us have failed to understand.  Perhaps out of our own lack of empathy.</p>

<p>It’s clear that so many of us have still failed to understand, with some explanations that Hillary lost largely because America is misogynist.  Or that Trump’s supporters are all old, racist, uneducated, white hillbillies out in flyover country.</p>

<p>These arguments are simply intellectually lazy, and they should be identified as such.</p>

<p>To be sure, there are plenty of racist Trump supporters who have created enough spectacles on their own, apart from Trump creating his own spectacles which we all gobbled up.  Heck, the KKK endorsing Trump was a spectacle on its own (the KKK also endorsed Reagan, but unlike Trump he was <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/1984/05/02/us/reagan-spurns-klan-support.html">quite vocal against them</a>).</p>

<p>The point here is that it’s a logical leap to say that the majority of Trump supporters are this way.  This is simply a lazy stereotype that uncritically pushes these supporters to the sidelines.</p>

<p>Ironically and sadly, we continue to have a very surface-level understand of Trump supporters.  But why should we be so supportive of folks with alternative ways of life, such as LGBT folks, but immediately dismissive of Trump supporters?  The truth is that it’s much easier to write off these folks as 100% racist, block them on social media, laugh at them, and shut then down, than to understand them.  The same motivation that encourages folks to flee communities that don’t share their political opinions.</p>

<p>What do folks expect from people whose voices are silenced?  They turn more extremist than you could possibly imagine.  Sadly, I think some of them do turn resentful and become racist and sexist, when they would have had no incentive to do so otherwise.</p>

<p>If you find yourself growing up in a middle America town, but find yourself not fitting in politically, surely you are silenced and shut down in a similar way.  If you are not “one of them”, how are you supposed to even engage in debate, except by fleeing flyover country and joining the rest of your like-minded folks on either coast?  Further dividing these united states, segregating ideologies into geographic echo chambers.</p>

<p>It must be something driven by human nature, something that drives folks apart and into like-minded groups.  Something that is comfortable, no doubt.  It’s definitely more comfortable to flee different viewpoints than to struggle to understand them.</p>

<p>But maybe it’s more healthy for us to embrace discomfort?  I don’t know.  I just know that whatever we’re doing now isn’t working.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quine and Heidegger: Against Reductionism]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-19T22:15:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" content="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reductionism" />

<p>Earlier this year I had the opportunity to attend my first philosophy class in about a decade.  The class was on the infamous philosopher Martin Heidegger, and the course was taught at Stanford University by Forrest Hartman (PHI 98: An Introduction to Martin Heidegger (Spring 2016)).</p>

<p>Heidegger is famous for being obscure and notoriously difficult to read, but I believe I made some headway in what turned out to be a very interesting philosophy.  Most interestingly, though Heidegger is considered to be a “continental” philosophy, I found some common ground with Quine, who is considered to be an “analytical” philosophy, supposedly in a diametrically opposed camp.</p>

<p>I’ve been meaning to post this for a while - this is the paper I wrote for the class.  Would be interested in any feedback!</p>

<p>For convenience, <a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/writing/David%20Calhoun%20-%20Quine%20and%20Heidegger.pdf">here it is in PDF form</a>!</p>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>Comparing two thinkers from opposite philosophical traditions may initially seem like an impossible and fruitless task, a sort of culture clash two cultures cognitively thousands of miles apart.  It should be easy to find the points of departure between Quine and Heidegger<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, but what I’m more looking forward to here is what seems to be an eerie agreement on a few key topics, in particular reactions against science: a move back towards accepting metaphysics, against the dominant trend of their time.  And a move away from a reductionist approach and towards a more holist view of knowledge.</p>

<p>Their seeming agreement here is almost as if two wanderers have hiked up a mountain from opposite sides, eventually arriving at the same peak.  And when two very different thinkers end up at similar positions, at the very least I think we should have a look.</p>

<h2 id="a-quick-look-at-quine">A quick look at Quine</h2>

<p>It makes sense to take a look at Quine first, because he represents a tradition which Heidegger is reacting against.  Being from the analytic philosophical tradition, Quine sees his work as a continuation of the philosophical tradition initiated by Descartes (modernism).  A tradition that strives for exactness in methods and in its own writings, seeking clarity and concision<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup>.  This all seems well and good coming from the point of view of science, however this tradition has been criticized for being too focused on language and science, too sterile and academic, and consequently for ordinary people, not only inaccessible but sadly irrelevant for them.</p>

<p>Quine himself wouldn’t argue that science should be so closely tied to philosophy: in Quine’s view, philosophy somewhat cohabitates with science<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote">3</a></sup>.  And sometimes philosophy is even secondary, as something that comes along afterwards in order to clarify and clean up little messes and points of ambiguity that science has left behind.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<p>How can we even begin to understand the world with this approach?  For science, phenomena is king: it is from phenomena that we get observation sentences, which are foundational for scientific understanding:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Typical observation sentences are about bodies: ‘This is a table,’ ‘This table is square,’ ‘The cat is on the mat.’. Always the situation that makes an observation sentence true will be a situation that is intersubjectively observable; that is, it will be the sort of situation to which multiple witnesses could, if present, attest.”<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote">5</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s important to note here that this methodology distinguishes between witnesses and bodies; between subjects and objects.  Unfortunately this disconnect has lead to many problems for this philosophy and its descendants: subjects can never have direct access to objects<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote">6</a></sup>.  Consequently there is always an untraversable distance between us and our world; the extreme of this being external world skepticism, that we can never be sure we have knowledge of the world as it <em>really</em> is in itself.  This troublesome view seems to be confirmed by the “progress” of philosophy through the centuries: philosophical frameworks are confidently built up only to be later gleefully destroyed in a seemingly endless churn.</p>

<p>What is the nature of reality?  Who knows, but the next generation of philosophers will surely have a different answer.  This long and seemingly unsuccessful churning of philosophy was one of the reasons for Descartes’ radical questioning, and wanting to rebuild philosophy on firm foundations.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote">7</a></sup></p>

<p>Yet science cannot afford to endlessly doubt, sit still and not make progress, and so it must start somewhere.  The best science can hope for is a sort of pragmatic approach: to aggregate multiple observation sentences from multiple subjects (the “multiple witnesses” in the statement above), and hope that the observations agree.  For a philosophy based on science, these observations end up being foundational for all meaning and knowledge.  This leads to a logical extreme, the verification theory of meaning, the theory that “…the meaning of a statement is the method of empirically confirming or infirming it.”<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" class="footnote">8</a></sup>.  In other words, an extreme approach which <em>reduces all meaning down to merely scientific observation sentences</em>.</p>

<p>Quine reacts against this view in his most famous paper, Two Dogmas of Empiricism, and it’s here that we find strange similarities to Heidegger’s views in Being and Time.</p>

<p>But more on this later, since first we need to consider Heidegger’s own approach.</p>

<h2 id="a-quick-look-at-heidegger">A quick look at Heidegger</h2>

<p>Heidegger himself comes from the continental philosophical tradition and sees his work in opposition to Descartes in many ways.  We would say he represents a sense of anti or post-modernism.  Some would also accuse him of being obscure and difficult to understand, in many cases purposely unclear and imprecise<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" class="footnote">9</a></sup>.  Also, some might see Heidegger’s stance as anti-science<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" class="footnote">10</a></sup>, though this is a mischaracterization, at least of the Heidegger of Being and Time, which is my focus here.</p>

<p>For Heidegger, philosophy is clearly the starting point for knowledge, that which must be made clear before examining other domains such as the sciences<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11" class="footnote">11</a></sup><sup id="fnref:12"><a href="#fn:12" class="footnote">12</a></sup>.  Heidegger’s project is actually similar to Descartes’ in the sense that both are looking for a foundation, a starting point from which to begin philosophy.  Descartes looks to build from a firm <em>epistemic foundation</em>, obsessed with certainty: starting from the only thing which he can’t reasonably doubt: that he exists.  The famous cogito ergo sum: “I think, therefore I am”.</p>

<p>But Heidegger takes him to task for not digging deep enough: “he leaves the ‘sum’ completely undiscussed, even though it is regarded as no less primordial than the cogito.”<sup id="fnref:13"><a href="#fn:13" class="footnote">13</a></sup>  This “sum”, the “I am”, is what Heidegger calls Dasein, the study of which he thinks should be prior to all other study.  Dasein isn’t a what but a who.  Dasein is <em>us</em>, something that is mysteriously close and yet far: “that which is ontically closest and well known, is ontologically the farthest and not known at all”<sup id="fnref:14"><a href="#fn:14" class="footnote">14</a></sup>.  Heidegger thinks we should not start with epistemology as Descartes did, but with metaphysics, specifically with the <em>fundamental ontology</em> of Dasein.</p>

<p>Here the method of examining Dasein might strike us as very unusual, because the very nature of Dasein refuses to be categorized as any other object that has properties to be examined, like Descartes’ “thinking substance”.  No, Dasein is something strange and is not like other beings: it cannot be talked about as a what but as a <em>who</em><sup id="fnref:15"><a href="#fn:15" class="footnote">15</a></sup>, as a living-through experiences<sup id="fnref:16"><a href="#fn:16" class="footnote">16</a></sup>, of intentional actions<sup id="fnref:17"><a href="#fn:17" class="footnote">17</a></sup>.  It’s not something which we can study with our scientific toolbox, the world of subject and object.  (Note that we need not throw out the idea of subject/object entirely, only when discussing Dasein<sup id="fnref:18"><a href="#fn:18" class="footnote">18</a></sup>).</p>

<p>Also, there is no problem of not being able to see <em>things in themselves</em> for Heidegger.  There is no untraversable distance between subject and object with Dasein, because there is no subject/object distinction.  Dasein <em>experiences things as they are in themselves</em>, albeit in a different way than the Kantian sense.</p>

<p>Note that we cannot also apply science’s familiar reductionist strategy here: Dasein is not some object to be broken into parts which can then be classified and understood individually<sup id="fnref:19"><a href="#fn:19" class="footnote">19</a></sup>, then added up again to understand Dasein as a whole.<sup id="fnref:20"><a href="#fn:20" class="footnote">20</a></sup>  One of the reasons being that it’s problematic that we would even know how to “put the world together again”<sup id="fnref:21"><a href="#fn:21" class="footnote">21</a></sup> - that already-knowing-how is exactly what Heidegger is trying to uncover: trying to “get behind” or get “prior” to this already-knowing-how to put the pieces back together.</p>

<p>Yet we can still talk about Dasein’s structure<sup id="fnref:22"><a href="#fn:22" class="footnote">22</a></sup> in what Heidegger calls “existentialia”: various ways of describing states of Dasein’s Being<sup id="fnref:23"><a href="#fn:23" class="footnote">23</a></sup>, perhaps most importantly for our discussion: Dasein being-in-the-world (in a sense the world is “embedded”, but in a different way than things are usually “being-in” each other – it’s difficult here to avoid the subject-object language we’re usually accustomed to<sup id="fnref:24"><a href="#fn:24" class="footnote">24</a></sup>).  Being-in-the-world and other structures of Dasein turn out to be equiprimordial: they are prior and impossible to “get behind”, so much so that they must be presupposed and cannot be questioned<sup id="fnref:25"><a href="#fn:25" class="footnote">25</a></sup>.</p>

<p>What’s vital to understand here is that it’s impossible to take any of these “existentialia” out of the world and look at them in isolation, then look at them individually as if in a petri dish; the scientific approach of reducing our world down into smaller, more understandable parts.  These structures of Dasein can only be examined in relation to each other as part of a whole, as a part of a holistic understanding.  To examine in isolation is to examine away from its natural habitat, and thus what Heidegger would call an “inappropriate” study that yields no understanding.  Instead of examining parts in isolation, Heidegger’s “hermeneutical circle” approach is both an attempt at expressing this difficult holism and also an explanation of Dasein’s ontological understanding of itself<sup id="fnref:26"><a href="#fn:26" class="footnote">26</a></sup>.</p>

<h2 id="the-two-thinkers-compared">The two thinkers compared</h2>

<p>Coming back to our comparison with Quine, it may be very difficult at this point to see where Heidegger might have any points of agreement at all.  Heidegger in a sense seems to have jumped into the deep end of metaphysics, starting philosophy at the farthest point away from empiricism (science).  And from everything I’ve outlined above, we may think that Quine would here be on the front lines defending science against these strange speculative metaphysics of Dasein.  But the reality turns out to be quite different.</p>

<p>In his well-known Two Dogmas of Empiricism, Quine goes on the attack against the logical positivists, an extreme group of empiricists who fundamentally believed that all truths can be <em>broken down into pieces</em> that end up being either analytic (such as mathematical proofs) or synthetic (such as scientific statements)<sup id="fnref:27"><a href="#fn:27" class="footnote">27</a></sup>.  Both points of Quine’s attack end up forcing us out of this extreme reductionist view and into a position that forces us to embrace a sort of holism, in a very different sort of way than the traditional scientific reductionist view.</p>

<p>Quine’s first point of attack is against a distinction that goes back to Kant: that truths are either analytic or synthetic:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Analytic sentences: propositions “grounded in meanings independently of matters of fact”<sup id="fnref:28"><a href="#fn:28" class="footnote">28</a></sup> - such as “all bachelors are unmarried”, which are supposedly able to speak for themselves in complete isolation, like mathematical truths.</li>
  <li>Synthetic truths: propositions that we must go out into the world to find out about – sentences such as “bachelors are lonely people”.  These are the sorts of truths uncovered by empiricism (science).</li>
</ol>

<p>Quine attacks this distinction by explaining that it’s impossible to even explain how analytic sentences have meaning in isolation.  For instance, how do we know that “bachelor” is equivalent to “unmarried man” - don’t we have to consult a dictionary or have some prior knowledge to make such a statement?  We also must have some of idea of synonymy <em>beforehand</em>, to understand the very meaning behind something like “A is the same as - is synonymous with - B” in order to understand a sentence such as “all bachelors are unmarried”.</p>

<p>It turns out that “pure” analytic sentences are not so pure after all: in every case it’s impossible to understand the sentence in isolation, without appealing to some wider body of knowledge.  In each case, as Heidegger might say, there is <em>always-already an idea of synonymy</em>, and for that language speaker, always-already an understanding of the meaning of “bachelor” and “unmarried”.</p>

<p>The result of Quine’s discussion is that it seems there is no distinction between analytic and synthetic propositions at all: there actually appear to be no true analytic sentences that can “stand on their own”.</p>

<p>The second prong of Quine’s attack is more explicitly against reductionism in general, which is somewhat a continuation of his first attack.  Where Quine was previously attacking isolated analytic sentences as incomprehensible, he also says it makes no sense to talk about synthetic statements being meaningful by themselves.  No, observation sentences, of science and otherwise, only have meaning in relation to a larger body of observation sentences, an entire <em>web of belief</em>.  And it turns out that one observation sentence might challenge the whole web of belief and force some beliefs to be rejected, while in other cases supporting other beliefs.</p>

<p>Each observation sentence affects the whole web of belief.   Each observation sentence <em>has meaning only in relation to the whole web of belief</em>.</p>

<p>This should seem very similar to what we discussed previously in regards to Heidegger’s hermeneutic circle approach, and his resistance to talking about any of the existialia by themselves, in isolation from the others.  Just as Quine argued that one observation sentence by itself has no meaning, but only meaning in relation to the whole web of belief, so too does Heidegger argue that it’s inappropriate to speak of the existialia of Dasien without understanding its activity, its be-ing, in the whole of Dasein.  That is to say, the whole hermeneutic circle approach.</p>

<h2 id="leaving-the-door-open-for-metaphysics">Leaving the door open for metaphysics</h2>

<p>Also, as it turns out, in the wake of Quine’s attack on logical positivism, it once again becomes useful to look towards metaphysics, something science in general seems to try to shy away from.  Where logical positivists were trying to shut the door on all metaphysics, Quine now puts his foot in the door, leaving open the possibility to talk about metaphysics:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“The same normativity which leads Quine to attack logical positivism … encourages a more modest metaphysical attitude … it would seem sensible to be liberal about the possibilities of speculative metaphysics. Quine blurs the boundary between speculative metaphysics and natural science…”<sup id="fnref:29"><a href="#fn:29" class="footnote">29</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Leaving open the possibility for metaphysics is of course crucial, as all of Heidegger’s philosophy starts with metaphysics: the fundamental ontology of Dasein.  Yet of course Quine is still coming from perspective of the vastly different scientific different world, and would definitely not agree that philosophy should start with metaphysics like Heidegger does.</p>

<p>In a way, Heidegger has his own view about how we must approach philosophy, but he accommodates science and allows it to be useful and to exist in its own world as a regional ontology.  And Quine, though coming from a scientific background, has his own view about how we must approach philosophy, his own argument moderates the extreme scientific view of the logical positivists and actually ends up accommodating metaphysics, keeping the door open for speculative metaphysics such as Heidegger’s.</p>

<h2 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h2>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>In particular I want to compare the Quine of Two Dogmas of Empiricism and the Heidegger of Being and Time. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>“In more general terms, I strive for clarity and brevity. It happens so often that by going over something and making it shorter I improve it.” (W.V. Quine: Perspectives on Logic, Science and Philosophy, The Harvard Review of Philosophy, Spring 1994 p. 56) <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>“I think of philosophy as continuous with science, but philosophy differs by degree in various respects. Philosophy undertakes to analyze the general, basic concepts of science - the sort of concepts the practicing scientist will typically take for granted. These are such basic notions as truth, existence, and necessity. Also, philosophy investigates questions of evidence for science - that’s epistemology.” (W.V. Quine: Perspectives on Logic, Science and Philosophy, The Harvard Review of Philosophy, Spring 1994 p. 47) <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>“…I think “tying up loose ends” [of science] is a good way of condensing philosophy’s purpose.” (W.V. Quine: Perspectives on Logic, Science and Philosophy, The Harvard Review of Philosophy, Spring 1994 p. 48) <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
      <p>Quine, Web of Belief pg 25 <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6">
      <p>For instance, this object-in-the-world is basically the Kantian thing-in-itself, which we can only have indirect knowledge of. <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7">
      <p>“Philosophy has been pursued for many centuries by the best minds, and yet everything in it is still disputed and hence doubtful; and I wasn’t so arrogant as to hope to achieve more in philosophy than others had done. Considering how many different opinions learned men may maintain on a single question - where at most one can be true - I regarded everything that was merely probable as being near enough to false.” (Descartes, Discourse on Method) <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:8">
      <p>Two Dogmas of Empiricism, The Philosophical Review, Vol. 60, No. 1, Jan, 1951, pg. 35 <a href="#fnref:8" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:9">
      <p>“At its best, it seems that American analytic philosophy tends toward a radically clear, taut style that one sees particularly in both your work and Nelson Goodman’s.  It reflects a very different spirit from the German philo- sophical prose of someonelike Heidegger.” (W.V. Quine: Perspectives on Logic, Science and Philosophy, The Harvard Review of Philosophy, Spring 1994 p. 56) <a href="#fnref:9" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:10">
      <p>“[Richard Rorty’s position in Philosophy and the Mirror of Nature] shows a bit of the anti-scientific bias that is more extreme in people like Derrida and Heidegger”.  The Harvard Review of Philosophy, Spring 1994 p. 57 <a href="#fnref:10" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:11">
      <p>“The existential analytic of Dasein comes before any psychology or anthropology, and certainly before any biology”. (Heidegger, H. 45 Being and Time). <a href="#fnref:11" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:12">
      <p>These other disciplines, such as the various sciences, are in Heidegger’s terms called regional ontologies, and are all fine and good, but these regional ontologies must be preceded by a proper understanding first laid down in a fundamental ontology of Dasein, which is Heidegger’s task in Being and Time. <a href="#fnref:12" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:13">
      <p>Heidegger  H. 46, Being and Time <a href="#fnref:13" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:14">
      <p>Heidegger  H. 44, Being and Time <a href="#fnref:14" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:15">
      <p>“Here we are seeking that which one inquires into when one asks the question ‘Who?’ By a phenomenological demonstration(1) we shall determine who is in the mode of Dasein’s average everydayness.” (Heidegger H. 53 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:15" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:16">
      <p>“For Scheler, the person is never to be thought of as a Thing or a substance; the person ‘is rather the unity of living-through [Er-lebens] which is immediately experienced in and with our Experiences—not a Thing merely thought of behind and outside what is immediately Experienced’.” (Heidegger H. 47 Being and Time)  Also see H. 48 <a href="#fnref:16" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:17">
      <p>H. 48 <a href="#fnref:17" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:18">
      <p>For Heidegger, it’s perfectly fine to retain the subject-object distinction in regional ontologies such as science, where such terminology is useful in terms of that particular regional ontology. <a href="#fnref:18" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:19">
      <p>“We shall not get a genuine knowledge of essences simply by the syncretistic activity of universal comparison and classification.” (Heidegger H. 52 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:19" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:20">
      <p>“…[man’s Being] is not something we can simply compute by adding together those kinds of Being which body, soul, and spirit respectively possess - kinds of Being whose nature has not as yet been determined.” (Heidegger H. 49 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:20" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:21">
      <p>“So if one is to put various pictures of the world in order, one must have an explicit idea of the world as such. And if the ‘world’ itself is something constitutive for Dasein, one must have an insight into Dasein’s basic structures in order to treat the world-phenomenon conceptually.” (Heidegger H. 52 Being and Time).  Also “In interpreting these entities within-the-world, however, we have always ‘presupposed’ the world. Even if we join them together, we still do not get anything like the ‘world’ as their sum.” (H. 72) <a href="#fnref:21" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:22">
      <p>“But while Being-in-the-world cannot be broken up into contents which may be pieced together, this does not prevent it from having several constitutive items in its structure.” (Heidegger H. 53 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:22" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:23">
      <p>(Heidegger H. 54 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:23" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:24">
      <p>“But subject and Object do not coincide with Dasein and the world.” (Heidegger H. 60 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:24" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:25">
      <p>As in the case of another existential, being-with: “Being-with is such that the disclosedness of the Dasein-with of Others belongs to it; this means that because Dasein’s Being is Being-with, its understanding of Being already implies the understanding of Others. This understanding, like any understanding, is not an acquaintance derived from knowledge about them, but a primordially existential kind of Being, which, more than anything else, makes such knowledge and aquaintance possible.” (Heidegger H. 124 Being and Time) <a href="#fnref:25" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:26">
      <p>“From Heidegger’s point of view, the hermeneutical circle is not a method, rather, it is the existential character of human understanding, so, he describes the circle in terms of an existential grounding. The hermeneutical circle is the existential condition of human understanding and is an essential attribute of Dasein’s knowledge. Thus the circle of understanding is not a methodological circle, making it unnecessary for us at the end of the process of interpretation, but it describes an element of the ontological structure of understanding. An understanding is fundamentally circular. Heidegger appeals to the hermeneutical circle in order to express the existential fore‐structure of Dasein - according to his view, understanding ontologically occurs in a circular manner. The world of Dasein is the mental horizon of Dasein that consists of its presuppositions, expectations, attitudes and beliefs.” (The Hermeneutical Reflections of Heidegger, Ahmad Vaezi, Transcendent Philosophy, Volume 3, Number 3, September 2002) <a href="#fnref:26" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:27">
      <p>For synthetic truths, the empiricists believes in the verification theory of meaning, roughly the belief that “…every meaningful statement is held to be translatable into a statement (true or false) about immediate experience.” (Two Dogmas of Empiricism, The Philosophical Review, Vol. 60, No. 1, Jan, 1951, pg. 36) <a href="#fnref:27" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:28">
      <p>Two Dogmas of Empiricism, The Philosophical Review, Vol. 60, No. 1, Jan, 1951, pg. 20 <a href="#fnref:28" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:29">
      <p>Heidegger and Quine on the (Ir)relevance of Logic For Philosophy, A House Divided, pg. 179 <a href="#fnref:29" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-politics-tv-body-mind-truth/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-13T17:06:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-politics-tv-body-mind-truth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can’t be bothered to be bored with non-junk.  We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways.  We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.</p>

<p>We are attracted to politicians for their image over all else. Never mind the arguments, or the truth which all politicians unabashedly lay claim to.  Did they speak in a confident way at the last debate? That’s what I really care about.  Because confidence is what we really need in a leader, over all else. Did they provide nice entertaining zingers in rebuttal to their opponent?  Because those witty one-liners are what we need to lead the free world.</p>

<p>Did someone sniffle during the last debate? Did someone stumble over their words? Did someone physically stumble and need help getting into their van?  Did Mr. Funny Man With A Funny Name ask a question at the debate?  I forgot what question he asked, or what the answers were.  What brand was his sweater?  I’d like to wear it this Halloween so I can poke fun at people who don’t appear super polished on TV.  These are the things that really matter.</p>

<p>This is no doubt the era of image politics, not issue politics (arguably this has been happening since the Kennedy-Nixon debates…).</p>

<p>Just like junk image politics, junk TV is more entertaining than non-junk TV, and we are attracted to it like flies to garbage. Cable TV has become a cesspool, and not coincidentally. Networks have found what people are attracted to, and maximized its airing time in order to maximize viewers.  Create masses of junk, and people will flock to it.</p>

<p>And food!  We are attracted to junk food, and not just snacks - even junk added to our main meals. I would argue that the staple food of the US is now sugar. It’s in everything. We eat it with abandon and oftentimes unknowingly. Without regard for long-term effects and without regard for how it affects our bodies and minds.</p>

<p>Because we have a God-given American right to eat what we want, just like our forefathers intended.  George Washington would be proud that I ate a fruit rollup for breakfast, followed by two burgers for lunch.</p>

<p>And we defend our body images in all shapes and sizes, because we have a right to it, dammit.  And we are beautiful and healthy regardless of what anyone says. I have a right to live my life the way I want to, without regard for what anyone else says. That’s the American Way©, after all (copyrighted by North American Coca-Cola).</p>

<p>We defend our version of the truth, because we have a God-given right to it. I have a right to believe what I want to. It’s the American Way to live my life and believe what I want to.  If you question or challenge me, you are attacking my very way of life.  And that’s super unamerican.</p>

<p>We defend the position of our in-group, and anything said against that position is an attack on the in-group itself. We have a right to our position, and it’s more important to show confidence and unwavering commitment to that position than to show hesitancy and a wavering opinion.  And we like to blast our politicians for waffling on positions, never thinking that maybe it’s healthy to reassess beliefs over time.  I’m gonna stick to my guns on this one.</p>

<p>America is undoubtedly in a decline.</p>

<p>And we have a God-given right to be in decline, dammit!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-04T00:32:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><figure itemprop='image' itemscope itemtype='http://schema.org/ImageObject' class='center'><meta itemprop='width' content='1000'><meta itemprop='height' content='666'><meta itemprop='url' content='http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg'><img itemprop='contentUrl' src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg" width="1000" height="666" title="Haleakala sunset" ><figcaption itemprop='caption'>Haleakala sunset</figcaption></figure></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We’re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks?  And it’s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who’s bored is asleep, and somebody who’s asleep will not say no?<br />From <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRBZDmf1jSw">My Dinner With Andre</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unless I die young, I haven’t quite made it to my midlife crisis yet.  But it does seem to me that I’ve heard more and more about people experiencing their “quarter-life” crises.  Is this something new?  Or have people always had so many of these doubting periods?  Or maybe we’re at a time where so many of us have the freedom and luxury to even contemplate such a thing, a freedom that leads to our own detriment.</p>

<p>I’m admittedly not great at math, but it does seem to me these quarter-life crises should occur in someone’s early 20’s.  Is that crisis somehow supposed to eventually pass, or just it just get quietly ignored while we distract ourselves with other concerns?  Then we learn to get comfortably numb and sleepy and learn to accept life for how mundane it really is?  Can a midlife crisis still re-emerge later on in life, after a person wakes up again?</p>

<p>I’m fairly certain I’ve been asleep these past few years.  I wouldn’t be surprised, since I do like to sleep (I sometimes waste entire weekends on the couch or in bed, but that’s another story).</p>

<p>I’m too old for these childish quarter-life crises.  The only explanation for this current one is that I must’ve graduated to the rarely-if-ever-mentioned third-life crisis.  A relevant question to ask myself here: just how many damn life crises is it normal for someone to have, and do they ever stop?</p>

<p>In my 20’s I graduated college, had a choice of career paths and started to float and drift a bit, getting a job testing cellphone games.  There I made some friends, but it didn’t really advance my career or my personal life outside of that.</p>

<p>I got older, I worked more, I got a job at a big corporate job, doing what I thought was a decent career.  But I learned that big corporate jobs are soul-numbing.  I quit my big corporate job and did the inevitable clichéd trip to Asia.  Particularly in my field, folks seem to get the same idea.  (Not unlike other things I suppose: Everyone wants to travel to Asia, everyone wants to move to Portland or Austin, everyone wants to save up for a house, everyone wants a Tesla).</p>

<p>That experience traveling helped me grow as a person more than any job ever did, but apparently I didn’t grow or learn enough, because I found myself falling into the same pattern as before.  Get the comfortable corporate job, dance like a monkey if I wanted to advance and get promoted, then try to save up for a house like everyone else.</p>

<p>The idiotic Silicon Valley version: save up for a down payment on a ridiculously overpriced house that’s in the bad part of town and also falling apart (because that’s the only one you can afford making comparative chump change to everyone else).  Maybe also save up for a Tesla, so at the very least you can brag to your coworkers that you bought a Tesla.  Because Tesla.</p>

<p>Then you get a job at what’s supposed to be the Best Place To Work In The Universe, according to a survey of all known workers in the universe.  You find that it’s not too much different than your previous Big Corporate Job.  Is this really all there is to look forward to?  So I can buy a house and a Tesla?  What next after that even?  Work the rest of the best years of my life paying off the house?</p>

<p>What if I don’t want a house (though not sharing walls would be nice)?  What if I don’t want a Tesla?  I don’t think I’m the only one.  I think all those folks who quit their jobs to travel the world likely have the same feelings.  They’re trying to escape from something.  Their inner selves seem to have woken up from a nightmare in the night, and are restlessly awake, pacing back and forth.  Except they’re pacing through the world, not just their bedrooms.</p>

<p>Some of these folks even get the idea that the ideal lifestyle is being a traveling nomad, hopping from country to country, somehow earning enough money to get by.  If they can make it work, I think they do tend to be happier, or at least more alive and more childlike and inquisitive.  Is it just the permanent change in scenery?  I’m not sure I’d be comfortable in that sort of lifestyle myself.  It is always nice to come back home eventually, and to spend time with familiar friends and family, and familiar things in general.  Sometimes it’s nice to be a little hobbit-like.</p>

<p>Is all this travelling and escaping just a delaying of inevitable adulthood?  What if I’m already an adult - does it mean I’m just deceiving myself?  Am I running away from myself?  Is adulthood really just the acceptance that you’re not special, that this really is the only thing life is about?  That your life is the thing that happens for a few brief hours after work, and entire weekends that you may end up wasting on stupid pursuits?</p>

<p>As much as philosophy has helped me, in cases like this I think it’s kind of made me dissatisfied with everything.</p>

<p>Maybe I can still somehow play and enjoy the game of life, even if I realize it’s only some silly game we’ve concocted to keep ourselves busy?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
