<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: yosemite | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/yosemite/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-04T17:23:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My year in photos (2016)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T23:17:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014/">part one</a> and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014-part-2/">part two</a>).  I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!</p>

<p>Onto the pics!</p>

<h2 id="february">February</h2>

<p>I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-01-feb-yosemite-night-sky.jpg 1000 666 Night sky from Yosemite %}</p>

<p>For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.  I was super happy with the way this turned out.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-02-feb-pinecrest-lake-in-snow.jpg 1000 666 Pinecrest Lake in the snow (California, near Yosemite) %}</p>

<p>Interesting tree stumps around Pinecrest Lake area, in the snow.</p>

<h2 id="march">March</h2>

<p>At the end of March, I quit my job and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again/">ended up in Japan again</a> for the next few months!</p>

<p>One of my favorite photos from the entire several months was taken from the first night at the hotel.  I had a corner room in the Star Gate hotel, which towers over south Osaka and has a great view of the Kansai International Airport.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-03-march-kansai-international-airport.jpg 666 1000 Kansai International Airport seen from the Star Gate Hotel in Osaka, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-04-march-kyoto-sparrow-and-cherry-blossoms.jpg 666 1000 Sparrow and cherry blossoms on the Path of Philosophy in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<h2 id="april">April</h2>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-05-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-06-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-07-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-08-april-kyoto-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto backstreets at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-09-april-nara-monju-e-ceremony.jpg 1000 666 Nara Monju-e Ceremony %}</p>

<p>(<a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara/">see more photos and video from the Nara Monju-e Ceremony</a>)</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-10-april-nara-deer-and-lantern.jpg 666 1000 Nara deer and traditional lantern %}</p>

<p>I’ve always wanted to ride the shinkansen (bullet train) as far north as I could, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/">I finally did it</a>.  I boarded the bullet train in Kyoto and ended up at its terminus in Hakodate.  The final stretch of bullet train to Hakodate had only opened days before, and they were still celebrating its completion.</p>

<p>They’re currently building the final stretch from Hakodate to Sapporo, but it’s not due to be complete until sometime in the 2030s or so.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-11-april-rainy-shinkansen.jpg 1000 666 Rainy day on the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-12-april-northern-japan-coast.jpg 1000 666 The coast of northern Japan, seen from the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>This isn’t a super great photo, but I thought it was interesting for a few reasons.  There were these stone markers occassionally by the tracks.  And there was also a whole lot of trash, mostly fisherman trash like baubles.</p>

<p>Kind of surprising how much trash was along the coast here, especially for Japan’s reputation for cleanliness.  Was this remants of the 2011 tsunami?  Well, it’s five years later and this stuff is still here…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-13-april-hakodate-sunset.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate sunset %}</p>

<p>Hakodate is a fun little town.  Of course I had to take the tram up to the top of Mount Hakodate, then watch the sunset with all the other tourists…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-14-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-15-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view - the reality of the crowds.  Absolutely packed. %}</p>

<p>Mount Hakodate at sunset was swarming with tourists.  I’m glad I did it once, but I wouldn’t do it again.</p>

<p>Around Hakodate there was this trendy hamburger place called Lucky Pierrot, which looked more like a carnival.  They had some interesting vending machines propped up outside their shop.  Looked like something out of a video game:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-16-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-17-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>Sapporo was still a bit snowy in April!</p>

<p>…And I was totally unprepared.  I took some photos, then had to duck inside somewhere to warm up.  I found a mall with some ramen restaurants and a Uniqlo - both of which had things that could help me warm up.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-18-april-sapporo-ramen.jpg 666 1000 Delicious Sapporo ramen %}</p>

<h2 id="may">May</h2>

<p>In May I visited Indonesia with Yuka, but I was too afraid to bring my DSLR, which was a stupid idea in retrospect.  I took some video there, and took lots of photos with my phone, which I guess I’ll have to post eventually.</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/the-roads-of-indonesia/">Here you can watch a Muslim parade</a>, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/indonesia-trip-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/">here you can listen to me ramble on about my experience in Indonesia</a>.</p>

<p>When I came back to Japan, it was time to explore some more!</p>

<p>I returned to Byodoin Temple in Nara, which had been restored to its original vermillion colors since my last visit a few years back:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-19-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-20-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-21-may-kyoto-aqua-marine-diving-school.jpg 1000 666 Aqua Marine Diving School (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>This probably isn’t a super interesting photo for you, but I actually walked past this, then thought better of it and walked back to snap a photo, because I thought it was just interesting.  It jumped out again for me when going through my photos, so I had to include it among my favorites just for the subject matter.  The hiragana reads “Diving School”.</p>

<p>Yuka had been wanting to take me up to Mount Rokko for a while.  It was a fun experience riding the cable car to the top, then eating some good food at the top.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-22-may-mount-rokko-cable-car.jpg 666 1000 Accidental self-portrait, and a view from the Mount Rokko cable car (Osaka, Japan) %}</p>

<h2 id="june">June</h2>

<p>In June I tried something new: I gave myself a photo assignment.  Just to go out on a mission, and come back with some tangible decent photos.</p>

<p>I know Kyoto is amazing at night, with lots of things to discover in the nooks and crannies of the city I’ve spent the last few years exploring.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-23-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-24-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 1000 666 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>I posted a few more photos from my Kyoto photo assignment <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/">here</a>.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-25-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>I had mixed emotions about visiting Shirakawago, a UNESCO World Heritage site with a bunch of interesting old thatched houses.  The place was incredibly touristy, and I had a run-in with some pushy Japanese grandmas who unabashedly cut in line in front of me at a gift shop.</p>

<p>It was an interesting place - I may be back eventually in the winter, which is the more common time to take photos of the truly interesting old-fashioned houses.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-26-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-27-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-28-june-kamogawa-sparrows.jpg 1000 666 Sparrows playing beside the Kamogawa (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>I brought my DSLR to a short weekend trip to Busan with Yuka, but didn’t take many good photos there.  I did like this one shot of a cute dog in a traditional market though:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-29-june-dog-in-korea.jpg 666 1000 Cute dog (Busan, Korea) %}</p>

<h2 id="october">October</h2>

<p>Back in the US!</p>

<p>I took a few road trips, especially to capture the changing seasons in California.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-30-oct-june-lake-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains seen from June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-31-oct-june-lake.jpg 1000 666 Boat docked at June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32-oct-mono-lake-alien-moonrise.jpg 1000 666 Alien moonrise on the shores of Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32b-oct-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Mono Lake at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-33-oct-mountains-view-from-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowy mountains at night, seen from Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-34-oct-lake-sabrina-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains at Lake Sabrina %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-35-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Lundy Lake sunrise %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-36-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowcapped mountains seen from Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-37-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors along Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-38-oct-road-to-lobdell-lake-fall-colors.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors on the road to Lobdell Lake (California) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-39-oct-drive-back-to-san-bernardino-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Intense storm clouds seen on the drive back to the San Bernardino mountains %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-40-oct-fall-leaves-in-big-bear.jpg 1000 666 Fall leaves on a brick walkway, at home in Big Bear %}</p>

<h2 id="november">November</h2>

<p>My mom spontaneously booked a trip to New Orleans, and I agreed to tag along.  It was a nice return to a truly interesting city.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-41-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 The lobby of the W Hotel French Quarter (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-42-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square seen from the steamboat Natchez, on the Missisippi River %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-43-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Chartres %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-44-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 “At Rest” gravestone in a New Orleans cemetery %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-45-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Statue near the French Market: Michelle by sculptor Paul Perret (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-46-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square at night with the largest supermoon in decades (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-47-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 S. Andral Kilmer, M.D. Swamp Root medicine at the LSU Rural Life Museum  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-48-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Swamp trees in Louisiana %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-49-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Turtle sunbathing on the swamp %}</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/">See more photos from my New Orleans trip</a>.</p>

<h2 id="december">December</h2>

<p>One last road trip of the year!  Just before Christmas, I took a drive to Zion National Park.  I am definitely returning to this beautiful place, and I’m already planning future hikes and photo shoots here.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-50-dec-desert-near-baker.jpg 1000 666 Desert sunset, near Baker, Nevada %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-51-dec-zion.jpg 666 1000 Sandstone and ice (Zion National Park) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-52-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-53-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty Towers of the Virgin mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-54-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-19T19:05:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-07-18-milky-way-over-trees-yosemite-valley-david-calhoun-5D__3685.jpg 666 1000 Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am  %}</p>

<p>Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total.  The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.</p>

<p>While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky.  It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</p>

<p>My eyes started to track it across the sky, but it almost looked like it was dancing instead of advancing steadily.  It was going stop-go but very smoothly.</p>

<p>At this point I should mention that I’d drank much more coffee than I really should have, in preparation for the long drive.  Despite all the coffee I was getting very tired, which made for a bad combination with driving.</p>

<p>I think the dancing of the satellite was due to the effects of the coffee, that or it was just a natural optical illusion.</p>

<p>The satellite went behind some trees, and soon after that I saw a very bright star emerge over the mountains on the other side of the trees.</p>

<p>Must be a UFO!</p>

<p>I looked at the star intently, and could swear I could see it dancing as well, though a bit more stationary.  It was also changing colors - red, blue, white.  Obviously a very patriotic UFO.</p>

<p>My delirium-fueled excitement was pushing me to get out my super telephoto, which is exactly what I did.  Here I with the perfect equipment, tripod, and RAW video capabilities!  A really good UFO video to post to YouTube!</p>

<p>But nope.  Zoomed in on a tripod, it was clear it was a fairly stationary star, only moving progressively with the backdrop of the other stars in Yosemite’s real-life planetarium.</p>

<p>It was clear it was time to head to bed.  Who knows what else I’d start seeing after a while…</p>

<p>Parked somewhere in a gravel parking lot near Camp Curry and slept in my car (whoohoo for being single and getting to save money).</p>

<p>It was around 4am when I was finally getting to sleep.</p>

<p>Written at the top of Nevada Falls, Yosemite</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-07-18-international-space-station-and-capella.png 375 667 The “UFO” turned out to be the International Space Station, and when it appeared to come out of the trees over the mountain on the right, it was actually Capella  %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A ride on Yosemite's Sugar Pine Railroad]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-16T21:41:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1787.jpg 1000 666 Front view of the Sugar Pine Railroad  %}</p>

<p>On my last trip to Yosemite, I tagged along with my friends Kevin and Mari.  The first day we hiked in rain to the base of Upper Yosemite Falls.  By the second day, we were tired and looking for something quick and relaxing to do before driving back.</p>

<p>We decided to check out the Sugar Pine Railroad, which was right next to their hotel.</p>

<p>I remember passing by the railroad when I went to Yosemite with Yuka, and she seemed really excited to check it out.  Regrettably we didn’t have any time on that trip, and I sort of dismissed it as a tourist trap.</p>

<p>Yep, it’s a tourist trap.  But it’s historical and interesting, and it was fun to relax and take a ride on the old steam engine.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1772.jpg 1000 666 Side view  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1761.jpg 1000 666 Front side view.  “Lima Locomotive Works Incorporated March 1928”  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1765.jpg 1000 666 Front side view  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1773.jpg 1000 666 Lots o’ grease!  Come and get it.  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1777.jpg 1000 666 “Patented February 18, 1908”  %}</p>

<p>On the last stretch of the journey, there was a bunch of steam that came out of the side of the railroad.  I don’t really understand the reason for this - to let out pressure maybe?</p>

<p>Or maybe a good spectable for the tourists?  :)</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1796.jpg 1000 666 Releasing the steam.  Something for the tourists?  %}</p>

<p>We sat right next to the loudspeaker.  I’d advise against that.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-04-27-sugar-pine-railroad-5D__1802.jpg 1000 666 Don’t sit by the loudspeaker!  It’s quite loud.  %}</p>

<p>Note: all photos copyright David Calhoun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
