<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidbcalhoun.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2018)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</guid>
      <description>When the year&amp;rsquo;s days shorten and their number dwindles, I have liked to sometimes take the initiative to sort through all the photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken (with my &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; camera). The eventual goal: to put together a sampling of the photos that stand out, sometimes for technical reasons, and sometimes for other reasons.
This year I sadly didn&amp;rsquo;t get out with the camera as much as I have in previous years, which made this post much easier (no excuses this year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Introduction to Javascript Map and Reduce Array Helper Functions</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2018/a-simple-introduction-to-javascript-map-and-reduce-array-helper-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2018/a-simple-introduction-to-javascript-map-and-reduce-array-helper-functions/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve been programming for a while, and you&amp;rsquo;re pretty comfortable using for loops to traverse Arrays. However, you know how untidy and complicated for loops can get, and you are interested in better approaches to keep the code clean. Enter map and reduce!
First steps with for loops Most folks find for loops powerful enough to achieve all they need when they need to process items in an Array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behold the Birds of the Air (Soren Kierkegaard)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/behold-the-birds-of-the-air-soren-kierkegaard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 13:29:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/behold-the-birds-of-the-air-soren-kierkegaard/</guid>
      <description>From Soren Kierkegaard&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Upbuilding Discourses in Various Spirits&amp;rdquo;
(this excerpt is from Provocations, excerpts from Kierkegaard, Plough)
Once upon a time there was a wood dove. It had its nest in the fearsome forest, where wonder and apprehension dwelt together, among the erect, lonely trees. But nearby, where the smoke rises up from the farmer”s house, lived some tame doves. The wood dove would often meet a pair of these. He would sit on a branch that stretched out over the farmyard, not far from the two tame doves on the ridge of the roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stifling Laughter in Distant Places</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 20:10:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</guid>
      <description>New Cultures The first days of traveling usually involves laughing at the quaint and unusual customs of another culture. That sounds close-minded, because in many cases it probably is. But it&amp;rsquo;s something we all do, of course including yours truly. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a coping mechanism - laughing at things in the face of difficulties and differences.
To be fair, we&amp;rsquo;re thinking creatures, and as such it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard for us not to draw comparisons with our own home city and culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new photography YouTube channel</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 11:23:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while without an update.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working more and more on my photography endeavors, which includes building up a YouTube channel to document my travels and also my learnings. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it&amp;rsquo;s interesting and useful enough, especially for other aspiring photographers.
This year is definitely shaping up to be a year of travelling, and I&amp;rsquo;d also like to keep a blog of photos and such, so I&amp;rsquo;m working to get a separate photography blog setup at my photography website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning thoughts on the idea of a Great American Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 22:35:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/</guid>
      <description>The idea of a trip across the United States has become somewhat of an American institution. Something like a New American Dream, this one maybe a bit more accessible than that house, happy life, and nuclear family with 2.5 kids. It&amp;rsquo;s something that is undertaken by both the young and the old, with the former perhaps hitchhiking or sleeping in their cars while the latter leapfrog between National Parks in their expensive and comfortable motor homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans trip (November 2016)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:51:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I had the opportunity to visit New Orleans in the spring with my friend. Now I&amp;rsquo;ve returned with my parents to visit in the fall!
My mom had recently expressed a desire to do more travelling while still physically able, which kicked off creating a list of places to visit, and ultimately booking this first trip. Hopefully the first of many to come. She asked if I wanted to tag along, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass up another visit to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe it&#39;s healthier to embrace discomfort</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 09:35:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</guid>
      <description>Many folks, including yours truly, have had an unpleasant night, and this morning a bitter awakening at the announcement that our new President will be Trump. For most folks this comes as a shock, as we have all thought the chances of this happening were slim. Comedians chided him on and dared him to run. Even President Obama who continually roasted him at the White House Correspondents&amp;rsquo; Dinner in 2011, arguably the defining moment when Trump became driven to run for President (&amp;ldquo;He certainly would bring some change to the White House&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quine and Heidegger: Against Reductionism</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 22:15:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I had the opportunity to attend my first philosophy class in about a decade. The class was on the infamous philosopher Martin Heidegger, and the course was taught at Stanford University by Forrest Hartman (PHI 98: An Introduction to Martin Heidegger (Spring 2016)).
Heidegger is famous for being obscure and notoriously difficult to read, but I believe I made some headway in what turned out to be a very interesting philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:06:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</guid>
      <description>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to be bored with non-junk. We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways. We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for autumn adventures</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/time-for-autumn-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 16:06:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/time-for-autumn-adventures/</guid>
      <description>Maple leaves at Tofukuji Temple, Kyoto  It&amp;rsquo;s autumn again. The temperatures are dropping up here in the mountains of Big Bear, especially at night, when it&amp;rsquo;s now approaching freezing or below. A surprising number of trees are changing colors. I say surprising because this is California, after all, and we don&amp;rsquo;t usually see fall colors unless we know where to look.
The aspens are of course doing their thing and changing from green to yellow, and there are other surprising splashes of red and orange as I drive through the neighborhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monty Python and the Holy Grail (1975) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monty-python-and-the-holy-grail-1975-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 19:36:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monty-python-and-the-holy-grail-1975-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>This is a movie in the same spirit as the Marx Brothers’ Duck Soup: essentially a string of crazy anarchic skits held together weakly by some central theme. The story isn&amp;rsquo;t strong, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be and it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be. It&amp;rsquo;s just there as a sort of skeleton to hang all the skits on.
As a movie, this feels to me to be strangely out of place in the top 100 movies, maybe because it&amp;rsquo;s such a low budget production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo assignment: Kyoto alleyways at night</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:15:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Before setting off on my current trip, I wanted to give myself at least one &amp;ldquo;photo assignment&amp;rdquo;: some goal I could aim to accomplish by pretending like I&amp;rsquo;d been given an assignment by some employer.
This is the first of what I hope will be many. The assignment here is to try to capture the atmosphere of eastern Kyoto&amp;rsquo;s traditional streets at night.
A couple of things I had to plan for: Kyoto is a bit far from my hostel in Osaka, so I made sure to make a day trip out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival Parade Hadrah 2016 (Muslim parade in Solo, Indonesia)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/festival-parade-hadrah-2016-muslim-parade-in-solo-indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 08:52:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/festival-parade-hadrah-2016-muslim-parade-in-solo-indonesia/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia trip: the good, the bad, the ugly</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/indonesia-trip-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:26:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/indonesia-trip-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The roads of Indonesia</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/the-roads-of-indonesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:50:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/the-roads-of-indonesia/</guid>
      <description>The biggest culture shock of Indonesia had to be the bathroom facilities, but that&amp;rsquo;s best saved for another post. The second biggest culture shock had to be the roads, and the drivers on them.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never been to any third world Asian country before, so the idea of seeing roads dominated by scooters and motorcycles was really a foreign concept to me. This also meant that the style of driving is way different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shinkansen trip from Kyoto to Sapporo</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 11:25:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/</guid>
      <description>Rinku town and Kansai Airport at night  (I wrote this one a few weeks back but didn&amp;rsquo;t post the pics until now, so here it is in its complete form!).
I&amp;rsquo;ve been here in Japan for a month and in true form haven&amp;rsquo;t provided much in the way of updates since then. Doh.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a catch-up post, with plenty of pictures and videos to keep things interesting.
 Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy   Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy  Spring in Japan again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monju-e Ceremony in Nara (文殊会 興福寺)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 22:34:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</guid>
      <description> From April 25, 2016.
Monju or Manjusri is a bodhisattva of wisdom. In this ceremony children’s healthy growth and academic success are prayed for.
14:30~ A procession of children in traditional costumes. Starts from Jyokyoji Temple on Sanjyo St. towards Kofukuji Temple.
15:00~ Ritual ceremony at Tokondo Hall in Kofukuji Temple
文殊会 (興福寺) 毎月25日は文殊菩薩の縁日。東金堂の文殊菩薩は古くから学問僧の信仰を集めてきた。­文殊会では文殊菩薩の智恵を授かろうと稚児の行列が、浄教寺より一字書の奉額車を引い­て三条通りを練り歩きます。 なお、当日堂内の拝観は14時までですが、外からの拝観は可能。（受付終了は13時4­5分）
                                                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan once again: update from the Banana House in Osaka</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again-update-from-the-banana-house-in-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 19:44:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again-update-from-the-banana-house-in-osaka/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Japan for the past few weeks, and have been lazy about updating my blog, which I promised to do! I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy sorting through pictures!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a video update from where I&amp;rsquo;ll be staying long term at a place called the Banana House:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 mile Big Basin hike</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/11-mile-big-basin-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 08:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/11-mile-big-basin-hike/</guid>
      <description>GPS track log  See the interactive GPS track log here.
I really needed to get out of Silicon Valley again and go experience nature, so on Sunday I drove over to my favorite hiking spot, Big Basin. There&amp;rsquo;s a $10 fee to get in and park, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it considering it&amp;rsquo;s about the price of a movie and much more rewarding.
I arrived right after the park opened and started my hike to Berry Creek Falls at 8:20am, which is probably the earliest I&amp;rsquo;ve started there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casablanca (1942) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/casablanca-1942-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:31:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/casablanca-1942-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Casablanca more than a few times, and it&amp;rsquo;s become one of my favorite films. For this review I got to experience it in 35mm at the wonderful nearby Stanford Theatre.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not how I first experienced it. I first watched it at home and half paid attention to it. A lot of the movie was lost on me and I thought it was overrated, just ok, and not that great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schindler&#39;s List (1993) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:27:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>Schindler&#39;s List title card with candles  This is a film that is best experienced, not explained in a post like this. However, that being said, I&amp;rsquo;ll give this a try anyhow.
I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided this film all my life out of dread more than anything. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat weird then that I watched this so early in my &amp;ldquo;Top 100&amp;rdquo; films quest. I knew I&amp;rsquo;d have to watch it eventually anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikiru (1952) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/ikiru-1952-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 21:43:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/ikiru-1952-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>IKIRU, 生きる, TO LIVE  This is an existentialist story about a man who learns he has stomach cancer, leading to his reconsidering of life, which he realizes has been utterly wasted up until this point.
As it turns out, he realizes he hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been living at all. What&amp;rsquo;s inadvertently happened is that his job has turned into his life - the job of being section chief at one of the endless wasteful government bureaucracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Through The Top 100 Films</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/a-journey-through-the-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 09:26:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/a-journey-through-the-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of January, which means the beginning of a new year. And you know what that means - a time for making resolutions that will probably not be kept! Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see how far this one goes&amp;hellip;
Instead of wasting away my time playing video games, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take a bit more seriously another passion: watching movies. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to make this constructive by reviewing each of the top 100 movies, many of which I&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting down and watching for the very first time, and many of which are old favorites that I&amp;rsquo;ll be rewatching, unfortunately not with fresh eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Basin October Hike</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/big-basin-october-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 01:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/big-basin-october-hike/</guid>
      <description>GPS track log  See the interactive GPS track log here.
On Sunday I grabbed two sandwiches at Le Boulanger, and headed for a late hike in Big Basin, which is my favorite place to hike in the area. The drive from my apartment in Sunnyvale is almost an hour and a half, and the fee to park is $10, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it to go and spend time there once and a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile personals ad</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/agile-personals-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 20:12:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/agile-personals-ad/</guid>
      <description>(In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t guess, this is a parody. Please dont send me emails!)
I’m looking to find a fit and lean partner who can iterate rapidly on our relationship. The MVP for this partner is someone who can keep me entertained with user stories. Bonus point if the stories have a point (or several, as long as we keep to fibonacci numbers, which I have a strange fetish for).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:32:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Haleakala sunset   Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We&amp;rsquo;re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks? And it&amp;rsquo;s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who&amp;rsquo;s bored is asleep, and somebody who&amp;rsquo;s asleep will not say no?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick failed trip to Pinnacles National Park</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:40:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d been looking for a night like tonight for a long time, when the new moon fell squarely on the weekend. The only problem: unpredictable weather!
I drive about an hour and a half south on the 101 and then the 25 to head towards the east Pinnacles entrance, which I&amp;rsquo;d never been at before. I also chatted with Yuka over LINE for a bit of it, at least until the reception got bad and dropped the call about ten minutes beofre getting to the park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 19:05:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am  Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total. The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.
While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky. It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ride on Yosemite&#39;s Sugar Pine Railroad</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 21:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad/</guid>
      <description>Front view of the Sugar Pine Railroad  On my last trip to Yosemite, I tagged along with my friends Kevin and Mari. The first day we hiked in rain to the base of Upper Yosemite Falls. By the second day, we were tired and looking for something quick and relaxing to do before driving back.
We decided to check out the Sugar Pine Railroad, which was right next to their hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existential nights</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:05:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</guid>
      <description>These damn existential nights are the worst.
I&amp;rsquo;m tired of wasting my nights distracting myself, so I stayed at work late and went to the gym even later, then left around 10:45pm.
Even while exercising I could feel me asking myself nagging questions. Why am I working out? What&amp;rsquo;s the goal? What&amp;rsquo;s the point of keeping your body healthy if you don&amp;rsquo;t even know where you&amp;rsquo;re going?
These are important questions, but not the right questions when I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourist season in Japan, and a brief escape to Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 23:20:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>Inside Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan (Photo copyright David Calhoun)  (I originally wrote this while sitting in Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan)
I&amp;rsquo;m visiting Japan again, when part of me is constantly thinking I should instead be spending the time and money exploring other parts of the world.
I guess I just find myself coming back to the familiar and (somewhat) comfortable. I find that I have the same habit when returning to a restaurant, and ordering the same item from the menu each and every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beatitudes</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:29:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted.
Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth.
Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied.
Blessed are the merciful, for they shall obtain mercy.
Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.
Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The surprising benefits of going to the gym</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 21:40:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s well into the new year, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly start the new year off like everyone else, who I imagine all rushed daily into the gym in the first week or two, then apparently gave the habit up soon after.
Sometime in February I found out about a study being conducted at my workplace in conjunction with a university, to track the effects of exercise over the course of a month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living as driftwood</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 21:52:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two photo posts I wanted to avoid this sort of heavy reflection New Year post. But its time has finally come and it should be said, no matter how cheesy it may sound.
I have been living these last few years of my life as driftwood. At least professionally. I have all the makings of what should make me happy and successfully in my career, but it&amp;rsquo;s an illusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 2 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>I was just putting together this article and these photos on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve when I glanced and the clock and noticed I was already four minutes into 2015. Oops!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the second-parter for my favorite photo from 2014. Also be sure to check out the first part.
July Yuka was still here in early July, just in time to see Fourth of July fireworks at Big Bear Lake, California, before she had to go back to Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 1 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s nearing the year&amp;rsquo;s end, so of course this means a somewhat sentimental blog post from me. I was thinking of a &amp;ldquo;resolutions/goals&amp;rdquo; type post, but I decided against it. Instead here&amp;rsquo;s something more entertaining: my favorite photos from the past year! Note that these aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily my best, just my favorites.
Finding these is also a little bit of housekeeping for me and my photos. It forces me to sort the gigabytes and gigabytes of RAW photos I was casually dumping onto drives the entire year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The City Is A Medium, The Medium Is The Message</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 19:11:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</guid>
      <description>Vendors along Kamogawa River for the Tanabata (七夕) star festival in Kyoto (Photo by David Calhoun, 2011)  I had always heard of Marshall McCluhan&amp;rsquo;s famous &amp;ldquo;the medium is the message&amp;rdquo;, but really only had a surface level understanding of it until recently, when I first read the essay.
It&amp;rsquo;s a somewhat eye-opening and challenging piece for various reasons, because it challenges some things I thought I had a good grasp of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>async.parallel with a simple timeout (node.js)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/async.parallel-with-a-simple-timeout-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 00:36:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/async.parallel-with-a-simple-timeout-node.js/</guid>
      <description>A while back I had a need for a general timeout option for async.parallel and was surprised I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find much information about how to do it. I was using async.parallel to make a lot of REST calls in parallel, but one of them was getting blocked by a firewall, resulting in an eventual timeout minutes later.
One option was to specify a shorter timeout for each individual REST call, including the one causing the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 23:12:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui (at the Mauian hotel)  I was lucky enough to finally visit Hawaii with my parents. Being experts Hawaii tourists, they set us up in a nice traditional resort called The Mauian - a nice quiet(er) little place that has a time for &amp;ldquo;quiet hours&amp;rdquo; (apparently the other resorts are places to party).
We got back to the hotel a little after quiet hours, and my folks mentioned that you could see the Milky Way quite clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is AMD, CommonJS, and UMD?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/what-is-amd-commonjs-and-umd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 11:59:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/what-is-amd-commonjs-and-umd/</guid>
      <description>Intro Over the years there&amp;rsquo;s been a steadily increasing ecosystem of JavaScript components to choose from. The sheer amount of choices is fantastic, but this also infamously presents a difficulty when components are mixed-and-matched. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too long for budding developers to find out that not all components are built to play nicely together.
To address these issues, the competing module specs AMD and CommonJS have appeared on the scene, allowing developers to write their code in an agreed-upon sandboxed and modularized way, so as not to &amp;ldquo;pollute the ecosystem&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mobile web is dead (and we have killed it)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-mobile-web-is-dead-and-we-have-killed-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-mobile-web-is-dead-and-we-have-killed-it/</guid>
      <description>The mobile web is dead.
(Banner: would you like to download the app?)
The mobile web remains dead.
(Splash screen: download the app!)
And we have killed it.
(JavaScript prompt: &amp;ldquo;Yahoo! can serve you more accurate local weather and news if you enable location services&amp;rdquo;)
Yet its shadow still looms.
(Prompt: Yahoo! would like to use your Current Location)
How shall we comfort ourselves, the murderers of all murderers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Negative Scroll Blur (for browsers that support CSS filters)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/introducing-negative-scroll-blur-for-browsers-that-support-css-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/introducing-negative-scroll-blur-for-browsers-that-support-css-filters/</guid>
      <description>(2016: in retrospect, this is kind of gratuitous and doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be fully working anymore&amp;hellip;)
Demo
Just for fun, I wanted to reproduce a cool but completely superfluous UI I saw in the updated Foursquare app recently. Basically, when the user tries to scroll past the upper bound of the app/page, the header image becomes blurred.
We can do the same thing on the web by listening for negative scroll and then using (abusing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t JavaScript Under Pressure walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/you-cant-javascript-under-pressure-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/you-cant-javascript-under-pressure-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>A friend posted a link to this fun little quiz - You Can&amp;rsquo;t JavaScript Under Pressure.
The quizzes get more and more difficult, and they present a nice challenge if you fear your skills are getting rusty. Give it an honest try first, then come back here if you get seriously, honestly stuck. Try to do it yourself!
Quiz 1: doubleInteger Problem function doubleInteger(i) { // i will be an integer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Google Bitch</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch/</guid>
      <description>When I came back from Japan and accepted an offer to work at a startup in Silicon Valley, I knew one of the biggest challenges would be to find a decent and affordable apartment in Mountain View, close to where I&amp;rsquo;d be working. I had it all planned out, and how healthy and convenient it would be to walk to work and also Mountain View downtown!
Unfortunately, this dream was shared by me and hundreds of thousands of other like-minded software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth of July letter to my government</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</guid>
      <description>(this is a copy of a letter which I&amp;rsquo;ve sent to various representatives in government)
As a concerned citizen, I know you understand that I must occasionally voice my concern through letters such as this. My hope is that you will honestly consider my claims and take action on my part. I honestly appreciate you taking your time to seriously consider this letter.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing to you today specifically in response to abuses by the NSA overstepping its bounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSA&#39;s PRISM: from the minds of conspiracy nuts, turns out to be reality</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</guid>
      <description>The real shame about NSA/PRISM is that everyone will forget about it next week or next month. Just like we forgot about Trapwire and other endless abuses in the name of protecting society.
The US is now a nation too mentally castrated to do anything about these obvious constitutional abuses. Why are we only capable of short-lived and impotent protest attempts like Occupy? How did we get to be so sedated through this anesthesia of modern consumerism and entertainment?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick style comparison of mobile image search sites</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/quick-style-comparison-of-mobile-image-search-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/quick-style-comparison-of-mobile-image-search-sites/</guid>
      <description>The other day I glanced at a classmate using Baidu to perform an image search and was impressed with their presentation:

Note the nice big images and the lack of margins around images. After seeing this presentation, I realized that the common approach of adding margins around images is pretty unnecessary.
I also noticed that the images are a variety of sizes, leading to a less sterile experience. There&amp;rsquo;s surely some clever math going on behind the scenes here to make sure the images appear &amp;ldquo;justified&amp;rdquo; (to use a word from the recent Flickr redesign).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Cherry Blossoms 2013 (京都の桜２０１３年)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/kyoto-cherry-blossoms-2013-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%A1%9C%EF%BC%92%EF%BC%90%EF%BC%91%EF%BC%93%E5%B9%B4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/kyoto-cherry-blossoms-2013-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%A1%9C%EF%BC%92%EF%BC%90%EF%BC%91%EF%BC%93%E5%B9%B4/</guid>
      <description>Cherry blossoms in Kyoto, Japan 2013  Check out my cherry blossoms 2013 set on Flickr.
Japan has a healthy fascination with the beauty of nature, and this includes the ephemeral cherry blossoms. And one of the prime locations for cherry blossoms is Kyoto, Japan.
It takes a while to realize, but there actually seems to be a wide variety of cherry blossoms which blossom at different times. This stretches the season out a bit (the prime blossoming lasts only about a week).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Spring in Kyoto (京都の春)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/video-spring-in-kyoto-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%98%A5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/video-spring-in-kyoto-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%98%A5/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to import imiwa? vocabulary lists directly into Anki (iOS, iPhone guide)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/how-to-import-imiwa-vocabulary-lists-directly-into-anki-ios-iphone-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/how-to-import-imiwa-vocabulary-lists-directly-into-anki-ios-iphone-guide/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: big thanks to my classmate Robin from Switzerland who showed me the key steps to getting this figured out!
For the last six months, I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly been using imiwa? for iOS to look up Japanese words whenever I don&amp;rsquo;t know them (mostly in class). However, I found that I built up big lists without ever reviewing them.
The best way to review is of course through Anki, but it was a laborious process to import each word one-by-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan: from miniature train to bullet train</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</guid>
      <description>Japanese riding a miniature railroad, brought by Perry to Japan  (view the full image, image credit)
A long time ago, four black ships appeared off the coast of Japan, which had closed itself off from the world and its influences. These ships were from the US, and commanding them was Commodore Matthew C. Perry, who was instrumental in reopening Japan to the rest of the world.
As a result of this, and to promote a goodwill between the two countries, Perry gave various gifts to Japan, one of which was a one-fourth scale model train, in order to convincingly demonstrate the benefit of adopting Western technology:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forms of Escapism</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking lately that the fates of so many are motivated by, in a word, escapism. Including my own fate. These are folks whose lives seem quite different on first glance, but turn out to be similar. We can&amp;rsquo;t escape some of our basic human nature after all.
The Preservationist These are folks who, for lack of a better term, wish to preserve a &amp;ldquo;simpler time&amp;rdquo;. They are people such as Thoreau, who wanted a return to simpler times and aspired to self-sufficiency (or an approximation, in any case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A theory of leisure time, choice, and happiness</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</guid>
      <description>This is finally the end of my first week in Japanese language school here in Kyoto. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a long week, with the most studying I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done in my life. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone through nine chapters in a week, and just Friday received two more books for learning Kanji. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn our first 50 Kanji in a week, alongside the rest of our classes. I already know some words here and there, but for the most part, much of what we&amp;rsquo;ve just learned is a blur, which is forcing me to use almost all of my free time in running to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descartes on building software frameworks</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/descartes-on-building-software-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/descartes-on-building-software-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>Rene Descartes  Years ago I read Descartes&amp;rsquo;s Discourse on Method for what I found to be some of the more interesting philosophy courses of my college career: those of the history of modern philosophy. Modern philosophy technically starts with Descartes, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start, or to get re-acquainted with philosophy in general.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading through the Discourse again, and have found it to be more interesting and relatable this time around (particularly about lessons learned while traveling, but that&amp;rsquo;s a topic for another post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The life of your parents&#39; choosing</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</guid>
      <description>Several times I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;the religion of your parents&amp;rsquo; choosing&amp;rdquo;, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on TrapWire</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</guid>
      <description>Stratfor CEO George Friedman  &amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;but the hackers will not find intelligence of corporations and governments, or signs of a vast conspiracy&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; -Stratfor CEO George Friedman, January 2012
&amp;hellip;eight months later&amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;WIKILEAKS: Surveillance Cameras Around The Country Are Being Used In A Huge Spy Network&amp;rdquo; -Business Insider, August 2012
In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, there been some big news released recently as a result of another release of documents by Wikileaks on August 9, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More fun with WebKit pseudoelements: -webkit-search-cancel-button (or: Pseudoclass Inception)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/more-fun-with-webkit-pseudoelements--webkit-search-cancel-button-or-pseudoclass-inception/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/more-fun-with-webkit-pseudoelements--webkit-search-cancel-button-or-pseudoclass-inception/</guid>
      <description>Introduction UPDATE 2016: this appears to have even less support than before, and it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended to be used on a production site. Use a helper JS library instead.
(check out the Demo)
A while back I had a bit of a field day messing around with input type=&amp;ldquo;range&amp;rdquo;, trying to replicate the &amp;ldquo;unlock slider&amp;rdquo; on iOS using CSS, targeting special WebKit-only CSS pseudoelements such as webkit-slider-thumb.
Well, now I&amp;rsquo;m at it again, this time with a much simpler use case, trying to implement a custom &amp;ldquo;clear&amp;rdquo; button on search field inputs (note that this only works on input type=&amp;ldquo;search&amp;rdquo;):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial thoughts on the Retina MacBook Pro (after a few minutes at the store)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/initial-thoughts-on-the-retina-macbook-pro-after-a-few-minutes-at-the-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/initial-thoughts-on-the-retina-macbook-pro-after-a-few-minutes-at-the-store/</guid>
      <description>After work today, I stopped by the old bustling Apple Store in Palo Alto. I was there for a bit of a peek at what my next blank check to Apple would bring me.
I was between tables going back and forth between the updated MacBook Pro (non-retina) and the Retina MacBook Pro and came away with some initial impressions. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find these sort of &amp;ldquo;impartial&amp;rdquo; impressions elsewhere, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d record these impressions for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think I&#39;m learning Japanese: JLPT vocabulary words 1 to 50 (audio)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/i-think-im-learning-japanese-jlpt-vocabulary-words-1-to-50-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/i-think-im-learning-japanese-jlpt-vocabulary-words-1-to-50-audio/</guid>
      <description>(2016 note: this was a terrible idea because I&amp;rsquo;m neither a native speaker nor a good speaker in general.. but I&amp;rsquo;m leaving this up for posterity&amp;hellip;)
I have been learning bits and pieces of Japanese throughout the years, and picking up more and more on each of my trips to Japan. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to buckle down and get disciplined about learning, and make some real progress.
As with learning any language, having a decent vocabulary is critical in order to form coherent sentences, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to focus on this for the time being, in addition to learning hiragana and katakana and getting it down pat, with no errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to &#39;What’s next for mobile now that adaptive design has failed?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/response-to-whats-next-for-mobile-now-that-adaptive-design-has-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/response-to-whats-next-for-mobile-now-that-adaptive-design-has-failed/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a flurry of response to this article, entitled &amp;ldquo;What’s next for mobile now that adaptive design has failed?&amp;rdquo;.
There&amp;rsquo;s many problems with this article, so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to know where to start.
I will admit that defenders of responsive design have come out of the woodwork in trashing this article, but I suppose I count myself among them, being a proponent of responsive design. I still see the web heading that direction, and I definitely don&amp;rsquo;t see it heading in the direction the author of the article has described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New direction (Developer Blog to Blog)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve come to terms with the fact I need to try something new in my life - a true change in direction. I anticipate that this blog will take the same direction, so there will likely be less and less &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; posts and more and more posts of me living this new path. (TLDR: unsubscribe now, probably!)
Why the change in direction? I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived a comfortable life where I really haven&amp;rsquo;t had to worry about money (yet), but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned the hard way that buying &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t buy happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Philosophy still important?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/why-is-philosophy-still-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/why-is-philosophy-still-important/</guid>
      <description>This was posted on reddit recently, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d copy my response here.
First, just a quick introduction! There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of thought recently that philosophy is useless. The main arguments seem to be that
 science has replaced any need for philosophy philosophy is a useless subject to study in college  For the latter argument, I recently recorded my thoughts, and you can hear them here. For the first argument, read on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post a status update to the native Facebook app from a web link</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/post-a-status-update-to-the-native-facebook-app-from-a-web-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/post-a-status-update-to-the-native-facebook-app-from-a-web-link/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE 2/25/2013 As of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s update last year, it appears that many of the old Facebook URL schemes are no longer working&amp;hellip;. So this post looks to be outdated and useless already&amp;hellip; :)
The skinny Copy this code:
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;fb://publish/profile/me?text=foo&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Post to Facebook&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;  {:lang=&amp;ldquo;html&amp;rdquo;}
Explanation As you may know, Facebook has a URL scheme
fb://  which seems to be mainly used by native developers. What most folks don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that it&amp;rsquo;s just a URL scheme, like http://, and that we can use it within our mobile browsers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web development, Silicon Valley rant</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</guid>
      <description>(if you didn&amp;rsquo;t read the title - warning: rant&amp;hellip;)
As far as web development goes, I guess I could rant on and on about the generalities. Of all things ephemeral. The lust after money, gadgets, and other worthless material crap that we use to stuff inside our oversized houses.
The startling creativity and in equal amounts the lack of creativity. The amount of amazing invention and the equal amount of copying and ripping off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS5 SunSpider: iPhone 4S vs iPhone 4 vs iPhone 3GS</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/ios5-sunspider-iphone-4s-vs-iphone-4-vs-iphone-3gs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/ios5-sunspider-iphone-4s-vs-iphone-4-vs-iphone-3gs/</guid>
      <description>Result table (SunSpider 0.9.1, all devices running iOS 5)   Test   iPhone 4S   iPhone 4   iPhone 3GS     Total  2270ms   3483ms   4903ms     3D  281ms   486ms   672ms     Access  279ms   410ms   614ms     Bitops  177ms   200ms   270ms     Controlflow  20ms   26ms   34ms     Crypto  164ms   211ms   315ms     Date  332ms   528ms   770ms     Math  219ms   433ms   553ms     Regexp  88ms   117ms   151ms     String  711ms   1072ms   1525ms    Raw results iPhone 4S (iOS5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4S, iPhone 4, and iPhone 3GS photo comparison</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/iphone-4s-iphone-4-and-iphone-3gs-photo-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/iphone-4s-iphone-4-and-iphone-3gs-photo-comparison/</guid>
      <description>More photos likely to come.. this is just after I unboxed my new 4S. Time to play with it a bit!
iPhone 4S 
iPhone 4 
iPhone 3GS 
iPhone 3GS (alternate white balance point)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Performance Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/mobile-performance-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/mobile-performance-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I gave a talk (slides) outlining the latest and greatest in mobile performance, including a bit of my own unscientific research into carrier latency and bandwidth thanks to boomerang.js.
I realized that interest in mobile performance has exploded recently, especially with Steve Souders announcing his focus on mobile, and I thought it was time for an update, this time in blog form. Also, my old slides have been somewhat embarrassing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to base64 encode images (and when not to)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/when-to-base64-encode-images-and-when-not-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/when-to-base64-encode-images-and-when-not-to/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ever since Steve Souders started evangelizing web performance, it&amp;rsquo;s been pounded into our heads that extra HTTP requests add a lot of additional overhead, and that we should combine them if possible to dramatically decrease the load time of our web pages.
The practical implication of this has been to combine our JavaScript and CSS files, which is relatively easy and straightforward, but the harder question has been what to do with images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different ways of defining functions in JavaScript (this is madness!)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/different-ways-of-defining-functions-in-javascript-this-is-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/different-ways-of-defining-functions-in-javascript-this-is-madness/</guid>
      <description>Note: updated in July 2016 with ES6 arrow functions.
Russian translation thanks to Yevgeniy Pyastolov
This is madness! This&amp;hellip; is&amp;hellip; JavaScript! In JavaScript, there&amp;rsquo;s many different ways of doing something. This is both a good thing and a bad thing. To the newcomer this is definitely a bad thing, as it means not only more things to learn, but more little caveats and more places to go wrong. And so it is with declaring functions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On professional self-worth</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</guid>
      <description>Huge huge rant incoming, but all is not said and done, and much is open for debate of course. Counterpoints and criticisms are more than welcome in the comments. This is just my opinion based on my experience at this point in time.
Self-worth: the rich man and the poor man For a long while there have been places in the world that view self-worth as largely tied to wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Mobile Safari stuff in iOS5: position:fixed, overflow:scroll, new input type support, web workers, ECMAScript 5</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/new-mobile-safari-stuff-in-ios5-positionfixed-overflowscroll-new-input-type-support-web-workers-ecmascript-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/new-mobile-safari-stuff-in-ios5-positionfixed-overflowscroll-new-input-type-support-web-workers-ecmascript-5/</guid>
      <description>(note: this is based on the first iOS5 beta [9A5220p] and is subject to change on final release)
It looks like there&amp;rsquo;s finally some major improvements in mobile Safari, some of which I&amp;rsquo;ve found below on my &amp;ldquo;first glance&amp;rdquo; after downloading the SDK. Chime in if you find anything yourself!
Bad news first Much to my disappointment, browser-based file uploads are still not supported (input type=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo;), even though they have been supported on Android since version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The incredibly painful way of getting an RSS feed of a Twitter list</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/the-incredibly-painful-way-of-getting-an-rss-feed-of-a-twitter-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/the-incredibly-painful-way-of-getting-an-rss-feed-of-a-twitter-list/</guid>
      <description>Update: the Twitter REST API v1 is no longer active. This post has been preserved as a reference.
(why does Twitter make it so hard? What did RSS ever do to it?)
The skinny The Twitter API appears to support two methods for getting RSS feeds of lists. Both of these methods are pretty buried and their API docs don&amp;rsquo;t help too much, but nonetheless both of these feeds work:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android 3.0 Honeycomb is first to implement the Device API</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/android-3.0-honeycomb-is-first-to-implement-the-device-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/android-3.0-honeycomb-is-first-to-implement-the-device-api/</guid>
      <description>I fired up the newly released Android 3.0 SDK to run some tests and found they&amp;rsquo;ve implemented part of the long-awaited Device API (aka the Media Capture API). From your browser you can now upload pictures and videos from the camera as well as sounds from the microphone. The returned data should be available to manipulate via the File API (although I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet tested this).
Video I made a short video demo with some explanation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My O&#39;Reilly Books Wishlist</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/my-oreilly-books-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/my-oreilly-books-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ok, so this post is only here in the hopes I&amp;rsquo;ll actually win something.
O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Books has a promotion where a random winner will receive up to $500 of books on their wishlist, provided they post the list somewhere online. You can probably see why this is here then!
The List Programming the Mobile Web ($50)
Palm webOS ($45)
MongoDB: The Definitive Guide ($40)
JavaScript: The Definitive Guide: Rough Cuts Version, Sixth Edition ($50)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving yourself as a programmer versus as a human being</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/improving-yourself-as-a-programmer-versus-as-a-human-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/improving-yourself-as-a-programmer-versus-as-a-human-being/</guid>
      <description>(OR &amp;ldquo;The Post In Which I Conflate Programming and Philosophy&amp;rdquo; OR &amp;ldquo;The Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Existentialist Crisis&amp;rdquo;)
I woke up this morning to read Dmitry A. Soshnikov&amp;rsquo;s tweet:

While this seems like good advice for aspiring programmers, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think what this means for those who will buy into this. Us programmers have a keen ability to sit and focus on problems for extended periods of time, usually to the detriment of everything else around us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking for undefined, null, and empty variables in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/checking-for-undefined-null-and-empty-variables-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/checking-for-undefined-null-and-empty-variables-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>In general it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice to check for the existence of something before blindly using it by faith and hoping it works. There are various times during the execution of scripts when a variable may not be defined, it may be null, or it might be an empty string. These are three things that are easily conflated. A good way to look at this is thinking of these as having increasing levels of existence (getting a bit philosophical here for a moment&amp;hellip;):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A peek into Google&#39;s Jules Verne tribute (February 8, 2011)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/a-peek-into-googles-jules-verne-tribute-february-8-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/a-peek-into-googles-jules-verne-tribute-february-8-2011/</guid>
      <description>This is just a fun little video demo into the inner workings of today&amp;rsquo;s Google Doodle. Nothing you can&amp;rsquo;t do yourself with Firebug or Web Inspector (built into WebKit browsers such as Safari and Chrome). But I liked this doodle so much, I wanted to talk about it!
Disclaimer: I know the difference between HTML5 and CSS3, but I&amp;rsquo;m not much one for pedantic nomenclature (however, I am apparently supportive of pedantic words like nomenclature).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript SunSpider benchmark: iOS 4.3 vs iOS 4.0</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/javascript-sunspider-benchmark-ios-4.3-vs-ios-4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/javascript-sunspider-benchmark-ios-4.3-vs-ios-4.0/</guid>
      <description>Result table (SunSpider 0.9.1)    Test   iOS 4 (3GS)   iOS 4.3 beta 2 (3GS)   % change     Total   13787ms  5357ms  -61.1%     3D   1917ms  737ms  -61.6%     Access   1893ms  617ms  -67.4%     Bitops   1239ms  289ms  -76.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mobile Web Design (Cameron Moll, 2007)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/notes-mobile-web-design-cameron-moll-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/notes-mobile-web-design-cameron-moll-2007/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s this? These are some notes I collect as I read through Cameron Moll&amp;rsquo;s Mobile Web Design.
Introduction  Further info:  Designing the Mobile User Experience (Barbara Ballard)
dotMobi Web Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide (dev.mobi)
Global Authoring Practices for the Mobile Web (Luca Passani) (passani.it/gap)
Constant Touch: A Global History of the Mobile Web (Jon Agar)
Personal, Portable, Pedestrian: Mobile Phones in Japanese Life (Mizuko Ito)
Mobile Interaction Design (Matt Jones)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing iPhone&#39;s slider unlock with input type=&#39;range&#39;</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/implementing-iphones-slider-unlock-with-input-typerange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/implementing-iphones-slider-unlock-with-input-typerange/</guid>
      <description>(check out the live demo)
Introduction After reading &amp;ldquo;What the Heck is Shadow DOM?&amp;rdquo; I was inspired to see how far I could style the &amp;lt;input type=&amp;quot;range&amp;quot;&amp;gt; element. Pretty far, as it turns out!
My goal was to change the input&amp;rsquo;s default appearance:
To the visual appearance of the iPhone&amp;rsquo;s unlock slider:
As far as I can tell, only WebKit-based browsers and Opera have implemented input type=range. Mobile Safari hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet implemented it as of iOS 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript news resources</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/javascript-news-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/javascript-news-resources/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an overwhelming amount of information being pumped out of the JavaScript community each week, but how do you keep up with it? Here&amp;rsquo;s some sources to keep you busy.
Twitter This merits a category of its own. This has replaced the RSS reader for a lot of folks, or at the very least supplemented it.
I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently recommended Nathan Smith&amp;rsquo;s list of JavaScript folks. When I&amp;rsquo;m diligent, I keep up with this several times a week and favorite items from the feed to be considered for inclusion in that week&amp;rsquo;s JSMag Blog update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens when you have no JavaScript fallback?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/what-happens-when-you-have-no-javascript-fallback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/what-happens-when-you-have-no-javascript-fallback/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what happens when your interface completely relies on JavaScript. There&amp;rsquo;s code with translated mojibake of some sort which caused the JavaScript to break. The code wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a try-catch block, so it caused all of the code on the page to fail, thus presenting me with the only part of the screen that wasn&amp;rsquo;t generated by JavaScript: the completely useless header.
Where&amp;rsquo;s the tweets!?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to spot outdated JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/how-to-spot-outdated-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/how-to-spot-outdated-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Those that are just setting out to learn JavaScript are typically overwhelmed by the amount of online resources to be found about learning JavaScript. Not only this, but every webpage visited presents a potential learning opportunity just by inspecting the source.
However, not all resources are guaranteed to be up-to-date. JavaScript has been around for over a decade, and coding standards have changed drastically over time. While a code snippet may still work in today&amp;rsquo;s browsers, you may unknowingly be using an outdated practice that might eventually lead to a bit of embarrassment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a closure in JavaScript?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/what-is-a-closure-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2011/what-is-a-closure-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Intro There have been many attempts to answer this question in a succinct way, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been satisfied by them. Here&amp;rsquo;s my attempt at a (relatively) concise explanation.
This is adapted from a reply I posted on reddit which people seemed to have found useful.
Broad definition Normally when people talk about closures in JavaScript, they&amp;rsquo;re talking about methods and properties that outlive the scope of their original function (more on that in a second), but actually the definition is a bit broader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile JavaScript libraries and frameworks (Mobile Web Part 7)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-javascript-libraries-and-frameworks-mobile-web-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-javascript-libraries-and-frameworks-mobile-web-part-7/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is designed to be a &amp;ldquo;living&amp;rdquo; post of available materials which will hopefully be updated frequently.
Right now there&amp;rsquo;s not much, just some links, but I hope to keep adding materials, so check back!
The List Sencha Touch
PhoneGap - native wrapper which provides access to native hardware through their own JavaScript APIs
jQuery Mobile - a separate mobile UI which has jQuery as a dependency
iAd - an update to Apple&amp;rsquo;s PastryKit, but probably intended only for ads</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens when we serve JavaScript with random MIME types?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/what-happens-when-we-serve-javascript-with-random-mime-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/what-happens-when-we-serve-javascript-with-random-mime-types/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When people started to learn about the HTML5 doctype, they kind of freaked out a little, not knowing how older browsers would handle it. A post by Dustin Diaz prompted me to test out how pages rendered (in QuirksMode or Standards Mode) with a little help from document.compatMode, and I found that surprisingly every browser rendered in Standards Mode with the new doctype. In other words, no need to worry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top ten things HTML5 makes simpler</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/top-ten-things-html5-makes-simpler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/top-ten-things-html5-makes-simpler/</guid>
      <description>General word of caution: not all of these HTML5 simplifications are compatible with older browsers. Test it for yourself before implementing!
1. The doctype Old &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC &amp;quot;-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01//EN&amp;quot; &amp;quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/strict.dtd&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  New &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;  2. charset Old &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;Content-Type&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;text/html; charset=utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  New &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  3. The link tag’s type attribute Old &amp;lt;link href=&amp;quot;style.css&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/css&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;  New &amp;lt;link href=&amp;quot;style.css&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;  This one may be a bit controversial, but the HTML5 spec actually tells browser vendors not to treat the type attribute as the final word, which makes it seem pretty redundant:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does it still make sense to use em rather than px?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/does-it-still-make-sense-to-use-em-rather-than-px/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/does-it-still-make-sense-to-use-em-rather-than-px/</guid>
      <description>Alex Kessinger tweeted asking if there was a reason to still use EMs instead of PX measurements in mobile. This is an interesting question, but 140 characters isn&amp;rsquo;t quite enough to explain my thoughts. So here&amp;rsquo;s an old-fashioned blog post!
Just a quick review: em and percentage (%) units in CSS are relative measurements, whereas px and other measurements are not. What this means is that the resulting size of relative measurements depends on the size of the parent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript links from last week (September 26)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-links-from-last-week-september-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-links-from-last-week-september-26/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Asteroids - blow up any webpage with this bookmarklet!
JS1k contest - and the winner
PromoteJS - Google bombing with a good intent. Better links to JavaScript documentation!
Async and defer attributes for Script tags added to WebKit
Evercookie - uses devious ways to try to track users. Hmm, this one is questionable. Please use it for good, not evil&amp;hellip; :/
JSPerf.com - not really new news, but a nice quick way to test algorithm performance in JavaScript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Monday: Best Practices for Mobile Design (September 20, 2010)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-monday-best-practices-for-mobile-design-september-20-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-monday-best-practices-for-mobile-design-september-20-2010/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Monday panel left to right: Wesley Yun (RIM), Jared Benson (Punchcut), Anne Sullivan (Microsoft/Tellme Networks), Chris Nesladek (Google), Sue Booker (Nokia) (taken with my iPhone 3GS)
I just came back from Mobile Monday Silicon Valley: Best Practices for Mobile Design at the Computer History Museum in Mountain View. This was a panel discussion with representatives from Google, Microsoft, Nokia, RIM, and Punchcut. There were quite a few little nuggets of wisdom which I tried to write down in bullet form:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server side console.log</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/server-side-console.log/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/server-side-console.log/</guid>
      <description>The problem On the desktop we&amp;rsquo;re quite privileged to have nice debugging tools such as Firebug and Web Inspector in Webkit-based browsers. But when it comes to mobile, debugging JavaScript with console.log.
isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as easy.
Probably the best available tool on mobile at the moment is mobile Safari&amp;rsquo;s console, which looks like the following when enabled (Settings -&amp;gt; Safari -&amp;gt; Developer -&amp;gt; Debug Console):
Mobile Safari&amp;rsquo;s debug console</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing based on connection speed: using navigator.connection on Android 2.2&#43;</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/optimizing-based-on-connection-speed-using-navigator.connection-on-android-2.2-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/optimizing-based-on-connection-speed-using-navigator.connection-on-android-2.2-/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A little while back this post made the rounds, which took us on a journey through some of the new features introduced in the browser in Android 2.2 Froyo. Among the most overlooked features are the file upload functionality (you can upload photos from your browser now! But we&amp;rsquo;re still waiting on iPhone to support this&amp;hellip;) and a little-known JavaScript addition to the Browser Object Model (BOM) in the form of navigator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic HTML5 template</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/basic-html5-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/basic-html5-template/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Often times I end up creating short pages for testing short pieces of code, and I only need a very basic HTML template to write in. Short of using HTML5 Boilerplate, I just use a quick piece of code like the following. (note: yes, this has issues in IE, so you may want to use HTML5 Shiv/Shim)
The code &amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with device orientation (Mobile web part 6)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/dealing-with-device-orientation-mobile-web-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/dealing-with-device-orientation-mobile-web-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you read part 4 of this series, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that because of the variety of screen sizes, the best way to develop for mobile is to develop fluid layouts that take 100% of the available space on the screen.
What you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t think of is that there&amp;rsquo;s different screen widths even on the same device! This is due to screen orientation. And when the user changes the screen orientation, stuff may break (hey, it&amp;rsquo;s not a perfect world).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackBerry Torch SunSpider results (JavaScript benchmark)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/blackberry-torch-sunspider-results-javascript-benchmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/blackberry-torch-sunspider-results-javascript-benchmark/</guid>
      <description>Results ============================================ RESULTS (means and 95% confidence intervals) -------------------------------------------- Total: 322.2ms +/- 4.9% -------------------------------------------- 3d: 55.0ms +/- 15.3% cube: 19.8ms +/- 12.1% morph: 16.6ms +/- 35.8% raytrace: 18.6ms +/- 22.5% access: 32.8ms +/- 12.4% binary-trees: 1.8ms +/- 30.9% fannkuch: 14.2ms +/- 7.3% nbody: 12.6ms +/- 26.7% nsieve: 4.2ms +/- 24.8% bitops: 29.4ms +/- 10.2% 3bit-bits-in-byte: 2.4ms +/- 28.4% bits-in-byte: 8.0ms +/- 15.5% bitwise-and: 8.6ms +/- 21.9% nsieve-bits: 10.4ms +/- 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is a hash faster than a Switch in JavaScript?</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/is-a-hash-faster-than-a-switch-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/is-a-hash-faster-than-a-switch-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across this concept recently and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it, because I don&amp;rsquo;t generally see this pattern being used. More importantly, I also share test results that show that maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not always a good idea to use this pattern&amp;hellip;
The problem with Switch statements The basic switch statement in JavaScript looks something like this:
var foo = &#39;c&#39;; switch(foo) { case &#39;a&#39;: break; case &#39;b&#39;: break; case &#39;c&#39;: break; default: }  So what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Web Camp II at Stanford (July 17, 2010)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/open-web-camp-ii-at-stanford-july-17-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/open-web-camp-ii-at-stanford-july-17-2010/</guid>
      <description>Open Web Camp II at Stanford today was a blast! Lots of information. Plenty I&amp;rsquo;m already familiar with, but also lots I learned.
I woke up late, only to see people tweeting about the conference (doh!), so I missed seeing Molly Holzschlag. But I arrived just in time to see&amp;hellip;
Estelle Weyl: &amp;ldquo;CSS3 Implementable Features&amp;rdquo;  Estelle Weyl (@estellevw)  Estelle&amp;rsquo;s talk was about what features of CSS3 are available to use right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit From Flickr!</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/a-visit-from-flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/a-visit-from-flickr/</guid>
      <description>One of the best perks of working at Yahoo! is getting to attend first-class talks, especially when the talk is by one of your favorite groups. In this case, Flickr!
Flickr schwag: lens cleaner, phone cleaner, or iPhone 4 reception-enabler?  &amp;#8230;and it helps if one of the speakers was once a member of your team (Markus was in Yahoo! Mobile until recently).
Markus Spiering of Flickr  I probably can&amp;#8217;t chat too much about the future improvements they talked about, but I&amp;#8217;ll just say there are some exciting plans for Flickr in the coming months!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday links: mobile performance studies, the upcoming device element, and more (July 15)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/friday-links-mobile-performance-studies-the-upcoming-device-element-and-more-july-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/friday-links-mobile-performance-studies-the-upcoming-device-element-and-more-july-15/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Flickr for iPhone 1.2 released
Firefox Home For iPhone Approved, Lets You Sync Bookmarks, Open Tabs And More
Opera Mobile 10.1 for S60: W3C gelocation, border-radius &amp;amp; 2D transforms on S60 platform
Mobile Browser Cache Limits, Revisited by Ryan Grove
Mobile cache file sizes (and other performance tests on mobile devices) by Steve Souders
Out Of Nowhere, The iPad Has A Real Competitor: the Android-based Pandigital Novel
Ex-Apple Javascript Guru: HTML5 and Native Apps Can Live Together</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday links (July 8)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/thursday-links-july-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/thursday-links-july-8/</guid>
      <description>Mobile YouTube Mobile Gets a Kick Start
Battle of Champions: HTC Droid Incredible vs. Palm Pre Plus
Designing for the Retina Display (326ppi)
AUDIO: John Resig: You Don’t Know Mobile (Webstyle Magazine) &amp;#8211; ~$5,000 minimum to do mobile testing
Tapworthy: Designing Great iPhone Apps
eMobile: We have the fastest network in Japan!
Apple iPad User Analysis — Phase II
VIDEO: Using iPhone with a Braille display (Victor Tsaran)
Mobile Access 2010 (Pew Research)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting Internet Explorer (IE): the age-old struggle</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/targeting-internet-explorer-ie-the-age-old-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/targeting-internet-explorer-ie-the-age-old-struggle/</guid>
      <description>As long as I can remember, developers have always been trying to target IE one way or another. Thanks to the wonders of modern technology, there have been multiple ways to pull this off.
I guess I really haven&amp;#8217;t been keeping up with the latest frontend trends (doh!), as I&amp;#8217;ve just recently discovered this very elegant solution circa 2008 offered by Paul Irish, which sticks a class on the body tag using proprietary conditional IE tags (no JavaScript magic needed here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using mobile-specific HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Mobile web part 5)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/using-mobile-specific-html-css-and-javascript-mobile-web-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/using-mobile-specific-html-css-and-javascript-mobile-web-part-5/</guid>
      <description>(updated June 27, 2011)
Mobile-specific HTML Viewport tag Use the viewport tag to properly fit the content to the screen:
&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;  Tel scheme (to initiate phone calls) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;tel:18005555555&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Call us at 1-800-555-5555&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;  Sms scheme (to initiate text messages) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;sms:18005555555&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;sms:18005555555,18005555556&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- multiple recipients --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;sms:18005555555?body=Text%20goes%20here&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- predefined message body --&amp;gt;  Disable automatic telephone number linking &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;format-detection&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;telephone=no&amp;quot;&amp;gt;  iOS-specific HTML (some work on Android as well) You also have access to several Apple-specific tags to use in your iOS applications (iPhone, iPad, and don&amp;rsquo;t forget the iPod Touch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 4 SunSpider test results (22% faster than iPhone 3GS)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/iphone-4-sunspider-test-results-22-faster-than-iphone-3gs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/iphone-4-sunspider-test-results-22-faster-than-iphone-3gs/</guid>
      <description>============================================ RESULTS (means and 95% confidence intervals) -------------------------------------------- Total: 10669.4ms +/- 1.0% -------------------------------------------- 3d: 1471.5ms +/- 2.1% cube: 428.7ms +/- 2.6% morph: 584.3ms +/- 4.7% raytrace: 458.5ms +/- 0.6% access: 1476.7ms +/- 1.3% binary-trees: 151.6ms +/- 1.3% fannkuch: 664.0ms +/- 0.1% nbody: 397.9ms +/- 2.1% nsieve: 263.2ms +/- 6.3% bitops: 947.2ms +/- 2.1% 3bit-bits-in-byte: 195.7ms +/- 2.0% bits-in-byte: 206.1ms +/- 1.0% bitwise-and: 179.7ms +/- 1.1% nsieve-bits: 365.7ms +/- 3.9% controlflow: 169.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript SunSpider test: iOS 3.1.3 versus iOS 4 GM</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-sunspider-test-ios-3.1.3-versus-ios-4-gm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-sunspider-test-ios-3.1.3-versus-ios-4-gm/</guid>
      <description>Result table    Test   iOS 3.1.3 (3GS)   iOS 4 GM (3GS)   % change     Total   15396ms   13787ms  -10.5%     3D   2411ms   1917ms  -20.5%     Access   1884ms   1893ms  +0.5%     Bitops   1044ms   1239ms  +18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript SunSpider: HTC Evo versus HTC Incredible versus Nexus One</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-sunspider-htc-evo-versus-htc-incredible-versus-nexus-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/javascript-sunspider-htc-evo-versus-htc-incredible-versus-nexus-one/</guid>
      <description>Result table    Test   Evo (2.1)   Incredible (2.1)   Nexus One (2.2)     Total   16167ms   15237ms  5452ms     3D   2014ms   1835ms  946ms     Access   2126ms   1892ms  463ms     Bitops   1519ms   1591ms  360ms     Controlflow   243ms   206ms  20ms     Crypto   1033ms   1003ms  344ms     Date   1849ms   1896ms  639ms     Math   1684ms   1419ms  602ms     Regexp   1779ms   1673ms  155ms     String   3920ms   3722ms  1923ms    Thoughts The Incredible is just slightly faster than the Evo, to the point where it&amp;#8217;s probably negligible or within a margin of error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install obsolete Android Virtual Devices (AVDs)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/how-to-install-obsolete-android-virtual-devices-avds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/how-to-install-obsolete-android-virtual-devices-avds/</guid>
      <description>Apparently it&amp;#8217;s no longer possible to easily download Android versions 2.0 and 2.0.1 from the AVD Manager. I noticed this problem when I got a new machine and had to install everything from scratch. In the future I suspect even more AVDs will be made obsolete, so this solution also applies to them.
Why would you want to install obsolete AVDs? In my case it&amp;#8217;s a matter of research: I simply want to see the progress of features being added to its browser, and track those changes over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First: Luke Wroblewski on mobile design</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-first-luke-wroblewski-on-mobile-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/mobile-first-luke-wroblewski-on-mobile-design/</guid>
      <description>In episode 6 of The Big Web Show, Luke Wroblewski gives his &amp;#8220;Mobile First&amp;#8221; talk, explaining his philosophy for designing for mobile, the challenges, and a look at the road ahead. Luke explains that because of the limitations on mobile, developers are forced to really optimize the user experience for mobile. Often times this mobile experience turns out much better than on the desktop, where the &amp;#8220;gluttony of resources&amp;#8221; results in distracting and excessive webpages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On designing a mobile webpage (Mobile web part 4)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/on-designing-a-mobile-webpage-mobile-web-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/on-designing-a-mobile-webpage-mobile-web-part-4/</guid>
      <description>The frontend engineer lives at the intersection between design and engineering, and this is perhaps nowhere more true than in the world of mobile. In order to make a usable desktop website, an engineer must have at least some sense of design, and fortunately a lot of this has been standardized over the years. But the world of mobile is full of more unknowns, and the field is changing rapidly, especially lately from the shift away from older feature phones to the focus on smartphones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing buttons that don&#39;t suck (Mobile web part 3)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/designing-buttons-that-dont-suck-mobile-web-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/designing-buttons-that-dont-suck-mobile-web-part-3/</guid>
      <description>A button is something that seems to be made just for mobile: it&amp;#8217;s designed to be big and easy to activate, as opposed to small and harder to activate, like normal text links. This seems ideal for a mobile devices, which have a small display area and whose form of input is a person&amp;#8217;s (relatively) fat finger interacting with the screen. Contrast this with the desktop, where the display area is much larger and the input device, the mouse, is a much more highly refined and sensitive pointing device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mobile developer&#39;s toolkit (Mobile web part 2)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/the-mobile-developers-toolkit-mobile-web-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/the-mobile-developers-toolkit-mobile-web-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Tools of the trade You&amp;#8217;re no mobile developer unless you have the tools to develop on mobile! And while it&amp;#8217;s good to own at least one of the smartphones you&amp;#8217;re developing on, it&amp;#8217;s probably unrealistic to think that you&amp;#8217;re going to go out of your way to buy several other unlocked smartphones just to test with. So you should have the next best thing: an SDK!
But an SDK is just one of the tools of the trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The viewport metatag (Mobile web part 1)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/the-viewport-metatag-mobile-web-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/the-viewport-metatag-mobile-web-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The skinny Use this:
&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;  Introduction This series of posts is intended to introduce web developers to basic techniques for designing for the mobile web. It assumes at least a basic knowledge of creating desktop websites.
The problem Ok, so you&amp;rsquo;ve settled down to learn how to write a website for a mobile device using your current knowledge of building desktop websites. So you start off with some pretty basic HTML:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Clockwork Box</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/a-clockwork-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/a-clockwork-box/</guid>
      <description>With CSS there are always various ways to accomplish something. After reading this short tidbit, you should be familiar with the various ways of controlling the size of an element&amp;#8217;s padding, border, and margin, and you should know what the handy &amp;#8220;clockwork&amp;#8221; tip is, and how it will be useful to remember when you&amp;#8217;re putting your CSS into practice.
Equal values on all four sides If all four values (top, right, bottom, and left) are equal, then you simply write the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links for the week of February 21, 2010</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-21-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-21-2010/</guid>
      <description> General links  Video: Flash performance on the Nexus One   censorzilla   PHP compiler performance &amp;#8211; PHP Classes blog   Mobile  10 Great Tools to Create a Mobile Version of Your Site   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links for the week of February 14, 2010</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-14-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-14-2010/</guid>
      <description>General links  What really happens when you navigate to a URL &amp;#8211; great in-depth explanation of computer-to-server transactions. With pictures!  (Google) Update on Qualified Developer Program &amp;#8211; some insight into the motivation behind Google&amp;#8217;s Qualified Developer Program   HTML5/CSS3 and new web technology   I Can&amp;#8217;t Believe It&amp;#8217;s Not Flash: Thomas Fuchs&amp;#8217;s slides from his presentation at Webstock 2010   You Can Use CSS3 Right Now   Designing for the Future with HTML5+CSS3 : Tutorials and Best Practices   &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; Mobile &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul class=&amp;quot;links&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overall iPhone browser traffic share is decreasing (Jan2009 to Jan2010)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/overall-iphone-browser-traffic-share-is-decreasing-jan2009-to-jan2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/overall-iphone-browser-traffic-share-is-decreasing-jan2009-to-jan2010/</guid>
      <description>According to the statistics available on statcounter.com, from January 2009 to January 2010, iPhone browser traffic share actually decreased, not increased, as one might expect.
This is likely due to new competition from Android phones, as well as the possibility that more users are simply using iPhone native apps instead of web apps.
In any case, in my opinion these are the figures we ought to be looking at, not overall phone sales, as others such as PPK concentrate on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links for the week of February 7, 2010</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-7-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2010/links-for-the-week-of-february-7-2010/</guid>
      <description>General links  Video for Everybody!: cross-browser support of HTML5 video and methods of fallback   Oracle Cuts Affect GNOME Accessibility Work: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;as a result of the layoffs &amp;#8230; &amp;#8216;the accessibility of the GNOME desktop will become the open source equivalent of an unfunded mandate, doomed ultimately to fail&amp;#8217; &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;   Google Acquires Aardvark For $50 million   &amp;#8220;the latest publication of HTML5 is now blocked by Adobe, via an objection that has still not been made public (despite yesterday&amp;#8217;s promise to make it so)&amp;#8221;   The iPhone obsession (QuirksMode)   Performance  DOMTiming interface being implemented in Chromium and Firefox   A Hidden Cost of Javascript: file size is a factor in performance, but so is parse and load time   Announcing High Performance JavaScript: Nicholas Zakas announces his latest book, due in March 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A primer on CSS colors</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/a-primer-on-css-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/a-primer-on-css-colors/</guid>
      <description>Color keywords Example usage:
// Example body { color: red; } // Generalization (not actual code) body { color: color_name; } Because color names are easy to remember, they&amp;#8217;re handy for getting quick results, especially while doing rapid prototyping.
W3C&amp;#8217;s CSS1 recommendation first mentioned 16 color keywords that you can use: aqua, black, blue, fuchsia, gray, green, lime, maroon, navy, olive, purple, red, silver, teal, white, and yellow:
   Color   Hexadecimal   Color   Hexadecimal   Color   Hexadecimal   Color   Hexadecimal     aqua / cyan  #00FFFF   gray  #808080   navy  #000080   silver  #C0C0C0     black  #000000   green  #008000   olive  #808000   teal  #008080     blue  #0000FF   lime  #00FF00   purple  #800080   white  #FFFFFF     fuchsia / magenta  #FF00FF   maroon  #800000   red  #FF0000   yellow  #FFFF00    (color table from Wikipedia)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: John Resig - Testing, Performance Analysis, and jQuery 1.4</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/video-john-resig---testing-performance-analysis-and-jquery-1.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/video-john-resig---testing-performance-analysis-and-jquery-1.4/</guid>
      <description>In case you hadn&amp;#8217;t seen it yet, John Resig was kind enough to stop by Yahoo! for the December Bayjax meetup. Here&amp;#8217;s the video:
 Usually developers are more interested in just getting the dang code to work, and as a result actual the testing and maintenance of JavaScript isn&amp;#8217;t talked about too much, so I&amp;#8217;m sure this will be new territory for many developers. And since it&amp;#8217;s John Resig speaking, there was of course a bit about using TestSwarm, a testing distributed framework-agnostic automated testing tool (that&amp;#8217;s a mouthful!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PastryKit: digging into an Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/pastrykit-digging-into-an-apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/pastrykit-digging-into-an-apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday John Gruber wrote about Apple&amp;#8217;s PastryKit, iPhone&amp;#8217;s JavaScript framework that&amp;#8217;s been discovered &amp;#8220;in the wild&amp;#8221; on the iPhone user guide at http://help.apple.com/iphone/3/mobile/. There&amp;#8217;s a few ways to access the page:
 with an actual iPhone or iTouch by browsing with an iPhone/iTouch user agent. If you&amp;#8217;re using Safari, enable the Developer menu in Safari&amp;gt;Preferences&amp;gt;Advanced and switching user agents by clicking on Develope&amp;gt;User Agent  What&amp;#8217;s all the big fuss?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript tidbit: special variables ($, $$, _, etc)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-special-variables---_-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-special-variables---_-etc/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re probably used to typical variables names such as the following:
var personName = &#39;Joe&#39;;  You may not realize it, but there are some non-alphanumeric variables at your disposal.
Using $ For instance, the $ variable has been made popular by several JavaScript libraries, most notably jQuery. You can use it to alias operations that are commonly performed, such as the following (1):
var $ = document.getElementById; var myElement = $(&#39;targetElement&#39;);  If you declare this variable outside of a function it will be a global variable and will compete with libraries that use the same global variable, so it&amp;rsquo;s probably best not to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways of passing data to functions in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/ways-of-passing-data-to-functions-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/ways-of-passing-data-to-functions-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Passing data is quite important in functional programming languages like JavaScript. When there are multiple functions (which is most of the time), there needs to be a way to pass data between the functions. This is done by passing values in parenthesis: myFunction(myData). Even when there is no data to be passed, we still have to declare and execute functions by using parenthesis: myFunction().
Simple Passing I&amp;rsquo;ve already referred to the common method of passing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEMobile 6/7 bug: classes and id not supported on the HTML element</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/iemobile-6/7-bug-classes-and-id-not-supported-on-the-html-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/iemobile-6/7-bug-classes-and-id-not-supported-on-the-html-element/</guid>
      <description>As it turns out, IEMobile 6&amp;frasl;7 (and presumably anything earlier) doesn&amp;#8217;t support classes and ids that are attached to the HTML element. I confirmed this on both IEMobile 6 and 7. Fortunately it looks to be fixed in IEMobile 8 (which makes sense, since it works fine in desktop IE6, which it&amp;#8217;s based on).
The consequence of this is that adding an id/class to the html tag will result in the style not being applied to the document:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP: dealing with stuff that doesn&#39;t exist</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/php-dealing-with-stuff-that-doesnt-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/php-dealing-with-stuff-that-doesnt-exist/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As the application you&amp;#8217;re coding becomes more and more complex, there&amp;#8217;s more of an opportunity for things to go wrong in all sorts of unforseen ways. One of these problems is variables or functions that don&amp;#8217;t exist. The problem is when you code in such a way that you presuppose their existence. But their existence isn&amp;#8217;t guaranteed!
A simple case of this happening is when you&amp;#8217;re dealing with user input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfalls of declaring variables in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/pitfalls-of-declaring-variables-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/pitfalls-of-declaring-variables-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of the things that&amp;#8217;s always been confusing to me is that there are multiple ways to declare variables in JavaScript, and some ways are better than others. For the beginner programmer, just getting to code to work means complete success, but for the intermediate or advanced programmer, this is just the first step. The next step is to clean up the code and make sure everything is written in the best way it could have been written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Tidbit: Block scope with let</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-block-scope-with-let/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-block-scope-with-let/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript has functional scope. Meaning that if you (properly) define variables within functions, those variables remain accessible only inside the function.
Block scope, on the other hand, defines scope within a block of code, usually defined by braces. JavaScript now has block scope as of version 1.7, which means it&amp;#8217;s available in these browsers:
 Firefox 2+  Block scope is enabled in JavaScript with the use of &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8221;:
let(x=100) { alert(x); }; It also works perfectly well on one line, without the use of braces:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Tidbit: Shorthand Object Instantiation</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-shorthand-object-instantiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/javascript-tidbit-shorthand-object-instantiation/</guid>
      <description>The skinny: here&amp;#8217;s a neat little trick to reduce the amount of code users have to type to instantiate objects:
function jQuery(str, con){ if ( window == this ) return new jQuery(str, con); // ... } new jQuery(&amp;quot;#foo&amp;quot;); // this is now equivalent... jQuery(&amp;quot;#foo&amp;quot;); // ...to this!  {:lang=&amp;ldquo;js&amp;rdquo;}
Explanation: when jQuery(&amp;#8220;#foo&amp;#8221;) is typed, the function first determines if the context in which it&amp;#8217;s being called is the global object (window).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Tidbit: Dead simple singleton</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/php-tidbit-dead-simple-singleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/php-tidbit-dead-simple-singleton/</guid>
      <description>class Singleton { private static $instance; public static function getInstance() { if(!isset(self::$instance)) { $c = __CLASS__; self::$instance = new $c(); } return self::$instance; } } And the explanation&amp;#8230;
class Singleton { private static $instance; // static variable to hold our 1 instance public static function getInstance() { // function to get the 1 instance if(!isset(self::$instance)) { // this will only run once (and instantiate once) $c = __CLASS__; // get the class (Singleton) self::$instance = new $c(); // instantiate the class and store it in our variable } return self::$instance; // return the instance } public static function myFunction() { // we can get to this through Singleton::getInstance()-myFunction() // .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IE Mobile 6.12 problem: browser ignores the specificity of CSS display styles</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/ie-mobile-6.12-problem-browser-ignores-the-specificity-of-css-display-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2009/ie-mobile-6.12-problem-browser-ignores-the-specificity-of-css-display-styles/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: I found that the problem is actually that inline-block is completely unsupported in this version of IE Mobile, and is likely also unsupported in IE Mobile 7, which is also based on IE4. This is in contrast to desktop IE6, where inline-block is supported on elements that are natively inline (span, em, etc.).
Just found this today, for what it&amp;#8217;s worth. If you&amp;#8217;re unlucky enough to be working with older Windows Mobile phones you have probably realized that the browser is based on IE6, which all the desktop web developers notoriously complain about constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>