<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 20:10:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stifling Laughter in Distant Places</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 20:10:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</guid>
      <description>New Cultures The first days of traveling usually involves laughing at the quaint and unusual customs of another culture. That sounds close-minded, because in many cases it probably is. But it&#39;s something we all do, of course including yours truly. Maybe it&#39;s a coping mechanism - laughing at things in the face of difficulties and differences.
To be fair, we&#39;re thinking creatures, and as such it&#39;s pretty hard for us not to draw comparisons with our own home city and culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:06:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</guid>
      <description>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can&#39;t be bothered to be bored with non-junk. We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways. We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The surprising benefits of going to the gym</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 21:40:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s well into the new year, and I didn&#39;t exactly start the new year off like everyone else, who I imagine all rushed daily into the gym in the first week or two, then apparently gave the habit up soon after.
Sometime in February I found out about a study being conducted at my workplace in conjunction with a university, to track the effects of exercise over the course of a month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living as driftwood</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 21:52:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two photo posts I wanted to avoid this sort of heavy reflection New Year post. But its time has finally come and it should be said, no matter how cheesy it may sound.
I have been living these last few years of my life as driftwood. At least professionally. I have all the makings of what should make me happy and successfully in my career, but it&#39;s an illusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The City Is A Medium, The Medium Is The Message</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 19:11:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</guid>
      <description>Vendors along Kamogawa River for the Tanabata (七夕) star festival in Kyoto (Photo by David Calhoun, 2011)  I had always heard of Marshall McCluhan&#39;s famous &amp;ldquo;the medium is the message&amp;rdquo;, but really only had a surface level understanding of it until recently, when I first read the essay.
It&#39;s a somewhat eye-opening and challenging piece for various reasons, because it challenges some things I thought I had a good grasp of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Google Bitch</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch/</guid>
      <description>When I came back from Japan and accepted an offer to work at a startup in Silicon Valley, I knew one of the biggest challenges would be to find a decent and affordable apartment in Mountain View, close to where I&#39;d be working. I had it all planned out, and how healthy and convenient it would be to walk to work and also Mountain View downtown!
Unfortunately, this dream was shared by me and hundreds of thousands of other like-minded software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth of July letter to my government</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</guid>
      <description>(this is a copy of a letter which I&#39;ve sent to various representatives in government)
As a concerned citizen, I know you understand that I must occasionally voice my concern through letters such as this. My hope is that you will honestly consider my claims and take action on my part. I honestly appreciate you taking your time to seriously consider this letter.
I&#39;m writing to you today specifically in response to abuses by the NSA overstepping its bounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSA&#39;s PRISM: from the minds of conspiracy nuts, turns out to be reality</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality/</guid>
      <description>The real shame about NSA/PRISM is that everyone will forget about it next week or next month. Just like we forgot about Trapwire and other endless abuses in the name of protecting society.
The US is now a nation too mentally castrated to do anything about these obvious constitutional abuses. Why are we only capable of short-lived and impotent protest attempts like Occupy? How did we get to be so sedated through this anesthesia of modern consumerism and entertainment?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forms of Escapism</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been thinking lately that the fates of so many are motivated by, in a word, escapism. Including my own fate. These are folks whose lives seem quite different on first glance, but turn out to be similar. We can&#39;t escape some of our basic human nature after all.
The Preservationist These are folks who, for lack of a better term, wish to preserve a &amp;ldquo;simpler time&amp;rdquo;. They are people such as Thoreau, who wanted a return to simpler times and aspired to self-sufficiency (or an approximation, in any case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The life of your parents&#39; choosing</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</guid>
      <description>Several times I&#39;ve heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;the religion of your parents&amp;rsquo; choosing&amp;rdquo;, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on TrapWire</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</guid>
      <description>Stratfor CEO George Friedman  &amp;quot;&amp;hellip;but the hackers will not find intelligence of corporations and governments, or signs of a vast conspiracy&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; -Stratfor CEO George Friedman, January 2012
&amp;hellip;eight months later&amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;WIKILEAKS: Surveillance Cameras Around The Country Are Being Used In A Huge Spy Network&amp;rdquo; -Business Insider, August 2012
In case you haven&#39;t noticed, there been some big news released recently as a result of another release of documents by Wikileaks on August 9, 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New direction (Developer Blog to Blog)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&#39;ve come to terms with the fact I need to try something new in my life - a true change in direction. I anticipate that this blog will take the same direction, so there will likely be less and less &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; posts and more and more posts of me living this new path. (TLDR: unsubscribe now, probably!)
Why the change in direction? I&#39;ve had my fun, I&#39;ve lived a comfortable life where I really haven&#39;t had to worry about money (yet), but I&#39;ve learned the hard way that buying &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; doesn&#39;t buy happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web development, Silicon Valley rant</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</guid>
      <description>(if you didn&#39;t read the title - warning: rant&amp;hellip;)
As far as web development goes, I guess I could rant on and on about the generalities. Of all things ephemeral. The lust after money, gadgets, and other worthless material crap that we use to stuff inside our oversized houses.
The startling creativity and in equal amounts the lack of creativity. The amount of amazing invention and the equal amount of copying and ripping off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On professional self-worth</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</guid>
      <description>Huge huge rant incoming, but all is not said and done, and much is open for debate of course. Counterpoints and criticisms are more than welcome in the comments. This is just my opinion based on my experience at this point in time.
Self-worth: the rich man and the poor man For a long while there have been places in the world that view self-worth as largely tied to wealth. No doubt there is more than just money, as even within the rich community there&#39;s a distinction between the established rich and the &amp;ldquo;nouveau riche&amp;rdquo;, or the newly rich.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>