<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sakura on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/sakura/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sakura on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 23:20:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/sakura/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourist season in Japan, and a brief escape to Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 23:20:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>Inside Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan (Photo copyright David Calhoun)  (I originally wrote this while sitting in Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan)
I&#39;m visiting Japan again, when part of me is constantly thinking I should instead be spending the time and money exploring other parts of the world.
I guess I just find myself coming back to the familiar and (somewhat) comfortable. I find that I have the same habit when returning to a restaurant, and ordering the same item from the menu each and every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto Cherry Blossoms 2013 (京都の桜２０１３年)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/kyoto-cherry-blossoms-2013-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%A1%9C%EF%BC%92%EF%BC%90%EF%BC%91%EF%BC%93%E5%B9%B4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/kyoto-cherry-blossoms-2013-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%A1%9C%EF%BC%92%EF%BC%90%EF%BC%91%EF%BC%93%E5%B9%B4/</guid>
      <description>Cherry blossoms in Kyoto, Japan 2013  Check out my cherry blossoms 2013 set on Flickr.
Japan has a healthy fascination with the beauty of nature, and this includes the ephemeral cherry blossoms. And one of the prime locations for cherry blossoms is Kyoto, Japan.
It takes a while to realize, but there actually seems to be a wide variety of cherry blossoms which blossom at different times. This stretches the season out a bit (the prime blossoming lasts only about a week).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>