<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new orleans on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/new-orleans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new orleans on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/new-orleans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans trip (November 2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 11:51:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I had the opportunity to visit New Orleans in the spring with my friend. Now I&#39;ve returned with my parents to visit in the fall!
My mom had recently expressed a desire to do more travelling while still physically able, which kicked off creating a list of places to visit, and ultimately booking this first trip. Hopefully the first of many to come. She asked if I wanted to tag along, and I couldn&#39;t pass up another visit to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 1 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s nearing the year&#39;s end, so of course this means a somewhat sentimental blog post from me. I was thinking of a &amp;ldquo;resolutions/goals&amp;rdquo; type post, but I decided against it. Instead here&#39;s something more entertaining: my favorite photos from the past year! Note that these aren&#39;t necessarily my best, just my favorites.
Finding these is also a little bit of housekeeping for me and my photos. It forces me to sort the gigabytes and gigabytes of RAW photos I was casually dumping onto drives the entire year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>