<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Half Marathon: Hiking Half the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-half-marathon-hiking-half-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-half-marathon-hiking-half-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Mt Katahdin at the northern terminus of the Appalachian Trail in Maine  (note: all photos shot on my older iPhone 7)
Thank you! Thanks to everyone who helped me on my AT journey! Special thanks:
 to my mom for helping mail me resupply packages to my sister and her family for their support, small snacks, kids&amp;rsquo; drawings for support, and for liking some of my best picture uploads to my friends James and Jessica for the very generous care package which helped me get back on the trail after a month away to Gomer Pyle (John) and Sawbones (Sarah) who let me tag along with them and bought me too many meals, drinks, and even a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 mile Big Basin hike</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/11-mile-big-basin-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 08:47:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/11-mile-big-basin-hike/</guid>
      <description>GPS track log  See the interactive GPS track log here.
I really needed to get out of Silicon Valley again and go experience nature, so on Sunday I drove over to my favorite hiking spot, Big Basin. There&amp;rsquo;s a $10 fee to get in and park, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it considering it&amp;rsquo;s about the price of a movie and much more rewarding.
I arrived right after the park opened and started my hike to Berry Creek Falls at 8:20am, which is probably the earliest I&amp;rsquo;ve started there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Basin October Hike</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/big-basin-october-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 01:34:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/big-basin-october-hike/</guid>
      <description>GPS track log  See the interactive GPS track log here.
On Sunday I grabbed two sandwiches at Le Boulanger, and headed for a late hike in Big Basin, which is my favorite place to hike in the area. The drive from my apartment in Sunnyvale is almost an hour and a half, and the fee to park is $10, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it to go and spend time there once and a while.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>