<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top 100 Films on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/top-100-films/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top 100 Films on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/top-100-films/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Godfather Review (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/the-godfather-review-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/the-godfather-review-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>The Godfather opening logo  Intro It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, but I&amp;rsquo;m still at it! I&amp;rsquo;m on a journey to watch and review all of the top 100 films, using a list I worked out a while back. I recommend checking out that original post
Today&amp;rsquo;s film is one that is undeniably near the top of many &amp;ldquo;top 100&amp;rdquo; lists: The Godfather.
Opening shot: &#39;I believe in America&#39;  The Story I&amp;rsquo;m actually not a super big fan of the film, but it&amp;rsquo;s entertaining and really well done of course, so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to deny it the attention it deserves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monty Python and the Holy Grail (1975) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monty-python-and-the-holy-grail-1975-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 19:36:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monty-python-and-the-holy-grail-1975-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>This is a movie in the same spirit as the Marx Brothers’ Duck Soup: essentially a string of crazy anarchic skits held together weakly by some central theme. The story isn&amp;rsquo;t strong, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be and it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be. It&amp;rsquo;s just there as a sort of skeleton to hang all the skits on.
As a movie, this feels to me to be strangely out of place in the top 100 movies, maybe because it&amp;rsquo;s such a low budget production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Casablanca (1942) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/casablanca-1942-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:31:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/casablanca-1942-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Casablanca more than a few times, and it&amp;rsquo;s become one of my favorite films. For this review I got to experience it in 35mm at the wonderful nearby Stanford Theatre.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not how I first experienced it. I first watched it at home and half paid attention to it. A lot of the movie was lost on me and I thought it was overrated, just ok, and not that great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schindler&#39;s List (1993) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:27:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>Schindler&#39;s List title card with candles  This is a film that is best experienced, not explained in a post like this. However, that being said, I&amp;rsquo;ll give this a try anyhow.
I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided this film all my life out of dread more than anything. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat weird then that I watched this so early in my &amp;ldquo;Top 100&amp;rdquo; films quest. I knew I&amp;rsquo;d have to watch it eventually anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikiru (1952) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/ikiru-1952-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 21:43:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/ikiru-1952-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>IKIRU, 生きる, TO LIVE  This is an existentialist story about a man who learns he has stomach cancer, leading to his reconsidering of life, which he realizes has been utterly wasted up until this point.
As it turns out, he realizes he hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been living at all. What&amp;rsquo;s inadvertently happened is that his job has turned into his life - the job of being section chief at one of the endless wasteful government bureaucracies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Through The Top 100 Films</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/a-journey-through-the-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 09:26:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/a-journey-through-the-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of January, which means the beginning of a new year. And you know what that means - a time for making resolutions that will probably not be kept! Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see how far this one goes&amp;hellip;
Instead of wasting away my time playing video games, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take a bit more seriously another passion: watching movies. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to make this constructive by reviewing each of the top 100 movies, many of which I&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting down and watching for the very first time, and many of which are old favorites that I&amp;rsquo;ll be rewatching, unfortunately not with fresh eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>