<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-04T17:23:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stifling Laughter in Distant Places]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-09T20:10:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="new-cultures">New Cultures</h3>

<p>The first days of traveling usually involves laughing at the quaint and unusual customs of another culture.  That sounds close-minded, because in many cases it probably is.  But it’s something we all do, of course including yours truly.  Maybe it’s a coping mechanism - laughing at things in the face of difficulties and differences.</p>

<p>To be fair, we’re thinking creatures, and as such it’s pretty hard for us not to draw comparisons with our own home city and culture.  Especially when we spot things that we consider outdated in our own culture.  Our reaction may be disgust (“Fax machines?!  Didn’t those go extinct in the 90s?!”) or nostalgia (“Ahh decent customer service - it’s been way too long”).</p>

<p>After one or two weeks, and we may still be poking fun at the quirks of our temporarily home.  But this changes when we settle in for the long term.  Weeks turn to months, and the funny quirks become more visible, in just the same way as quirks of spouses are discovered, as we’re forced to live with them each day.  Laughter at those quirks can turn to annoyance, and not far beyond that is outright hatred.</p>

<h3 id="the-marriage-analogy">The Marriage Analogy</h3>

<p>I don’t think the marriage analogy is too much of a stretch - living in a city can almost be like being married (though I can only guess): each day venturing out from our beds we have to confront the city or the spouse daily, and encounter both the good and the bad just to get through with the day.  At least with cities we can escape into our own rooms and private spaces.  But with marriage there is often no room to escape to, except maybe the bathroom.  This may explain why men sometimes spend so long in these very private places…</p>

<p>In a relationship, some of the personal quirks we discover are at first quaint, but our attitude can soon progress to annoyance, or worse.  If we’re unable to tolerate the quirks, our hatred can soon multiply and be reason for divorce. Or on the other end of the analogy: emigration from the city.  Us leaving the city is sort of like a break up or divorce.</p>

<p>I’m not sure about what you think, but I think this progression from laughter to annoyance to hatred doesn’t seem too productive.  What if we try to go down a quite different path, one which doesn’t start with laughter and disdain?  Maybe this path will take us to a better place.</p>

<p>At the very least, outright laughter at foreign customs does seem to be a sort of childlike reaction, because it’s unskilled: it’s basically a quick judgement and unrestrained laughter.</p>

<h3 id="people-do-things-differently--and-thats-usually-ok">People Do Things Differently.  And That’s (usually) OK.</h3>

<p>It reminds me of the scene in To Kill A Mockingbird where a poor boy is invited to the Finch household.  At breakfast, the poor kid steeps his entire breakfast in syrup, much to the disgust of the Finch girl.  She starts to react, but Atticus, the father, calmly quiets her.  His reaction at “foreign” customs is more mature - he doesn’t laugh, but instead looks past the poor boy making all his food soggy with syrup.  The boy is a guest, and what’s more, the moral of the whole story is tolerance of different folks and their ways.  Atticus is the hero of the story, and the one who sets an example for his daughter.  And for us.</p>

<p>In our travels we’ll often come across things that seem backwards in some way on first appearance.  And it may go deeper than appearance - many of these things may turn out to actually be very backwards.  But it helps me to try to have patience, to suspend judgement and give the benefit of a doubt.  For instance, Japan has an unusually rigid culture with a structured way of doing things, even small things such as opening small packages of food by pulling the correct tabs on the packaging.  In the correct order.  To do otherwise is simply incorrect.  After being corrected constantly on tiny little ways I was doing things wrong, I started to go mad.  My initial reaction was wanting to rebel, to do things my own way.  I think this approach still has merit, if we have the right attitude towards it.</p>

<p>It helps to remind myself that there’s a structure in the culture for a reason, because it’s worked well for decades (or maybe centuries), and while there may be better ways, this way is the way this culture works best.  It’s pragmatic.  It may change over time, but for the moment this is the smoothest way for everything to harmonize.</p>

<p>But you aren’t part of that culture, so you may very well find more efficient ways to do things.  Perhaps you’ll bypass the tabs on the food packaging and take some scissors to the whole thing, ignoring the instructions.  I think that’s fine - finding a way that works for you.  Just don’t laugh at other folks for doing things differently.  Though conversely, the natives will probably laugh at you and try to constantly correct you.  I guess you’ll have to get used to it.</p>

<h3 id="your-options">Your Options</h3>

<p>As a foreigner you have a few options:</p>

<p>-adopt the ways of the culture and love it<br />
-adopt the ways of the culture, but secretly hate it and resent it<br />
-do things your own way, and tolerate the other ways<br />
-do things your own way, and secretly hate and resent the other ways</p>

<p>Which of these works best?  I guess you can experiment for yourself and draw your own conclusions!  Judge for yourself!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My new photography YouTube channel]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-11T11:23:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/my-new-photography-youtube-channel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello friends!  It’s been a while without an update.</p>

<p>I’ve been working more and more on my photography endeavors, which includes building up a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCg5jVvaChTjkL74IQ334FzQ">YouTube channel</a> to document my travels and also my learnings.  I’m hoping it’s interesting and useful enough, especially for other aspiring photographers.</p>

<p>This year is definitely shaping up to be a year of travelling, and I’d also like to keep a blog of photos and such, so I’m working to get a separate photography blog setup at <a href="https://davidcalhounphotography.com">my photography website</a>.  I’m hoping to get that up soon, as I’m already falling behind!  And I have a trip to Japan coming up next week already!</p>

<p>Anyhow, here’s a few recent videos you can check out.</p>

<p>From my recent trip to Edinburgh.  I didn’t take much video footage, but was able to put together a quick video with what I had.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2lUHx6l4DvQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Big Bear Lake in the snow.  Just the tail end of the winter season, so I had to take advantage and get out a bit!</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i40R_zkPjg8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>A lazy winter photography test run in my backyard.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ItT7Z3ozmRM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Right now my channel is in its very humble beginnings, but I’m still working on getting good content there, and learning to edit my videos better and better as I progress.  Turns out I’m learning photography and a bit of videography and editing as well!</p>

<p>Please check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCg5jVvaChTjkL74IQ334FzQ">my channel</a> and subscribe!  I promise a TON more adventures just in the coming year.  Here’s what’s already booked:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Japan (March)</li>
  <li>Atlanta (April)</li>
  <li>Yosemite, Sequoia, Crater Lake road trip with Mark (May)</li>
  <li>Copenhagen and Norway (May/June)</li>
  <li>New Orleans (July)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning thoughts on the idea of a Great American Road Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-11T22:35:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea of a trip across the United States has become somewhat of an American institution.  Something like a New American Dream, this one maybe a bit more accessible than that house, happy life, and nuclear family with 2.5 kids.  It’s something that is undertaken by both the young and the old, with the former perhaps hitchhiking or sleeping in their cars while the latter leapfrog between National Parks in their expensive and comfortable motor homes.</p>

<p>It’s something that can be undertaken alone, along a lonely journey which becomes a sort of vision quest to find one’s purpose.  Or it can be undertaken with friends and family, and turned into more of a quest to check off bucket list destinations and to experience America.</p>

<p>Whatever the circumstance, the thought of the American Road Trip hangs in the back of every American’s mind in some way.  I can’t help think that there is daily at least one person stuck in a cubicle or trapped in a job behind a computer screen that isn’t tempted in some way to recklessly abandon their current situation and make plans to hit the road.  Even if the trip amounts to nothing, and no progress on a sense of life purpose, at the very least there is a thrill of escape, of running away from the daily struggle.  What a thrill, like escaping a prison - a prison we’ve willingly signed up for.</p>

<p>And why not take a chance?  It’s like the escape of running off to travel the world, except much less expensive and with far less communication barriers along the way.</p>

<p>Of course I should say that anyone lucky enough to be in circumstances to even entertain these thoughts is privileged.  I’m sure some shake their heads in disgust that such spoiled people aren’t content, and feel the need to escape from their comfortable life.</p>

<p>Maybe the person wanting to make a jailbreak is a millenial such as myself, somewho is spoiled, never had to truly struggle as generations past, and all through life lead along nowhere-in-particular with a carrot-on-a-stick, a buildup to the glorious present.  The present, which turned out to be the mundane grind of a meaningless job that happens to pay well, and maybe continues to spoil you with free food and other perks, in the hopes to stifle those existential pains.</p>

<p>We have all this and then still complain?  I know why folks are outraged at the thought, but this struggle isn’t new, and the American Road Trip has always been a cross-generational outlet to find one’s purpose in the face of mundane reality.  I’m not sure how far back you have to go to be considered a “millenial”, but stretching it back to Jack Kerouac’s <em>On The Road</em> would be reaching.</p>

<p>A bit of a side note: but I thought I was Generation Y, not Millenial?  Or are they the same?  I never really liked being lumped into a category, especially one based on a time period in which I was born.  Next thing you know, folks will be analyzing personalities based on their birth month.  But I guess we’ll leave that to astrology and other bunk.</p>

<p>In any case, why not explore the possibilities?</p>

<p>If I stayed in a good but meaningless job where my ego was stroked and my belly and wallet fattened, that would be a sure way to come out in ten years as a bored, unfulfilled, fat, entitled individual.  And ten years older at that, probably with debts and a mortgage to pay off for life (the terms of the sentence).  Perhaps I’d become lazy and never challenged myself to get out and explore different possibilities, different ways of making a living.  Perhaps I’d never considered that I could make money doing other things, that I could seriously consider and try other modes of living, or at least observe them in others as I sped by their world in my car.</p>

<p>What better way of doing all that, than on a trip across the country?  Where you could get out and see how different folks existing and living in various ways?  What a taste of all the options, all the possibilities.  At the very least you could figure out if the air smelled differently in different parts, if people talked differently, if folks were kinder in some parts or had different attitudes.  What a shame never to experience it.</p>

<p>Many folks may be comparatively well-off to be able to undertake such an adventure.  But what a truly great adventure it must be!  What a truly great opportunity, and what a privilege to have the option to look at these possibilities and to turn them over in one’s mind for days on end, to take them seriously and try to understand them.</p>

<p>Socrates once said:</p>

<blockquote>
Besides, it is a disgrace to grow old through sheer carelessness before seeing what manner of man you may become by developing your bodily strength and beauty to their highest limit.
<br /><br />
αἰσχρὸν δὲ καὶ τὸ διὰ τὴν ἀμέλειαν γηρᾶναι, πρὶν ἰδεῖν ἑαυτὸν ποῖος ἂν κάλλιστος καὶ κράτιστος τῷ σώματι γένοιτο
<br /><br />
(from Xenophon's Memorabilia)
</blockquote>

<p>This can also be applied to our mental life, and our way of living.  We have the opportunity to push our bodies to its limits to test it and know how much we are possible of.</p>

<p>How much can we push our comfort zone and know other ways of living, and to explore those possibilities?  What a shame to grow old and never have experienced those limits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My year in photos (2016)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T23:17:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014/">part one</a> and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-2014-part-2/">part two</a>).  I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!</p>

<p>Onto the pics!</p>

<h2 id="february">February</h2>

<p>I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-01-feb-yosemite-night-sky.jpg 1000 666 Night sky from Yosemite %}</p>

<p>For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.  I was super happy with the way this turned out.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-02-feb-pinecrest-lake-in-snow.jpg 1000 666 Pinecrest Lake in the snow (California, near Yosemite) %}</p>

<p>Interesting tree stumps around Pinecrest Lake area, in the snow.</p>

<h2 id="march">March</h2>

<p>At the end of March, I quit my job and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again/">ended up in Japan again</a> for the next few months!</p>

<p>One of my favorite photos from the entire several months was taken from the first night at the hotel.  I had a corner room in the Star Gate hotel, which towers over south Osaka and has a great view of the Kansai International Airport.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-03-march-kansai-international-airport.jpg 666 1000 Kansai International Airport seen from the Star Gate Hotel in Osaka, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-04-march-kyoto-sparrow-and-cherry-blossoms.jpg 666 1000 Sparrow and cherry blossoms on the Path of Philosophy in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<h2 id="april">April</h2>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-05-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-06-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-07-april-kiyomizudera-lightup.jpg 1000 666 Kiyomizudera lightup in Kyoto, Japan %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-08-april-kyoto-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto backstreets at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-09-april-nara-monju-e-ceremony.jpg 1000 666 Nara Monju-e Ceremony %}</p>

<p>(<a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara/">see more photos and video from the Nara Monju-e Ceremony</a>)</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-10-april-nara-deer-and-lantern.jpg 666 1000 Nara deer and traditional lantern %}</p>

<p>I’ve always wanted to ride the shinkansen (bullet train) as far north as I could, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/">I finally did it</a>.  I boarded the bullet train in Kyoto and ended up at its terminus in Hakodate.  The final stretch of bullet train to Hakodate had only opened days before, and they were still celebrating its completion.</p>

<p>They’re currently building the final stretch from Hakodate to Sapporo, but it’s not due to be complete until sometime in the 2030s or so.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-11-april-rainy-shinkansen.jpg 1000 666 Rainy day on the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-12-april-northern-japan-coast.jpg 1000 666 The coast of northern Japan, seen from the shinkansen %}</p>

<p>This isn’t a super great photo, but I thought it was interesting for a few reasons.  There were these stone markers occassionally by the tracks.  And there was also a whole lot of trash, mostly fisherman trash like baubles.</p>

<p>Kind of surprising how much trash was along the coast here, especially for Japan’s reputation for cleanliness.  Was this remants of the 2011 tsunami?  Well, it’s five years later and this stuff is still here…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-13-april-hakodate-sunset.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate sunset %}</p>

<p>Hakodate is a fun little town.  Of course I had to take the tram up to the top of Mount Hakodate, then watch the sunset with all the other tourists…</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-14-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-15-april-hakodate-night-view.jpg 1000 666 Hakodate night view - the reality of the crowds.  Absolutely packed. %}</p>

<p>Mount Hakodate at sunset was swarming with tourists.  I’m glad I did it once, but I wouldn’t do it again.</p>

<p>Around Hakodate there was this trendy hamburger place called Lucky Pierrot, which looked more like a carnival.  They had some interesting vending machines propped up outside their shop.  Looked like something out of a video game:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-16-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-17-april-hakodate-lucky-pierrot-vending-machine.jpg 666 1000 Lucky Pierrot vending machine %}</p>

<p>Sapporo was still a bit snowy in April!</p>

<p>…And I was totally unprepared.  I took some photos, then had to duck inside somewhere to warm up.  I found a mall with some ramen restaurants and a Uniqlo - both of which had things that could help me warm up.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-18-april-sapporo-ramen.jpg 666 1000 Delicious Sapporo ramen %}</p>

<h2 id="may">May</h2>

<p>In May I visited Indonesia with Yuka, but I was too afraid to bring my DSLR, which was a stupid idea in retrospect.  I took some video there, and took lots of photos with my phone, which I guess I’ll have to post eventually.</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/the-roads-of-indonesia/">Here you can watch a Muslim parade</a>, and <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/indonesia-trip-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/">here you can listen to me ramble on about my experience in Indonesia</a>.</p>

<p>When I came back to Japan, it was time to explore some more!</p>

<p>I returned to Byodoin Temple in Nara, which had been restored to its original vermillion colors since my last visit a few years back:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-19-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-20-may-byodoin-temple.jpg 1000 666 Byodoin Temple in Nara %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-21-may-kyoto-aqua-marine-diving-school.jpg 1000 666 Aqua Marine Diving School (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>This probably isn’t a super interesting photo for you, but I actually walked past this, then thought better of it and walked back to snap a photo, because I thought it was just interesting.  It jumped out again for me when going through my photos, so I had to include it among my favorites just for the subject matter.  The hiragana reads “Diving School”.</p>

<p>Yuka had been wanting to take me up to Mount Rokko for a while.  It was a fun experience riding the cable car to the top, then eating some good food at the top.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-22-may-mount-rokko-cable-car.jpg 666 1000 Accidental self-portrait, and a view from the Mount Rokko cable car (Osaka, Japan) %}</p>

<h2 id="june">June</h2>

<p>In June I tried something new: I gave myself a photo assignment.  Just to go out on a mission, and come back with some tangible decent photos.</p>

<p>I know Kyoto is amazing at night, with lots of things to discover in the nooks and crannies of the city I’ve spent the last few years exploring.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-23-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 666 1000 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-24-june-kyoto-alleyways-at-night.jpg 1000 666 Kyoto alleyways at night %}</p>

<p>I posted a few more photos from my Kyoto photo assignment <a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/">here</a>.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-25-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>I had mixed emotions about visiting Shirakawago, a UNESCO World Heritage site with a bunch of interesting old thatched houses.  The place was incredibly touristy, and I had a run-in with some pushy Japanese grandmas who unabashedly cut in line in front of me at a gift shop.</p>

<p>It was an interesting place - I may be back eventually in the winter, which is the more common time to take photos of the truly interesting old-fashioned houses.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-26-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-27-june-shirakawago.jpg 1000 666 Shirakawago %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-28-june-kamogawa-sparrows.jpg 1000 666 Sparrows playing beside the Kamogawa (Kyoto, Japan) %}</p>

<p>I brought my DSLR to a short weekend trip to Busan with Yuka, but didn’t take many good photos there.  I did like this one shot of a cute dog in a traditional market though:</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-29-june-dog-in-korea.jpg 666 1000 Cute dog (Busan, Korea) %}</p>

<h2 id="october">October</h2>

<p>Back in the US!</p>

<p>I took a few road trips, especially to capture the changing seasons in California.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-30-oct-june-lake-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains seen from June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-31-oct-june-lake.jpg 1000 666 Boat docked at June Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32-oct-mono-lake-alien-moonrise.jpg 1000 666 Alien moonrise on the shores of Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-32b-oct-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Mono Lake at night %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-33-oct-mountains-view-from-mono-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowy mountains at night, seen from Mono Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-34-oct-lake-sabrina-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Mountains at Lake Sabrina %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-35-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Lundy Lake sunrise %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-36-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Snowcapped mountains seen from Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-37-oct-lundy-lake.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors along Lundy Lake %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-38-oct-road-to-lobdell-lake-fall-colors.jpg 1000 666 Fall colors on the road to Lobdell Lake (California) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-39-oct-drive-back-to-san-bernardino-mountains.jpg 1000 666 Intense storm clouds seen on the drive back to the San Bernardino mountains %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-40-oct-fall-leaves-in-big-bear.jpg 1000 666 Fall leaves on a brick walkway, at home in Big Bear %}</p>

<h2 id="november">November</h2>

<p>My mom spontaneously booked a trip to New Orleans, and I agreed to tag along.  It was a nice return to a truly interesting city.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-41-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 The lobby of the W Hotel French Quarter (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-42-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square seen from the steamboat Natchez, on the Missisippi River %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-43-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Chartres %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-44-nov-new-orleans.jpg 666 1000 “At Rest” gravestone in a New Orleans cemetery %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-45-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Statue near the French Market: Michelle by sculptor Paul Perret (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-46-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square at night with the largest supermoon in decades (New Orleans) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-47-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 S. Andral Kilmer, M.D. Swamp Root medicine at the LSU Rural Life Museum  %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-48-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Swamp trees in Louisiana %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-49-nov-new-orleans.jpg 1000 666 Turtle sunbathing on the swamp %}</p>

<p><a href="//davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/">See more photos from my New Orleans trip</a>.</p>

<h2 id="december">December</h2>

<p>One last road trip of the year!  Just before Christmas, I took a drive to Zion National Park.  I am definitely returning to this beautiful place, and I’m already planning future hikes and photo shoots here.</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-50-dec-desert-near-baker.jpg 1000 666 Desert sunset, near Baker, Nevada %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-51-dec-zion.jpg 666 1000 Sandstone and ice (Zion National Park) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-52-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-53-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty Towers of the Virgin mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-best-of-54-dec-zion.jpg 1000 666 Misty morning mountains in Zion National Park %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Orleans trip (November 2016)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-21T11:51:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/new-orleans-trip-november-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I had the opportunity to visit New Orleans in the spring with my friend.  Now I’ve returned with my parents to visit in the fall!</p>

<p>My mom had recently expressed a desire to do more travelling while still physically able, which kicked off creating a list of places to visit, and ultimately booking this first trip.  Hopefully the first of many to come.  She asked if I wanted to tag along, and I couldn’t pass up another visit to the city.  I also thought I could help out a bit, since I’d already visited the city before.</p>

<p>On to the photos!</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-01.jpg 666 1000 No visit is complete without trying out some beignets!  From Cafe Beignet on Bourbon Street. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-02.jpg 1000 666 Al “Jumbo” Hirt Jazz statue at Cafe Beignet. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-03.jpg 666 1000 Grave of Marie Laveau, Queen of Voodoo.  Note the barely visible “XXX” marks. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-04.jpg 666 1000 Unique vertical tomb style, stacked five caskets high. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-05.jpg 1000 666 Nicholas Cage’s future resting place.  Not joking. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-06.jpg 1000 666 Cemetery %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-07.jpg 1000 666 Angel statue, melted by time (and acid rain) %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-08.jpg 1000 666 Statue near the French Market: Michelle by sculptor Paul Perret %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-09.jpg 666 1000 Joan of Arc statue %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-10.jpg 666 1000 “At Rest” from Cypress Grove Cemetery %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-11.jpg 1000 666 Swamp tree %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-12.jpg 1000 666 Turtles sunbathing in a swamp %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-13.jpg 1000 666 Alligator in a swamp %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-14.jpg 1000 666 Spider in a swamp.  The tour guide got close to this one and rubbed its belly with his bare hands.  “You know you’re in Louisiana when they tickle the spiders” said one fellow tourist. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-15.jpg 1000 666 Great Blue Heron %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-16.jpg 1000 666 Swamp trees %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-17.jpg 1000 666 The bayou with another tourist riverboat in view. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-18.jpg 1000 666 Alligators %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-19.jpg 1000 666 Alligator hiding underwater %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-20.jpg 1000 666 New Orleans skyline at sunset. %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-21.jpg 666 1000 Benito Juarez statue %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-22.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad on Bourbon Street.  My mom was on the phone with my sister, who was trying to get a screen grab of us on a street webcam. %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-23.jpg 1000 666 Segway tours trailing a horse and carriage %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-24.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-25.jpg 1000 666 Aboard the Natchez Steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-26.jpg 1000 666 Jackson Square seen from the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-27.jpg 1000 666 Speed control on the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-28.jpg 1000 666 Closeup from the engine room of the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-29.jpg 1000 666 Closeup from the engine room of the steamboat %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-30.jpg 1000 666 View down the street %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-31.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Santa Ana %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-32.jpg 1000 666 Balcony in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-33.jpg 666 1000 Hot sauce paradise %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-34.jpg 666 1000 Building in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-35.jpg 1000 666 Balcony in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-36.jpg 1000 666 Acme Oyster House %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-37.jpg 1000 666 Chargrileld Oysters from Acme Oyster House %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-38.jpg 1000 666 Jazz band in the French Quarter %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-39.jpg 666 1000 Mom and dad in front of some shady establishments on Bourbon Street %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-40.jpg 1000 666 Great colors in the driveway of our hotel (The W Hotel) %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-41.jpg 666 1000 W Hotel courtyard at night %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-42.jpg 1000 666 Andrew Jackson statue at night %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-43.jpg 1000 666 Steamboat Natchez at sunrise %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-44.jpg 1000 666 Sunrise on the Mississipi River - taken standing on the levee %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-45.jpg 666 1000 Calle D Chartres.  This was the street our hotel was on, so we got to know its name well! %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-46.jpg 666 1000 Spanish moss %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-47.jpg 1000 666 Slave prison, from the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-48.jpg 1000 666 Teche Mamou Genuine Mentholated Cough Syrup %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-49.jpg 1000 666 S. Andral Kilmer, M.D. Swamp Root %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-50.jpg 1000 666 Poor folks’ church in the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}</p>

<p>{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-51.jpg 1000 666 Painted windows instead of stained windows at the poor folks’ church in the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-52.jpg 1000 666 Creepy statue in the cemetery at the LSU Rural Life Museum in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-53.jpg 1000 666 Crab and Crawfish Au Gratin from Parrain’s Seafood Restaurant in Baton Rouge %}<br />
{% imgcap center //davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/2016-11-new-orleans-54.jpg 1000 666 Andouille Encrusted Fresh Fish from Parrain’s Seafood Restaurant in Baton Rouge %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
