<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nara on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/nara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nara on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/nara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!&#xA;Onto the pics!&#xA;February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.&#xA;Night sky from Yosemite For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monju-e Ceremony in Nara (文殊会 興福寺)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 22:34:10 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</guid>
      <description>From April 25, 2016.&#xA;Monju or Manjusri is a bodhisattva of wisdom. In this ceremony children’s healthy growth and academic success are prayed for.&#xA;14:30~ A procession of children in traditional costumes. Starts from Jyokyoji Temple on Sanjyo St. towards Kofukuji Temple.&#xA;15:00~ Ritual ceremony at Tokondo Hall in Kofukuji Temple&#xA;文殊会 (興福寺) 毎月25日は文殊菩薩の縁日。東金堂の文殊菩薩は古くから学問僧の信仰を集めてきた。­文殊会では文殊菩薩の智恵を授かろうと稚児の行列が、浄教寺より一字書の奉額車を引い­て三条通りを練り歩きます。 なお、当日堂内の拝観は14時までですが、外からの拝観は可能。（受付終了は13時4­5分）</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 2 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>I was just putting together this article and these photos on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve when I glanced and the clock and noticed I was already four minutes into 2015. Oops!&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the second-parter for my favorite photo from 2014. Also be sure to check out the first part.&#xA;July Yuka was still here in early July, just in time to see Fourth of July fireworks at Big Bear Lake, California, before she had to go back to Japan.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
