<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>california on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/california/</link>
    <description>Recent content in california on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/california/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2018)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:48:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2018/my-year-in-photos-2018/</guid>
      <description>When the year&amp;rsquo;s days shorten and their number dwindles, I have liked to sometimes take the initiative to sort through all the photos I&amp;rsquo;ve taken (with my &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; camera). The eventual goal: to put together a sampling of the photos that stand out, sometimes for technical reasons, and sometimes for other reasons.
This year I sadly didn&amp;rsquo;t get out with the camera as much as I have in previous years, which made this post much easier (no excuses this year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 2 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-2-2014/</guid>
      <description>I was just putting together this article and these photos on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve when I glanced and the clock and noticed I was already four minutes into 2015. Oops!
Here&amp;rsquo;s the second-parter for my favorite photo from 2014. Also be sure to check out the first part.
July Yuka was still here in early July, just in time to see Fourth of July fireworks at Big Bear Lake, California, before she had to go back to Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos, part 1 (2014)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/my-year-in-photos-part-1-2014/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s nearing the year&amp;rsquo;s end, so of course this means a somewhat sentimental blog post from me. I was thinking of a &amp;ldquo;resolutions/goals&amp;rdquo; type post, but I decided against it. Instead here&amp;rsquo;s something more entertaining: my favorite photos from the past year! Note that these aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily my best, just my favorites.
Finding these is also a little bit of housekeeping for me and my photos. It forces me to sort the gigabytes and gigabytes of RAW photos I was casually dumping onto drives the entire year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
