<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Politics on David Calhoun's blog</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on David Calhoun's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 09:35:44 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maybe it's healthier to embrace discomfort</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 09:35:44 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many folks, including yours truly, have had an unpleasant night, and this morning a bitter awakening at the announcement that our new President will be Trump. For most folks this comes as a shock, as we have all thought the chances of this happening were slim. Comedians chided him on and dared him to run. Even President Obama who continually roasted him &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n9mzJhvC-8E">at the White House Correspondents&amp;rsquo; Dinner in 2011&lt;/a>, arguably the defining moment when Trump became driven to run for President (&amp;ldquo;He certainly would bring some change to the White House&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:06:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to be bored with non-junk. We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways. We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fourth of July letter to my government</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government/</guid><description>&lt;p>(this is a copy of a letter which I&amp;rsquo;ve sent to various representatives in government)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a concerned citizen, I know you understand that I must occasionally voice my concern through letters such as this. My hope is that you will honestly consider my claims and take action on my part. I honestly appreciate you taking your time to seriously consider this letter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m writing to you today specifically in response to abuses by the NSA overstepping its bounds. Citizens of the United States and citizens of the world now know its private data is being indiscriminately collected, sifted through, and intruded upon by the NSA. These actions are clearly antithetical to our own Constitution and set a terrible precedent for the future of this country and the rest of the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on TrapWire</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/thoughts-on-trapwire/</guid><description>&lt;figure itemprop="image" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject" class="center">
 &lt;meta itemprop="width" content="817" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="height" content="1000" />
 &lt;meta itemprop="url" content="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg" />
 &lt;a href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg">
 &lt;img itemprop="contentUrl" src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/george-friedman-stratfor.jpg" alt="Stratfor CEO George Friedman" />
 &lt;/a>
 &lt;figcaption itemprop="caption">Stratfor CEO George Friedman&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;quot;&amp;hellip;but the hackers will not find intelligence of corporations and governments, or signs of a vast conspiracy&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; -Stratfor CEO George Friedman, January 2012&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;eight months later&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;WIKILEAKS: Surveillance Cameras Around The Country Are Being Used In A Huge Spy Network&amp;rdquo; -Business Insider, August 2012&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, there been some big news released recently as a result of another release of documents by Wikileaks on August 9, 2012. The documents are &lt;a href="http://mirror2.wikileaks-press.org/gifiles/releasedate/2012-08-09.html">emails from the global intelligence company Stratfor&lt;/a>. The most recent release has confirmed what many conspiracy theorists have feared for years: that the government is operating a vast secret surveillance network that is collecting data on citizens and their movements.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>