<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>japanese on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/japanese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in japanese on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/japanese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to import imiwa? vocabulary lists directly into Anki (iOS, iPhone guide)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/how-to-import-imiwa-vocabulary-lists-directly-into-anki-ios-iphone-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/how-to-import-imiwa-vocabulary-lists-directly-into-anki-ios-iphone-guide/</guid>
      <description>EDIT: big thanks to my classmate Robin from Switzerland who showed me the key steps to getting this figured out!
For the last six months, I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly been using imiwa? for iOS to look up Japanese words whenever I don&amp;rsquo;t know them (mostly in class). However, I found that I built up big lists without ever reviewing them.
The best way to review is of course through Anki, but it was a laborious process to import each word one-by-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think I&#39;m learning Japanese: JLPT vocabulary words 1 to 50 (audio)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/i-think-im-learning-japanese-jlpt-vocabulary-words-1-to-50-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/i-think-im-learning-japanese-jlpt-vocabulary-words-1-to-50-audio/</guid>
      <description>(2016 note: this was a terrible idea because I&amp;rsquo;m neither a native speaker nor a good speaker in general.. but I&amp;rsquo;m leaving this up for posterity&amp;hellip;)
I have been learning bits and pieces of Japanese throughout the years, and picking up more and more on each of my trips to Japan. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to buckle down and get disciplined about learning, and make some real progress.
As with learning any language, having a decent vocabulary is critical in order to form coherent sentences, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to focus on this for the time being, in addition to learning hiragana and katakana and getting it down pat, with no errors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
