<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: night | David Calhoun's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/night/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-26T10:21:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick failed trip to Pinnacles National Park]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-12T23:40:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’d been looking for a night like tonight for a long time, when the new moon fell squarely on the weekend.  The only problem: unpredictable weather!</p>

<p>I drive about an hour and a half south on the 101 and then the 25 to head towards the east Pinnacles entrance, which I’d never been at before.  I also chatted with Yuka over LINE for a bit of it, at least until the reception got bad and dropped the call about ten minutes beofre getting to the park.</p>

<p>In any case, I made past the folks camping nearby, to the wide open dirt parking lot.  I rolled down my window, and stuck my head out the window to look up at the sky.  Wait, what sky?  It turned out to be clouds.  100% clouds.</p>

<p>The forecast said it would be partly cloudy, which has sometimes meant 10% clouds whereas other times…  Well, I guess this fell into the “other times” category.</p>

<p>Just proves that you can’t win them all, and you can’t plan everything.  Sometimes you just have to travel a lot and occassionally get lucky.</p>

<p>Like the time the moon was rising straight over the road behind me on the way to my parents’ house in Big Bear, but I didn’t have my camera stuff ready in time.  That would’ve been an awesome shot, but now it’s an awesome memory.</p>

<p>Or the time I drove up Whitney Portal Road to get a shot of <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/franksvalli/13234418335">the snow-covered mountains that you could see visibly glowing under the moonlight</a>.</p>

<p>Until next time!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-19T19:05:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><figure class='center'><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-07-18-milky-way-over-trees-yosemite-valley-david-calhoun-5D__3685.jpg" width="666" height="1000" title="Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am" ><figcaption>Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am</figcaption></figure></p>

<p>Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total.  The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.</p>

<p>While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky.  It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</p>

<p>My eyes started to track it across the sky, but it almost looked like it was dancing instead of advancing steadily.  It was going stop-go but very smoothly.</p>

<p>At this point I should mention that I’d drank much more coffee than I really should have, in preparation for the long drive.  Despite all the coffee I was getting very tired, which made for a bad combination with driving.</p>

<p>I think the dancing of the satellite was due to the effects of the coffee, that or it was just a natural optical illusion.</p>

<p>The satellite went behind some trees, and soon after that I saw a very bright star emerge over the mountains on the other side of the trees.</p>

<p>Must be a UFO!</p>

<p>I looked at the star intently, and could swear I could see it dancing as well, though a bit more stationary.  It was also changing colors - red, blue, white.  Obviously a very patriotic UFO.</p>

<p>My delirium-fueled excitement was pushing me to get out my super telephoto, which is exactly what I did.  Here I with the perfect equipment, tripod, and RAW video capabilities!  A really good UFO video to post to YouTube!</p>

<p>But nope.  Zoomed in on a tripod, it was clear it was a fairly stationary star, only moving progressively with the backdrop of the other stars in Yosemite’s real-life planetarium.</p>

<p>It was clear it was time to head to bed.  Who knows what else I’d start seeing after a while…</p>

<p>Parked somewhere in a gravel parking lot near Camp Curry and slept in my car (whoohoo for being single and getting to save money).</p>

<p>It was around 4am when I was finally getting to sleep.</p>

<p>Written at the top of Nevada Falls, Yosemite</p>

<p><figure class='center'><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/2015-07-18-international-space-station-and-capella.png" width="375" height="667" title="The “UFO” turned out to be the International Space Station, and when it appeared to come out of the trees over the mountain on the right, it was actually Capella" ><figcaption>The “UFO” turned out to be the International Space Station, and when it appeared to come out of the trees over the mountain on the right, it was actually Capella</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
