<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astrophotography on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/astrophotography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astrophotography on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:40:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/astrophotography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick failed trip to Pinnacles National Park</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:40:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quick-failed-trip-to-pinnacles-national-park/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d been looking for a night like tonight for a long time, when the new moon fell squarely on the weekend. The only problem: unpredictable weather!
I drive about an hour and a half south on the 101 and then the 25 to head towards the east Pinnacles entrance, which I&amp;rsquo;d never been at before. I also chatted with Yuka over LINE for a bit of it, at least until the reception got bad and dropped the call about ten minutes beofre getting to the park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 19:05:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am  Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total. The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.
While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky. It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 23:12:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui (at the Mauian hotel)  I was lucky enough to finally visit Hawaii with my parents. Being experts Hawaii tourists, they set us up in a nice traditional resort called The Mauian - a nice quiet(er) little place that has a time for &amp;ldquo;quiet hours&amp;rdquo; (apparently the other resorts are places to party).
We got back to the hotel a little after quiet hours, and my folks mentioned that you could see the Milky Way quite clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
