<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:27:34 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schindler&#39;s List (1993) (Top 100 Films)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:27:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/schindlers-list-1993-top-100-films/</guid>
      <description>Schindler&#39;s List title card with candles  This is a film that is best experienced, not explained in a post like this. However, that being said, I&amp;rsquo;ll give this a try anyhow.
I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided this film all my life out of dread more than anything. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat weird then that I watched this so early in my &amp;ldquo;Top 100&amp;rdquo; films quest. I knew I&amp;rsquo;d have to watch it eventually anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan: from miniature train to bullet train</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</guid>
      <description>Japanese riding a miniature railroad, brought by Perry to Japan  (view the full image, image credit)
A long time ago, four black ships appeared off the coast of Japan, which had closed itself off from the world and its influences. These ships were from the US, and commanding them was Commodore Matthew C. Perry, who was instrumental in reopening Japan to the rest of the world.
As a result of this, and to promote a goodwill between the two countries, Perry gave various gifts to Japan, one of which was a one-fourth scale model train, in order to convincingly demonstrate the benefit of adopting Western technology:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>