<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-23T16:24:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-04T00:32:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><figure itemprop='image' itemscope itemtype='http://schema.org/ImageObject' class='center'><meta itemprop='width' content='1000'><meta itemprop='height' content='666'><meta itemprop='url' content='http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg'><img itemprop='contentUrl' src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/haleakala-sunset-david-calhoun.jpg" width="1000" height="666" title="Haleakala sunset" ><figcaption itemprop='caption'>Haleakala sunset</figcaption></figure></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We’re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks?  And it’s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who’s bored is asleep, and somebody who’s asleep will not say no?<br />From <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MRBZDmf1jSw">My Dinner With Andre</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unless I die young, I haven’t quite made it to my midlife crisis yet.  But it does seem to me that I’ve heard more and more about people experiencing their “quarter-life” crises.  Is this something new?  Or have people always had so many of these doubting periods?  Or maybe we’re at a time where so many of us have the freedom and luxury to even contemplate such a thing, a freedom that leads to our own detriment.</p>

<p>I’m admittedly not great at math, but it does seem to me these quarter-life crises should occur in someone’s early 20’s.  Is that crisis somehow supposed to eventually pass, or just it just get quietly ignored while we distract ourselves with other concerns?  Then we learn to get comfortably numb and sleepy and learn to accept life for how mundane it really is?  Can a midlife crisis still re-emerge later on in life, after a person wakes up again?</p>

<p>I’m fairly certain I’ve been asleep these past few years.  I wouldn’t be surprised, since I do like to sleep (I sometimes waste entire weekends on the couch or in bed, but that’s another story).</p>

<p>I’m too old for these childish quarter-life crises.  The only explanation for this current one is that I must’ve graduated to the rarely-if-ever-mentioned third-life crisis.  A relevant question to ask myself here: just how many damn life crises is it normal for someone to have, and do they ever stop?</p>

<p>In my 20’s I graduated college, had a choice of career paths and started to float and drift a bit, getting a job testing cellphone games.  There I made some friends, but it didn’t really advance my career or my personal life outside of that.</p>

<p>I got older, I worked more, I got a job at a big corporate job, doing what I thought was a decent career.  But I learned that big corporate jobs are soul-numbing.  I quit my big corporate job and did the inevitable clichéd trip to Asia.  Particularly in my field, folks seem to get the same idea.  (Not unlike other things I suppose: Everyone wants to travel to Asia, everyone wants to move to Portland or Austin, everyone wants to save up for a house, everyone wants a Tesla).</p>

<p>That experience traveling helped me grow as a person more than any job ever did, but apparently I didn’t grow or learn enough, because I found myself falling into the same pattern as before.  Get the comfortable corporate job, dance like a monkey if I wanted to advance and get promoted, then try to save up for a house like everyone else.</p>

<p>The idiotic Silicon Valley version: save up for a down payment on a ridiculously overpriced house that’s in the bad part of town and also falling apart (because that’s the only one you can afford making comparative chump change to everyone else).  Maybe also save up for a Tesla, so at the very least you can brag to your coworkers that you bought a Tesla.  Because Tesla.</p>

<p>Then you get a job at what’s supposed to be the Best Place To Work In The Universe, according to a survey of all known workers in the universe.  You find that it’s not too much different than your previous Big Corporate Job.  Is this really all there is to look forward to?  So I can buy a house and a Tesla?  What next after that even?  Work the rest of the best years of my life paying off the house?</p>

<p>What if I don’t want a house (though not sharing walls would be nice)?  What if I don’t want a Tesla?  I don’t think I’m the only one.  I think all those folks who quit their jobs to travel the world likely have the same feelings.  They’re trying to escape from something.  Their inner selves seem to have woken up from a nightmare in the night, and are restlessly awake, pacing back and forth.  Except they’re pacing through the world, not just their bedrooms.</p>

<p>Some of these folks even get the idea that the ideal lifestyle is being a traveling nomad, hopping from country to country, somehow earning enough money to get by.  If they can make it work, I think they do tend to be happier, or at least more alive and more childlike and inquisitive.  Is it just the permanent change in scenery?  I’m not sure I’d be comfortable in that sort of lifestyle myself.  It is always nice to come back home eventually, and to spend time with familiar friends and family, and familiar things in general.  Sometimes it’s nice to be a little hobbit-like.</p>

<p>Is all this travelling and escaping just a delaying of inevitable adulthood?  What if I’m already an adult - does it mean I’m just deceiving myself?  Am I running away from myself?  Is adulthood really just the acceptance that you’re not special, that this really is the only thing life is about?  That your life is the thing that happens for a few brief hours after work, and entire weekends that you may end up wasting on stupid pursuits?</p>

<p>As much as philosophy has helped me, in cases like this I think it’s kind of made me dissatisfied with everything.</p>

<p>Maybe I can still somehow play and enjoy the game of life, even if I realize it’s only some silly game we’ve concocted to keep ourselves busy?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Existential nights]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-30T00:05:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These damn existential nights are the worst.</p>

<p>I’m tired of wasting my nights distracting myself, so I stayed at work late and went to the gym even later, then left around 10:45pm.</p>

<p>Even while exercising I could feel me asking myself nagging questions.  Why am I working out?  What’s the goal?  What’s the point of keeping your body healthy if you don’t even know where you’re going?</p>

<p>These are important questions, but not the right questions when I’m not in the mood.  I thought exercise could keep some depression at bay, but it’s still there, and there it reappears at the most inconvenient times.</p>

<p>I’m fighting it.</p>

<p>My body is getting healthier and my mind is getting stronger, and I’m slowly figuring out the path I’m going to take.</p>

<p>Sleep is the best medicine for now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A theory of leisure time, choice, and happiness]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is finally the end of my first week in Japanese language school here in Kyoto. It’s been quite a long week, with the most studying I’ve ever done in my life. We’ve gone through nine chapters in a week, and just Friday received two more books for learning Kanji. We’ll learn our first 50 Kanji in a week, alongside the rest of our classes. I already know some words here and there, but for the most part, much of what we’ve just learned is a blur, which is forcing me to use almost all of my free time in running to catch up.</p>

<p>Having very little leisure time has been good in some ways. It’s been a marked change in the cozy, comfortable lifestyle of sitting in front of a computer screen all day, doing tasks which were somewhat challenging but ultimately not rewarding. Those days in Silicon Valley were ended with a gratuitous amount of free time (which is unusual, working for a startup). Which seems nice for a while, but becomes a bit maddening after long, at least for me.</p>

<p>I remember moving to Silicon Valley and buying my TV and PS3 and everything to set me up with all the comforts of my new lifestyle. After coming home from work, I would waste away my time on my computer, my TV, or my video games. After long it was pretty easy to see the same mundane cycle develop: wake up, work, waste time, sleep. Rinse, repeat. Ad nauseum. Ad absurdum.</p>

<p>It became apparent that this lifestyle wasn’t really healthy, mentally or physically. It would be better, I thought, to live in a city where I needed to walk around from place to place, or take public transport. San Francisco is perfect for that, but I gave the city (or should I say “The City” as folks there do) a shot and it never really grew on me. In my short time here on Earth, I’ve found there are other cities that are better suited to me. I wanted to find a city I liked, which ended up being far away Kyoto, where I’m at now.</p>

<p>My unhealthy physical lifestyle, combined with too much free time, had resulted in an unhealthy mental state. I believe lack of exercise leads to deteriorated mental performance as well as depression, and this is what I believe I experienced. This combined with too much free time, solitude, and a brooding time resulted in days where I’d come home from work and attempt to distract myself by browsing the internet the rest of the day. I ended up absorbing the highly-prized gift of free time which I wasted with abandon, before going asleep and starting the cycle over again.</p>

<p>Now, after becoming a student, I have relearned what it’s like to have every little free time. I’m stressed out and overwhelmed already (as a beginner Japanese language student), but it feels good in a lot of ways. I feel alive, but I also feel like I’m not squandering my free time, or worrying about what I do with the free time I have. In a lot of ways I think I became maddened with the choice, and maddened with brooding in my free time over my life path and the usefulness (to society) of my career choice. Maybe I had chosen the wrong one? I wonder what it would be like if I had chosen to live in Japan after all?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you marry, you will regret it; if you do not marry, you will also regret it; if you marry or do not marry, you will regret both;</p>

  <p>Laugh at the world’s follies, you will regret it, weep over them, you will also regret that; laugh at the world’s follies or weep over them, you will regret both; whether you laugh at the world’s follies or weep over them, you will regret both.</p>

  <p>Believe a woman, you will regret it, believe her not, you will also regret that; believe a woman or believe her not, you will regret both; whether you believe a woman or believe her not, you will regret both.</p>

  <p>Hang yourself, you will regret it; do not hang yourself, and you will also regret that; hang yourself or do not hang yourself, you will regret both; whether you hang yourself or do not hang yourself, you will regret both.</p>

  <p>This, gentlemen, is the sum and substance of all philosophy. (Kierkegaard)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This passage by Kierkegaard gives a lot of insight into the brooding mind of an existentialist, but arguably offers us a glimpse at the modern human predicament. We make choices daily, and we also make great life-changing choices. It’s natural to think “Would I have been better off if I did it differently? If I choose differently?”.</p>

<p>Kierkegaard himself, if I remember right, lived off of his family’s money and didn’t have to worry about work. He had an excessive amount of leisure time, and perhaps that influenced the amount of time he had to brood over his life’s choices. He certainly had enough time to write down these thoughts, so I would think that his thoughts themselves were more numerous than his writings.</p>

<p>Since I no longer have too much free time, but rather too little of it, I have that much less time to brood over matters. I have made my choices for now (moving to Japan, studying Japanese full time), and I will only know if I’ve made the right decision after spending more time giving this path a try.</p>

<p>This is good in a lot of ways. In a lot of ways, the choice of what to do in my leisure time has been made for me. I must use it to study.</p>

<p>The choice is made! The existentialist dilemma has been, at the very least, temporarily pushed aside.</p>

<p>And at the very best, the existentialist dilemma has been conquered. “Live in Japan or do not live in Japan, you will regret it either way”. Now I have done both. I’ve now lived on both sides of the coin, on both sides of the world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The life of your parents&#8217; choosing]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several times I’ve heard the phrase “the religion of your parents’ choosing”, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.</p>

<p>How strange then not to carry this philosophy into more of our social behaviors. Why should we then avoid phrases such as “the culture/land of your parents’ choosing”?</p>

<p>It seems to me that this carries the same implications as religious belief. For instance, permenently moving to another country is in a sense turning one’s back on their upbringing and their whole social group. Of course this isn’t a total turning away: a person might return to one’s home country after many years, just as they might return to their faith after many years away.</p>

<p>Both of these moves seem only possible after exposure to different ways of thinking, something increasingly made possible as the modern world progresses. It should be of little surprise then that more people will test the waters of other faiths, or lack of faith, just as they may test the waters of living in a different culture. It seems increasingly easy to do, especially in a highly individual-centered culture. Trying a new career or a new life may be a challenge, but it might have the same motive as turning over in bed: the current position has become uncomfortable, and a new position becomes increasingly more alluring.</p>

<p>Some people may stay in their new culture, new career, new faith – their new way of life – and some may eventually return.</p>

<p>Either way they are forever changed, and hopefully for the better: hardened by experience and permanently viewing the world through a different lens.</p>

<p>Either way I think is better than not having ventured out at all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New direction (&#8220;Developer Blog&#8221; -> &#8220;Blog&#8221;)]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I’ve come to terms with the fact I need to try something new in my life – a true change in direction. I anticipate that this blog will take the same direction, so there will likely be less and less “developer” posts and more and more posts of me living this new path. (TLDR: unsubscribe now, probably!)</p>

<p>Why the change in direction? I’ve had my fun, I’ve lived a comfortable life where I really haven’t had to worry about money (yet), but I’ve learned the hard way that buying “stuff” doesn’t buy happiness. It’s trite and it’s something you always hear, but I guess it’s something you have to figure out for yourself, the hard way. I read Walden in high school and thought I’d learned from its lessons. But I re-read it recently and came away completely changed. I can get by with a lot less, and most importantly – with a more meaningful job that pays much less.</p>

<p>I’ve worked at a few big companies and become a somewhat competent (and surely incompetent in some ways) frontend web developer. It’s a great way to grow right out of college and a really comfortable way to live out on your own for a little while. It’s probably a way to continue making a living while supporting a family, but that hasn’t happened to me yet.</p>

<p>And in any case, it’s not for me.</p>

<p>At the end of the day I can’t really say I’ve made a real difference in the world. I can work as hard as I can, but at the end of the day I’m just making websites for entertainment. Which is not to say there aren’t good causes out there, I suppose. And it’s not to say I can’t funnel some of this money into good causes, which I’m been forcing myself to do more and more in very small ways (I seem to be a naturally selfish person, but I’m trying to get better in that respect). But I can’t get past the feeling that my time can be better spent.</p>

<p>Now’s a fantastic time for web development, with so many opportunities to learn and grow as a developer, and so many opportunities to publish new findings and pioneer new methods. There will be trailblazers and figureheads, and people making an awesome use of technology. But it won’t be me. I’m taking steps to make sure of that.</p>

<p>At one time I viewed my web development skill as simply a means to an end – and only within the past few years has it been considered what philosophers would call “an end in itself”. I picked up this hammer to learn how to build. For a few years I joined the company of some of the best hammersmiths in the world. I even attended hammersmith conferences. But now I’m resting this hammer down for a little bit of a rest.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
