<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Uncategorized | David Calhoun's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/uncategorized/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-30T12:17:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Google Bitch]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch"/>
    <updated>2013-09-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/the-google-bitch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I came back from Japan and accepted an offer to work at a startup in Silicon Valley, I knew one of the biggest challenges would be to find a decent and affordable apartment in Mountain View, close to where I’d be working. I had it all planned out, and how healthy and convenient it would be to walk to work and also Mountain View downtown!</p>

<p>Unfortunately, this dream was shared by me and hundreds of thousands of other like-minded software engineers. Which isn’t unexpected, really. If you spend enough time in Silicon Valley, everyone’s ideas start to sound the same after a while.</p>

<p>Mountain View, if you didn’t already know, is home to the now omnipresent non-evil company known as Google. Google has been fast taking over Mountain View, building by building, campus extension by campus extension. They even have their name on the sidewalks near where I take walks at work. Because they own those, too. (Actually, they own the fiber connections running beneath them).</p>

<p>One day I went out apartment hunting and was pretty happy the apartment listed earlier in the day hadn’t already sold, as had happened several times earlier (yes, there is THAT much competition).</p>

<p>As I drove up and approached the apartment, I noticed the unwelcoming stare of a single woman waiting outside the complex. She didn’t say anything, so I mentioned that she must be waiting for the apartment walk-through the same as myself. She acknowledged and then mentioned that “he was supposed to be here 15 minutes ago”, referring to the current tenant who was supposed to show up earlier for an apartment viewing.</p>

<p>I saw that she was pretty serious about maintaining that she was here first, and I cracked a joke about folks being cutthroat because of the competition or some such thing, to try to break the tension. I even said it with a smile, which is supposed to prompt at least a crack of a smile in any human capable of empathy. Sadly it had no effect on this poor emotionless woman. It was clear that she was all business.</p>

<p>It’s not dissimilar to the animal kingdom, really. She was just establishing her dominance by passively explaining that she was here before I was. Oh I see, so even if I wanted this place, I’d have no shot at it, because you were here first? I guess that’s what you have to do these days to ensure you get a place…</p>

<p>I hear it’s worse in “The City®” (San Francisco), and I’m not surprised really. The last time I was looking for apartments there, it was a crappy little studio apartment in a crappy part of town, with what looked like 20 people lined up ahead of me to put down a deposit. No thank you. Sometimes I think I’d rather live someplace in the country.</p>

<p>Alright, back to my apartment hunting story in Mountain View. I figured I might as well take a look at the place, since I’d taken the time to come by. Some other folks showed up and started waiting in the same spot, until finally the current tenant came by, apologized for the wait, and took us through the apartment.</p>

<p>To be honest, the apartment was nothing special. It was an older apartment that was part of a fourplex with families with kids on all sides. Not exactly a quiet place. Sure, there was nice lush greenery everywhere, and of course it was conveniently situated in Mountain View, but it was overall not exceptional. But in a bubble economy, the location is now sufficient to make anything special and worth the price.</p>

<p>I asked the current tenant about cable internet availability, and the single woman decided to use her God-given right to interrupt and respond: “The entire city of Mountain View has WiFi provided for free by Google”. Without missing a beat, she added some other talking points as if they were coming out of a pre-prepared handbook. It actually kind of sounded like someone reciting a memorized passage from the Bible. And there was a certain pride behind it, to give me a hint that I need not ask if she worked for the blasted company.</p>

<p>I didn’t know what to say other than, “Oh, that’s cool”. I really wasn’t prepared to deal with corporate shills on what had become an epic search for an apartment.</p>

<p>After looking around a bit more, I was the second to last person to talk to the owner and take an application. He was more than patient with me, but I noticed the very last person waiting in the shadows to talk to him was The Google Bitch. Dammit, so she had some scheme she was waiting to thrust on the poor guy.</p>

<p>As I walked away and went back to my car, still within earshot The Google Bitch made an offer to the guy: “So, I am prepared to put down money today to secure this apartment” she said confidently. The current tenant just said “Wow, ok” and they talked from there.</p>

<p>Needless to say, I never turned in the application, as it would’ve just been a waste of everyone’s time.</p>

<p>I have since settled into an apartment community in Sunnyvale, where I have been adopted by a very extended, loving Indian family. They sometimes give me funny looks when I walk through the complex, but it’s all good. Perhaps the farther from The Google Bitch and people like her, the better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourth of July letter to my government]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/fourth-of-july-letter-to-my-government</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(this is a copy of a letter which I’ve sent to various representatives in government)</p>

<p>As a concerned citizen, I know you understand that I must occasionally voice my concern through letters such as this. My hope is that you will honestly consider my claims and take action on my part. I honestly appreciate you taking your time to seriously consider this letter.</p>

<p>I’m writing to you today specifically in response to abuses by the NSA overstepping its bounds. Citizens of the United States and citizens of the world now know its private data is being indiscriminately collected, sifted through, and intruded upon by the NSA. These actions are clearly antithetical to our own Constitution and set a terrible precedent for the future of this country and the rest of the world.</p>

<p>Today is the Fourth of July. However, this Fourth of July is a bit different for me. Instead of setting off fireworks and spending time with my family, I am alone in Japan. Yet I am not alone in my concerns that my constitutional rights are being forced away from me.</p>

<p>As you well know, there are protests today in support of restoring the fourth amendment and against organizations such as the NSA which subvert our Constitution in the name of national security. I sincerely wish I could join these rallies, but I must show support by other means, such as through this letter. While I admit it would be interesting to protest the Japanese way, parked at a street intersection shouting my protests through a megaphone, it seems more effective for me to write directly to you. And to other people such as you who have the full time job of representing me and people like myself.</p>

<p>While the US has never been a perfect country, I know it’s had better times. I’m not the only one who believes our nation is now in a bad way. Yet I hope to do my small part to help fix some of these problems in my lifetime, in order to make America a better place for us all. Since we are both Americans, I hope we share this common interest.</p>

<p>My growing list of grievances is too much to list here, therefore I want to focus on recent revelations by whistleblowers such as Edward Snowden. This has been a tipping point for me and many fellow Americans, whom I hope have also been awoken from a dogmatic slumber.</p>

<p>Somewhat counterintuitively, as a result I’ve started to become more of a believer in America. Or rather, what America is intended to be. I’ve recently found myself reading more about the history of my country. I’ve become interested in politics, and for the first time in my life I’ve seriously considered joining a protest. I have become a better citizen in the hope for a better America.</p>

<p>President Obama and others in positions of power have defended these NSA spying programs, responding by explaining that they have come into effect through lawful means. Yet there has been massive public backlash, which I believe should at least warrant a reconsideration of these surveillance programs. I trust people like you to make sure this happens.</p>

<p>It’s worth mentioning that this hasn’t been the first time in recent years the great disconnect between the governed and the government has been exposed. Perhaps our representatives are not really representing our interests after all? The situation isn’t dissimilar to what culminated in the breaking off and founding of our nation in the first place.</p>

<p>It will be a great shame, but perhaps we are part of the generation which collectively allowed the great American experiment to fail?</p>

<p>Update (July 12, 2013):</p>

<p>I received a reply from one of my senators, Diane Fienstein. While it’s a generic reply sent to everyone sending letters similar to my own (http://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/nsa-programs), I appreciate some sort of response.</p>

<p>I’m still concerned however. Fienstein argued her case with the same defense as Obama: our repesentatives in the House and Senate voted these spying initiatives into law. Therefore it’s “legal” and was created and approved by people we voted into law.</p>

<p>This is supposed to dissuade my fears in some way, but it actually makes me more apprehensive. Where are the people in government that represent me and my fears? Where are the people in Congress to re-examine the work they’ve made of the Constitution?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSA&#8217;s PRISM: from the minds of conspiracy nuts, turns out to be reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2013/nsas-prism-from-the-minds-of-conspiracy-nuts-turns-out-to-be-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The real shame about NSA/PRISM is that everyone will forget about it next week or next month. Just like we forgot about Trapwire and other endless abuses in the name of protecting society.</p>

<p>The US is now a nation too mentally castrated to do anything about these obvious constitutional abuses. Why are we only capable of short-lived and impotent protest attempts like Occupy? How did we get to be so sedated through this anesthesia of modern consumerism and entertainment?</p>

<p>As of today, it’s no longer just a thought confined to the head of some crazy conspiracy theorist.</p>

<p>UPDATE:<br />
Today <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-22820711">President Obama defended the spy programs (cell phone and internet espionage)</a>, directly against <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6fnfVJzZT4">his campaign promises (video from 2007)</a>, in I suppose a true political fashion.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100828955847631">Facebook</a> and <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what.html">Google</a> CEOs appeared to have denied involvement using carefully constructed statements. One of the commenter’s on Mark Zuckerberg’s post made the observation that his is a carbon copy of Larry Page’s, which is indeed very strange.</p>

<p>Here’s the statements side-by-side, emphasis mine.</p>

<h3 id="part-1-introduction">Part 1: Introduction</h3>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0.25em 0 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what.html">Google&#8217;s Larry Page and David Drummond</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    Dear Google users—
  </p>
  
  <p>
    You may be aware of press reports alleging that Internet companies have joined a secret U.S. government program called PRISM to give the National Security Agency direct access to our servers. As Google&#8217;s CEO and Chief Legal Officer, we wanted you to have the facts.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100828955847631">Facebook&#8217;s Mark Zuckerberg</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    I want to respond personally to the outrageous press reports about PRISM:
  </p>
</blockquote>

<h3 style="clear:both; margin-top: 1em;">
  Part 2: Deny direct involvement with any government program
</h3>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0.25em 0 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what.html">Google</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    First, we have not joined any program that would give the U.S. government—or any other government—direct access to our servers. Indeed, the U.S. government does not have <b>direct access</b> or a &#8220;back door&#8221; to the information stored in our data centers. <b>We had not heard of a program called PRISM until yesterday</b>.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100828955847631">Facebook</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    Facebook is not and has never been part of any program to give the US or any other government <b>direct access to our servers</b>. We have never received a blanket request or court order from any government agency asking for information or metadata in bulk, like the one Verizon reportedly received. And if we did, we would fight it aggressively. <b>We hadn&#8217;t even heard of PRISM before yesterday</b>.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<h3 style="clear:both; margin-top: 1em;">
  Part 3: Emphasize that data given to the government is on a case-by-case basis and in compliance with the law
</h3>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0.25em 0 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what.html">Google</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    Second, we provide user data to governments only in accordance with the law. Our legal team <b>reviews each and every request</b>, and frequently pushes back when requests are overly broad or don&#8217;t follow the <b>correct process</b>. Press reports that suggest that Google is providing open-ended access to our users&#8217; data are false, period. Until this week&#8217;s reports, we had never heard of the broad type of order that Verizon received—an order that appears to have required them to hand over millions of users&#8217; call records. We were very surprised to learn that such broad orders exist. Any suggestion that Google is disclosing information about our users&#8217; Internet activity on such a scale is completely false.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100828955847631">Facebook</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    When governments ask Facebook for data, <b>we review each request</b> carefully to make sure they always follow the <b>correct processes</b> and all applicable laws, and then only provide the information if is required by law. We will continue fighting aggressively to keep your information safe and secure.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<h3 style="clear:both; margin-top: 1em;">
  Part 4: Recommend more government transparency
</h3>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0.25em 0 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what.html">Google</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    Finally, this episode confirms what we have long believed—there needs to be a more <b>transparent</b> approach. Google has worked hard, within the confines of the current laws, to be open about the data requests we receive. We post this information on our Transparency Report whenever possible. We were the first company to do this. And, of course, we understand that the U.S. and other governments need to take action to protect their citizens&#8217; safety—including sometimes by using surveillance. But the level of secrecy around the current legal procedures undermines the <b>freedoms we all cherish</b>.
  </p>
  
  <p>
    Posted by Larry Page, CEO and David Drummond, Chief Legal Officer
  </p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote style="width: 49%; float: left; margin: 1em 0;">
  <p>
    (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10100828955847631">Facebook</a>)
  </p>
  
  <p>
    We strongly encourage all governments to be much more <b>transparent</b> about all programs aimed at keeping the public safe. It&#8217;s the only way to protect everyone&#8217;s civil liberties and create the safe and <b>free society we all want</b> over the long term.
  </p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m not sure if this is conspiracy or just laziness, but I would guess the latter. Both responses have similar wording (which is admittedly sometimes unavoidable) and are organized in the same three-part format, with the same talking point for each section.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forms of Escapism]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking lately that the fates of so many are motivated by, in a word, escapism. Including my own fate. These are folks whose lives seem quite different on first glance, but turn out to be similar. We can’t escape some of our basic human nature after all.</p>

<h3 id="the-preservationist">The Preservationist</h3>

<p>These are folks who, for lack of a better term, wish to preserve a “simpler time”. They are people such as Thoreau, who wanted a return to simpler times and aspired to self-sufficiency (or an approximation, in any case). They are folks such as the Amish, who saw no good in the coming changes, and decided to create an ideal society in the form of a living time capsule.</p>

<p>I also think backpackers and wilderness-goers fit into this category. Their journeys may be temporary escapes from city life, but they are escapes nonetheless.</p>

<p>The Preservationists stand against progress, for various reasons. These folks are most easily labeled escapists: their main drive is motivated by a desire to escape the progress of the world.</p>

<h3 id="the-progressive">The Progressive</h3>

<p>Perhaps controversially, I think the folks on the other end of the spectrum can also be placed with escapists, maybe in a small way.</p>

<p>The folks pushing progress are not satisfied with the world as it is, but instead of abandoning it (as the Preservationists do), they seek to improve their world from within.</p>

<p>They seek to to escape from the present world by changing it. And perhaps we’ve all wanted to change the world at one point or another, perhaps while we were young, and surely a long whole before we accepted that comfortable desk job at The Company.</p>

<h3 id="the-traveler">The Traveler</h3>

<p>Travelers are easily escapists, but they are temporary escapists, of course. (The more “permanent travelers” are what we call expatriots.)</p>

<p>Travelers are not necessarily unsatisfied with their current curcumstances, but their main drive for adventure of course requires them to escape from their everday routine. Or perhaps they just need a vacation, or as we so often say, an escape.</p>

<p>The traveler gets to experience an idealized, whitewashed version of everyday routine in some other part of the world. The real routine, revealed with time, isn’t as pretty as it seems. However, this is not to deny that a routine in a part of the world might be better than a routine in some other part of the world.</p>

<p>Actually, this must necessarily be the case, as it seems ridiculous to say that daily life all over the world is equally suited to everyone.</p>

<h3 id="the-recluse">The Recluse</h3>

<p>Our present technology is bringing the world together in many ways, as well as enabling reclusive people to more successfully live a literally sheltered life. These folks are paradoxes – Thoreaus who live among us in cities, even if they are rarely seen.</p>

<p>It helps the Recluse that we can now work, bank, and shop for food entirely online, enabling people to stay inside longer than ever before. Technology designed to bring us closer together ironically has stifled real-life interaction, making all of us a little more distant.</p>

<p>Whatever bad things we may think about The Recluse, we have to remind ourselves that there’s a little bit of Recluse in all of us. Who hasn’t ever been exhausted and decided to spend a “lazy Sunday” indoors, never bothering to even get dressed?</p>

<h3 id="the-suicide">The Suicide</h3>

<p>I saved the worst for last – the most extreme escapist is surely the person who removes themselves violently from the world. Perhaps they have tried the other forms of escapism, and perhaps they haven’t. Perhaps they think they know the ways of the world and are weary of it. But perhaps they are mistaken, and haven’t yet tried living other lives.</p>

<p>I’ve also been world-weary. At various points in my life I’ve felt this way, but have always wanted to try for something better without wanting to give up. This is what I’d advise anyone who feels this way: your feeling is one of extreme escapism, but perhaps there are other ways to escape. Ways which are less violent. Ways which still allow you to contact your family and friends.</p>

<p>Suicide is such an extreme form of escape, but the reason I wrote this post is to show that these feelings of escapism are widespread, and that they need not result in an “ultimate escape”.</p>

<p>The drive to escape, in its various forms, is widespread. I think it’s part of what defines us as human. And these different ways of coping are what define us as individuals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The life of your parents&#8217; choosing]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several times I’ve heard the phrase “the religion of your parents’ choosing”, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.</p>

<p>How strange then not to carry this philosophy into more of our social behaviors. Why should we then avoid phrases such as “the culture/land of your parents’ choosing”?</p>

<p>It seems to me that this carries the same implications as religious belief. For instance, permenently moving to another country is in a sense turning one’s back on their upbringing and their whole social group. Of course this isn’t a total turning away: a person might return to one’s home country after many years, just as they might return to their faith after many years away.</p>

<p>Both of these moves seem only possible after exposure to different ways of thinking, something increasingly made possible as the modern world progresses. It should be of little surprise then that more people will test the waters of other faiths, or lack of faith, just as they may test the waters of living in a different culture. It seems increasingly easy to do, especially in a highly individual-centered culture. Trying a new career or a new life may be a challenge, but it might have the same motive as turning over in bed: the current position has become uncomfortable, and a new position becomes increasingly more alluring.</p>

<p>Some people may stay in their new culture, new career, new faith – their new way of life – and some may eventually return.</p>

<p>Either way they are forever changed, and hopefully for the better: hardened by experience and permanently viewing the world through a different lens.</p>

<p>Either way I think is better than not having ventured out at all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
