<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>japan on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in japan on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Spring in Kyoto Revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/video-spring-in-kyoto-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/video-spring-in-kyoto-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the HTML5 video tag.  A while back I posted an old video I made of Spring in Kyoto, but the audio track was removed by YouTube. So I&#39;m self-hosting it here now, and reposting to revisit the memories!
I really enjoy the atmosphere in this video, and I wish I made more videos like them. I used my Canon 7D for a lot of the video, but I wish it was shot in RAW video and on a tripod, as a lot of the detail was lost and a lot of the video ended up &amp;ldquo;wobbly&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plum Blossoms at Kitano Tenmangu Shrine in Kyoto, Japan (京都の北野天満宮)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/plum-blossoms-at-kitano-tenmangu-shrine-in-kyoto-japan-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E5%8C%97%E9%87%8E%E5%A4%A9%E6%BA%80%E5%AE%AE/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/plum-blossoms-at-kitano-tenmangu-shrine-in-kyoto-japan-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E5%8C%97%E9%87%8E%E5%A4%A9%E6%BA%80%E5%AE%AE/</guid>
      <description>The roof of the main shrine (拝殿) at Kitano Tenmangu.  Almost a year ago now I was lucky to be able to go back to my old stomping grounds in Kyoto, where I once studied Japanese in the hopes of maybe learning enough of the language to enroll in a university there to continue my studies in philosophy, perhaps being able to one day be another &amp;ldquo;professional&amp;rdquo; philosopher to walk along the Philosopher&amp;#39;s Path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2019)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</guid>
      <description>In many ways this has been a strange and wonderful year, probably my most favorite year of my life to date. I traveled to Japan on a great flight deal, I hiked more than 1100 miles of the Appalachian Trail, and I drove across the USA on two (!) cross-country road trips, the latter a wonderful solo trip where I took my time photographing and visiting wonderful parks and museums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo assignment: Kyoto alleyways at night</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:15:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/photo-assignment-kyoto-alleyways-at-night/</guid>
      <description>Before setting off on my current trip, I wanted to give myself at least one &amp;ldquo;photo assignment&amp;rdquo;: some goal I could aim to accomplish by pretending like I&#39;d been given an assignment by some employer.
This is the first of what I hope will be many. The assignment here is to try to capture the atmosphere of eastern Kyoto&#39;s traditional streets at night.
A couple of things I had to plan for: Kyoto is a bit far from my hostel in Osaka, so I made sure to make a day trip out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shinkansen trip from Kyoto to Sapporo</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 11:25:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/shinkansen-trip-from-kyoto-to-sapporo/</guid>
      <description>Rinku town and Kansai Airport at night  (I wrote this one a few weeks back but didn&#39;t post the pics until now, so here it is in its complete form!).
I&#39;ve been here in Japan for a month and in true form haven&#39;t provided much in the way of updates since then. Doh.
Here&#39;s a catch-up post, with plenty of pictures and videos to keep things interesting.
 Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy   Closeup of cherry blossoms along the Path of Philosophy  Spring in Japan again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monju-e Ceremony in Nara (文殊会 興福寺)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 22:34:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/monju-e-ceremony-in-nara-%E6%96%87%E6%AE%8A%E4%BC%9A-%E8%88%88%E7%A6%8F%E5%AF%BA/</guid>
      <description> From April 25, 2016.
Monju or Manjusri is a bodhisattva of wisdom. In this ceremony children’s healthy growth and academic success are prayed for.
14:30~ A procession of children in traditional costumes. Starts from Jyokyoji Temple on Sanjyo St. towards Kofukuji Temple.
15:00~ Ritual ceremony at Tokondo Hall in Kofukuji Temple
文殊会 (興福寺) 毎月25日は文殊菩薩の縁日。東金堂の文殊菩薩は古くから学問僧の信仰を集めてきた。­文殊会では文殊菩薩の智恵を授かろうと稚児の行列が、浄教寺より一字書の奉額車を引い­て三条通りを練り歩きます。 なお、当日堂内の拝観は14時までですが、外からの拝観は可能。（受付終了は13時4­5分）
                                                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan once again: update from the Banana House in Osaka</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again-update-from-the-banana-house-in-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 19:44:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/japan-once-again-update-from-the-banana-house-in-osaka/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been in Japan for the past few weeks, and have been lazy about updating my blog, which I promised to do! I&#39;ve been busy sorting through pictures!
Here&#39;s a video update from where I&#39;ll be staying long term at a place called the Banana House:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourist season in Japan, and a brief escape to Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 23:20:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/tourist-season-in-japan-and-a-brief-escape-to-cafe-rhinebeck-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>Inside Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan (Photo copyright David Calhoun)  (I originally wrote this while sitting in Cafe Rhinebeck in Kyoto, Japan)
I&#39;m visiting Japan again, when part of me is constantly thinking I should instead be spending the time and money exploring other parts of the world.
I guess I just find myself coming back to the familiar and (somewhat) comfortable. I find that I have the same habit when returning to a restaurant, and ordering the same item from the menu each and every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Spring in Kyoto (京都の春)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/video-spring-in-kyoto-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%98%A5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/video-spring-in-kyoto-%E4%BA%AC%E9%83%BD%E3%81%AE%E6%98%A5/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the HTML5 video tag. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan: from miniature train to bullet train</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2013/japan-from-miniature-train-to-bullet-train/</guid>
      <description>Japanese riding a miniature railroad, brought by Perry to Japan  (view the [full image][2], [image credit][1]) A long time ago, four black ships appeared off the coast of Japan, which had closed itself off from the world and its influences. These ships were from the US, and commanding them was Commodore Matthew C. Perry, who was instrumental in reopening Japan to the rest of the world.
As a result of this, and to promote a goodwill between the two countries, Perry gave various gifts to Japan, one of which was a one-fourth scale model train, in order to convincingly demonstrate the benefit of adopting Western technology:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>