<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: maui | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/maui/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-04T17:23:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-07T23:12:20-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/franksvalli/15026495731/"><img src="http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/milky-way-galaxyrise-from-maui-hawaii.jpg" alt="Milky Way galaxyrise from Maui (at the Mauian hotel)" width="1000" height="667" /></a></p>

<p>I was lucky enough to finally visit Hawaii with my parents.  Being experts Hawaii tourists, they set us up in a nice traditional resort called The Mauian - a nice quiet(er) little place that has a time for “quiet hours” (apparently the other resorts are places to party).</p>

<p>We got back to the hotel a little after quiet hours, and my folks mentioned that you could see the Milky Way quite clearly.  Being Hawaii, and Maui at that, there wasn’t a lot of light pollution like we’re used to.  I thought I better not miss the chance, and went and grabbed my 16-35mm f/2.8.</p>

<p>I didn’t bring any sort of a tripod on this trip, so I grabbed my spare pants and rolled them up a bit, then rested the camera on them.  Not too bad, actually.</p>

<p>The final settings: 16mm f/2.8, 4 seconds @ ISO 6400.  I was also sure to move to manual focus and set the focus at the sweet-spot (live view helps a bit here).</p>

<p>There was surprisingly little post-processing.  I added the usual tweaks to highlights and shadows and adjusted the black and white levels very slightly.  Added a bit of clarity and a bit of vibrance to bring out the colors.  This was at ISO 6400, so I added some noise reduction combined with some sharpening.</p>

<p>Recently I have been lusting after a nicer astrophotography lens, the 24mm f/1.4, but this photo I took with my existing gear mostly proved to me that I can make do with what I have.  Also, location matters the most.  You can’t get these kinds of shots from where I live without driving hundreds and hundreds of miles away.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
