<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>appalachian trail on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/appalachian-trail/</link>
    <description>Recent content in appalachian trail on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/appalachian-trail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Death on the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/thoughts-on-death-on-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/thoughts-on-death-on-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Dead tired, but not dead yet: resting my feet at Peter&amp;#39;s Mountain Shelter in Pennsylvania.  Why such a serious topic? Cheerful subject, right? This post has been a long time coming; I decided I wanted to write about this topic while I was still out hiking last year. More than a few things made me think of it:
  Thoughts of my grandma who had died a few years before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Eight on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later): Muddy</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-eight-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-muddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-eight-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-muddy/</guid>
      <description>Original entry        Misty trees along the Appalachian Trail near Biglerville, Pennsylvania  Yesterday was a little bit rainy and very muddy all through the day. After the marathon 19+ miles from the previous day, my feet were surprisingly ok, but my back started to give me a little pain through the day. Seemed to have been helped by simply shifting the weight of my pack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Seven on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later): Did you bring a gun?</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-seven-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-did-you-bring-a-gun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-seven-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-did-you-bring-a-gun/</guid>
      <description>Original entry: Are you afraid of the dark?        Amazing tunnel staircase. This must&amp;#39;ve taken quite some time to build...  This turned out to be the longest day so far - a distance of 19.6 miles between shelters (Tumbling Run to Birch Run shelters). I originally planned for the day to end 7.4 miles back at Quarry Gap shelters, but there was a huge boy scout troop there that had taken over the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Six on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later): Five-Star Shelter Accommodations at Tumbling Run Shelters</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-six-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-five-star-shelter-accommodations-at-tumbling-run-shelters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-six-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later-five-star-shelter-accommodations-at-tumbling-run-shelters/</guid>
      <description>Original entry        Appalachian Trail sign along a road near Waynesboro, Pennslyvania  (written the morning of 4/13 inside the Tumbling Run shelter)
Only did 8.5 miles today. Didn’t want to overdo it, and also didn’t want to hike in the rain today. Big thunderstorm passed through here last night.
       Tumbling Run shelters, the nicest shelters I experienced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Five on the Appalachian Trail (Zero Day) (One Year Later): Lazy Zero Day in Waynesboro, Pennsylvania</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-five-on-the-appalachian-trail-zero-day-one-year-later-lazy-zero-day-in-waynesboro-pennsylvania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-five-on-the-appalachian-trail-zero-day-one-year-later-lazy-zero-day-in-waynesboro-pennsylvania/</guid>
      <description>Original entry. Zero day in Waynesboro      Map of Foursquare checkins from the start of my hike in Harper&amp;#39;s Ferry, all the way to Waynesboro, Pennsylvania. You can really see the outline of the Appalachian Trail here!  Yesterday (April 10) turned out to be the longest trek so far, and much of that was just getting from the AT to my distant hotel. I haphazardly researched the distance from the trail and paid the price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Four on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-four-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-four-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</guid>
      <description>(Bear with me! I plan to recap day-by-day for the first 7 days of my hike. After that I will be writing highlights and also some short essays on subjects I thought of while hiking.)
Original Entry from April 10, 2019        Spectacular view from High Rock Overlook (marred by graffiti...). Really nothing like this again till I hit New Hampshire and Maine.  The fourth day - today - saw an even earlier start than normal at around 7am (the first morning I was super later, like 10am, then the second morning I left camp around 9am).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Three on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-three-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-three-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</guid>
      <description>Original entry from April 9, 2019        A pedestrian walkway taking hikers safely over I-70 (the same I-70 which will take you west all the way to Utah)  I can see how folks end up injured when they push themselves to go harder than they should. The third day out on the trail I was trying to get in enough miles which would make it possible for me to get into town the following day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two on the Appalachian Trail (One Year Later)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-two-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/day-two-on-the-appalachian-trail-one-year-later/</guid>
      <description>My original entry Second night
Dahlgren backpacker’s campsite was amazing! Flush toilets, free showers with hot and cold water. Luxury.
There is a nice restaurant nearby that I was looking forward to, but it was closed on Monday unfortunately. Tempted to stay here and rest, but I want to keep moving on.
The first here are amazing. Saw some deep red bird, almost tropical looking. Woodpeckers heard but not seen. The usual crows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year Ago Today I Started Hiking the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/a-year-ago-today-i-started-hiking-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/a-year-ago-today-i-started-hiking-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>The Appalachian Trail Conservancy (ATC) takes photos of all hikers passing through Harper&amp;#39;s Ferry, including folks like me who just started.  Introduction One year ago today I began a big journey which I have yet to finish: hiking the Appalachian Trail. I kept a diary along the way, mostly to remind myself of my thoughts and observations about each day, and also to give long-forgotten context to the many photos I took along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Life On And Off the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/real-life-on-and-off-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/real-life-on-and-off-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Black and white view of a bog boardwalk leading into a misty forest, along the Mahoosec Trail in New Hampshire.  My former coworker had hiked the Camino de Santiago, a long pilgrimage trail in Spain, and I told her I wanted to hike the Appalachian Trail and was looking for all the insight I could get. One thing she told me was that hiking was such a raw and real experience, something so different from our world steeped in the abstract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2019)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-year-in-photos-2019/</guid>
      <description>In many ways this has been a strange and wonderful year, probably my most favorite year of my life to date. I traveled to Japan on a great flight deal, I hiked more than 1100 miles of the Appalachian Trail, and I drove across the USA on two (!) cross-country road trips, the latter a wonderful solo trip where I took my time photographing and visiting wonderful parks and museums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Half Marathon: Hiking Half the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-half-marathon-hiking-half-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2019/my-half-marathon-hiking-half-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Mt Katahdin at the northern terminus of the Appalachian Trail in Maine  (note: all photos shot on my older iPhone 7)
Thank you! Thanks to everyone who helped me on my AT journey! Special thanks:
 to my mom for helping mail me resupply packages to my sister and her family for their support, small snacks, kids&amp;rsquo; drawings for support, and for liking some of my best picture uploads to my friends James and Jessica for the very generous care package which helped me get back on the trail after a month away to Gomer Pyle (John) and Sawbones (Sarah) who let me tag along with them and bought me too many meals, drinks, and even a book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>