<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Gratefulness</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/lessons-in-gratefulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/lessons-in-gratefulness/</guid>
      <description>We all have times in life when we were forced to learn lessons the hard way, often in situations where we were absolutely humbled. A lot of these happen early on in childhood, but even so, I find that there are some lessons I am still learning to this day. I am trying to improve, trying to get better constantly.
One of these childhood lessons for me was a year when my family was tight on money and was forced to combine Christmas with a mid-year back-to-school resupply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Death on the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/thoughts-on-death-on-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/thoughts-on-death-on-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Dead tired, but not dead yet: resting my feet at Peter&amp;#39;s Mountain Shelter in Pennsylvania.  Why such a serious topic? Cheerful subject, right? This post has been a long time coming; I decided I wanted to write about this topic while I was still out hiking last year. More than a few things made me think of it:
  Thoughts of my grandma who had died a few years before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Life On And Off the Appalachian Trail</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/real-life-on-and-off-the-appalachian-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2020/real-life-on-and-off-the-appalachian-trail/</guid>
      <description>Black and white view of a bog boardwalk leading into a misty forest, along the Mahoosec Trail in New Hampshire.  My former coworker had hiked the Camino de Santiago, a long pilgrimage trail in Spain, and I told her I wanted to hike the Appalachian Trail and was looking for all the insight I could get. One thing she told me was that hiking was such a raw and real experience, something so different from our world steeped in the abstract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behold the Birds of the Air (Soren Kierkegaard)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/behold-the-birds-of-the-air-soren-kierkegaard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 13:29:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/behold-the-birds-of-the-air-soren-kierkegaard/</guid>
      <description>From Soren Kierkegaard&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Upbuilding Discourses in Various Spirits&amp;rdquo;
(this excerpt is from Provocations, excerpts from Kierkegaard, Plough)
Once upon a time there was a wood dove. It had its nest in the fearsome forest, where wonder and apprehension dwelt together, among the erect, lonely trees. But nearby, where the smoke rises up from the farmer”s house, lived some tame doves. The wood dove would often meet a pair of these. He would sit on a branch that stretched out over the farmyard, not far from the two tame doves on the ridge of the roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stifling Laughter in Distant Places</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 20:10:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/</guid>
      <description>New Cultures The first days of traveling usually involves laughing at the quaint and unusual customs of another culture. That sounds close-minded, because in many cases it probably is. But it&amp;rsquo;s something we all do, of course including yours truly. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a coping mechanism - laughing at things in the face of difficulties and differences.
To be fair, we&amp;rsquo;re thinking creatures, and as such it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard for us not to draw comparisons with our own home city and culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning thoughts on the idea of a Great American Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 22:35:47 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2017/beginning-thoughts-on-the-idea-of-a-great-american-road-trip/</guid>
      <description>The idea of a trip across the United States has become somewhat of an American institution. Something like a New American Dream, this one maybe a bit more accessible than that house, happy life, and nuclear family with 2.5 kids. It&amp;rsquo;s something that is undertaken by both the young and the old, with the former perhaps hitchhiking or sleeping in their cars while the latter leapfrog between National Parks in their expensive and comfortable motor homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe it&#39;s healthier to embrace discomfort</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 09:35:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/maybe-its-healthier-to-embrace-discomfort/</guid>
      <description>Many folks, including yours truly, have had an unpleasant night, and this morning a bitter awakening at the announcement that our new President will be Trump. For most folks this comes as a shock, as we have all thought the chances of this happening were slim. Comedians chided him on and dared him to run. Even President Obama who continually roasted him at the White House Correspondents&#39; Dinner in 2011, arguably the defining moment when Trump became driven to run for President (&amp;ldquo;He certainly would bring some change to the White House&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quine and Heidegger: Against Reductionism</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 22:15:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/quine-and-heidegger-against-reductionism/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I had the opportunity to attend my first philosophy class in about a decade. The class was on the infamous philosopher Martin Heidegger, and the course was taught at Stanford University by Forrest Hartman (PHI 98: An Introduction to Martin Heidegger (Spring 2016)).
Heidegger is famous for being obscure and notoriously difficult to read, but I believe I made some headway in what turned out to be a very interesting philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:06:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-junk-politics-junk-tv-junk-body-junk-mind-junk-truth/</guid>
      <description>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to be bored with non-junk. We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways. We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarter-life crisis, third-life crisis, mid-life crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:32:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/quarter-life-crisis-third-life-crisis-mid-life-crisis/</guid>
      <description>Haleakala sunset   Andre: OK. Yes, we are bored. We&amp;rsquo;re all bored now. But has it ever occurred to you, Wally, that the process that creates this boredom that we see in the world now may very well be a self-perpetuating, unconscious form of brainwashing, created by a world totalitarian government based on money, and that all of this is much more dangerous than one thinks? And it&amp;rsquo;s not just a question of individual survival Wally, but that somebody who&amp;rsquo;s bored is asleep, and somebody who&amp;rsquo;s asleep will not say no?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existential nights</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:05:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/existential-nights/</guid>
      <description>These damn existential nights are the worst.
I&amp;rsquo;m tired of wasting my nights distracting myself, so I stayed at work late and went to the gym even later, then left around 10:45pm.
Even while exercising I could feel me asking myself nagging questions. Why am I working out? What&amp;rsquo;s the goal? What&amp;rsquo;s the point of keeping your body healthy if you don&amp;rsquo;t even know where you&amp;rsquo;re going?
These are important questions, but not the right questions when I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beatitudes</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:29:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted.
Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth.
Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied.
Blessed are the merciful, for they shall obtain mercy.
Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God.
Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living as driftwood</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 21:52:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two photo posts I wanted to avoid this sort of heavy reflection New Year post. But its time has finally come and it should be said, no matter how cheesy it may sound.
I have been living these last few years of my life as driftwood. At least professionally. I have all the makings of what should make me happy and successfully in my career, but it&amp;rsquo;s an illusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The City Is A Medium, The Medium Is The Message</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 19:11:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/</guid>
      <description>Vendors along Kamogawa River for the Tanabata (七夕) star festival in Kyoto (Photo by David Calhoun, 2011)  I had always heard of Marshall McCluhan&amp;rsquo;s famous &amp;ldquo;the medium is the message&amp;rdquo;, but really only had a surface level understanding of it until recently, when I first read the essay.
It&amp;rsquo;s a somewhat eye-opening and challenging piece for various reasons, because it challenges some things I thought I had a good grasp of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forms of Escapism</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/forms-of-escapism/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking lately that the fates of so many are motivated by, in a word, escapism. Including my own fate. These are folks whose lives seem quite different on first glance, but turn out to be similar. We can&amp;rsquo;t escape some of our basic human nature after all.
The Preservationist These are folks who, for lack of a better term, wish to preserve a &amp;ldquo;simpler time&amp;rdquo;. They are people such as Thoreau, who wanted a return to simpler times and aspired to self-sufficiency (or an approximation, in any case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A theory of leisure time, choice, and happiness</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/a-theory-of-leisure-time-choice-and-happiness/</guid>
      <description>This is finally the end of my first week in Japanese language school here in Kyoto. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a long week, with the most studying I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done in my life. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone through nine chapters in a week, and just Friday received two more books for learning Kanji. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn our first 50 Kanji in a week, alongside the rest of our classes. I already know some words here and there, but for the most part, much of what we&amp;rsquo;ve just learned is a blur, which is forcing me to use almost all of my free time in running to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descartes on building software frameworks</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/descartes-on-building-software-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/descartes-on-building-software-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>Rene Descartes  Years ago I read Descartes&amp;rsquo;s Discourse on Method for what I found to be some of the more interesting philosophy courses of my college career: those of the history of modern philosophy. Modern philosophy technically starts with Descartes, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good place to start, or to get re-acquainted with philosophy in general.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading through the Discourse again, and have found it to be more interesting and relatable this time around (particularly about lessons learned while traveling, but that&amp;rsquo;s a topic for another post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The life of your parents&#39; choosing</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/the-life-of-your-parents-choosing/</guid>
      <description>Several times I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;the religion of your parents&#39; choosing&amp;rdquo;, used to scoff at adherents to various religions, as if they had no intelligent choice in the matter of their own beliefs. As the thought goes, religious standing (or lack thereof) should be a personal matter, one to be decided rationally (yes, there is such a thing as rational faith; to say otherwise is to label all religious people as fideists, which is a mistake) by individuals, apart from their social group if possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New direction (Developer Blog to Blog)</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/new-direction-developer-blog-to-blog/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve come to terms with the fact I need to try something new in my life - a true change in direction. I anticipate that this blog will take the same direction, so there will likely be less and less &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; posts and more and more posts of me living this new path. (TLDR: unsubscribe now, probably!)
Why the change in direction? I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived a comfortable life where I really haven&amp;rsquo;t had to worry about money (yet), but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned the hard way that buying &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t buy happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Philosophy still important?</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/why-is-philosophy-still-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2012/why-is-philosophy-still-important/</guid>
      <description>This was posted on reddit recently, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d copy my response here.
First, just a quick introduction! There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of thought recently that philosophy is useless. The main arguments seem to be that
 science has replaced any need for philosophy philosophy is a useless subject to study in college  For the latter argument, I recently recorded my thoughts, and you can hear them here. For the first argument, read on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web development, Silicon Valley rant</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/web-development-silicon-valley-rant/</guid>
      <description>(if you didn&amp;rsquo;t read the title - warning: rant&amp;hellip;)
As far as web development goes, I guess I could rant on and on about the generalities. Of all things ephemeral. The lust after money, gadgets, and other worthless material crap that we use to stuff inside our oversized houses.
The startling creativity and in equal amounts the lack of creativity. The amount of amazing invention and the equal amount of copying and ripping off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On professional self-worth</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/on-professional-self-worth/</guid>
      <description>Huge huge rant incoming, but all is not said and done, and much is open for debate of course. Counterpoints and criticisms are more than welcome in the comments. This is just my opinion based on my experience at this point in time.
Self-worth: the rich man and the poor man For a long while there have been places in the world that view self-worth as largely tied to wealth. No doubt there is more than just money, as even within the rich community there&amp;rsquo;s a distinction between the established rich and the &amp;ldquo;nouveau riche&amp;rdquo;, or the newly rich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving yourself as a programmer versus as a human being</title>
      <link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/improving-yourself-as-a-programmer-versus-as-a-human-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2011/improving-yourself-as-a-programmer-versus-as-a-human-being/</guid>
      <description>(OR &amp;ldquo;The Post In Which I Conflate Programming and Philosophy&amp;rdquo; OR &amp;ldquo;The Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Existentialist Crisis&amp;rdquo;)
I woke up this morning to read Dmitry A. Soshnikov&amp;rsquo;s tweet:

While this seems like good advice for aspiring programmers, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think what this means for those who will buy into this. Us programmers have a keen ability to sit and focus on problems for extended periods of time, usually to the detriment of everything else around us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
