<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yosemite on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/tags/yosemite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yosemite on David Calhoun&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidbcalhoun.com/tags/yosemite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My year in photos (2016)</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:17:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/my-year-in-photos-2016/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I put together my favorite photos of the year (see it: part one and part two). I decided to resurrect the tradition, and I hope to keep it going in the coming years!
Onto the pics!
February I visited Yosemite twice, first by myself and later with my friend Kevin.
Night sky from Yosemite  For this shot I drove to the empty Bridalveil Falls parking lot and placed an LED lantern in the middle of the parking lot, then shot straight up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee That Made the UFO Dance</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 19:05:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-coffee-that-made-the-ufo-dance/</guid>
      <description>Milky Way over the trees, seem from Yosemite Valley around 3am  Last night I attended an impromptu star party in Yosemite attended by only one person total. The sky was really clear, and the Milky Way was very easy to see with camera and the eye.
While taking some photos around 3:30am or so, I saw a bright satellite trawl across the sky. It was quite bright - maybe an Iridium flare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A ride on Yosemite&#39;s Sugar Pine Railroad</title>
      <link>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 21:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/a-ride-on-yosemites-sugar-pine-railroad/</guid>
      <description>Front view of the Sugar Pine Railroad  On my last trip to Yosemite, I tagged along with my friends Kevin and Mari. The first day we hiked in rain to the base of Upper Yosemite Falls. By the second day, we were tired and looking for something quick and relaxing to do before driving back.
We decided to check out the Sugar Pine Railroad, which was right next to their hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>