<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Washington Dc on David Calhoun's blog</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/washington-dc/</link><description>Recent content in Washington Dc on David Calhoun's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/tags/washington-dc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My year in photos (2023)</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2023/my-year-in-photos-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2023/my-year-in-photos-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>2023 has been a stressful and hard year, and I have a sneaking suspicion this is a preview of even harder years on my path ahead. I am finding myself more tired and having really poor sleep quality, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I see things improving but I am cautiously optimisitic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to keep positive by remembering my blessings as best I can, and this year came with a lot of blessings for sure. This post I do yearly forces me to acknowledge those blessings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My year in photos (2021)</title><link>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/my-year-in-photos-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.davidbcalhoun.com/2021/my-year-in-photos-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Despite the continuing COVID-19 pandemic this year, I am grateful I was able to travel a bit. Two separate flights to California and a few road trips. While trying to keep as safe as possible, and being lucky so far not to have symptoms of COVID over this two year period (at the moment anyway&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my favorite hiking spots this year was the Williamson Preserve, which is a long path of hiking and biking trails that was recently converted from farmland. In the summertime the crews there planted a ton of flowers which attracted so many large butterflies. On one of my hikes this area was swarming with Eastern Tiger Swallowtails, along with a lot of bees. Pollinators&amp;rsquo; paradise!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>