<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rant | David Calhoun]]></title>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/blog/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-04T17:23:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Calhoun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stifling Laughter in Distant Places]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-09T20:10:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2017/stifling-laughter-in-distant-places</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="new-cultures">New Cultures</h3>

<p>The first days of traveling usually involves laughing at the quaint and unusual customs of another culture.  That sounds close-minded, because in many cases it probably is.  But it’s something we all do, of course including yours truly.  Maybe it’s a coping mechanism - laughing at things in the face of difficulties and differences.</p>

<p>To be fair, we’re thinking creatures, and as such it’s pretty hard for us not to draw comparisons with our own home city and culture.  Especially when we spot things that we consider outdated in our own culture.  Our reaction may be disgust (“Fax machines?!  Didn’t those go extinct in the 90s?!”) or nostalgia (“Ahh decent customer service - it’s been way too long”).</p>

<p>After one or two weeks, and we may still be poking fun at the quirks of our temporarily home.  But this changes when we settle in for the long term.  Weeks turn to months, and the funny quirks become more visible, in just the same way as quirks of spouses are discovered, as we’re forced to live with them each day.  Laughter at those quirks can turn to annoyance, and not far beyond that is outright hatred.</p>

<h3 id="the-marriage-analogy">The Marriage Analogy</h3>

<p>I don’t think the marriage analogy is too much of a stretch - living in a city can almost be like being married (though I can only guess): each day venturing out from our beds we have to confront the city or the spouse daily, and encounter both the good and the bad just to get through with the day.  At least with cities we can escape into our own rooms and private spaces.  But with marriage there is often no room to escape to, except maybe the bathroom.  This may explain why men sometimes spend so long in these very private places…</p>

<p>In a relationship, some of the personal quirks we discover are at first quaint, but our attitude can soon progress to annoyance, or worse.  If we’re unable to tolerate the quirks, our hatred can soon multiply and be reason for divorce. Or on the other end of the analogy: emigration from the city.  Us leaving the city is sort of like a break up or divorce.</p>

<p>I’m not sure about what you think, but I think this progression from laughter to annoyance to hatred doesn’t seem too productive.  What if we try to go down a quite different path, one which doesn’t start with laughter and disdain?  Maybe this path will take us to a better place.</p>

<p>At the very least, outright laughter at foreign customs does seem to be a sort of childlike reaction, because it’s unskilled: it’s basically a quick judgement and unrestrained laughter.</p>

<h3 id="people-do-things-differently--and-thats-usually-ok">People Do Things Differently.  And That’s (usually) OK.</h3>

<p>It reminds me of the scene in To Kill A Mockingbird where a poor boy is invited to the Finch household.  At breakfast, the poor kid steeps his entire breakfast in syrup, much to the disgust of the Finch girl.  She starts to react, but Atticus, the father, calmly quiets her.  His reaction at “foreign” customs is more mature - he doesn’t laugh, but instead looks past the poor boy making all his food soggy with syrup.  The boy is a guest, and what’s more, the moral of the whole story is tolerance of different folks and their ways.  Atticus is the hero of the story, and the one who sets an example for his daughter.  And for us.</p>

<p>In our travels we’ll often come across things that seem backwards in some way on first appearance.  And it may go deeper than appearance - many of these things may turn out to actually be very backwards.  But it helps me to try to have patience, to suspend judgement and give the benefit of a doubt.  For instance, Japan has an unusually rigid culture with a structured way of doing things, even small things such as opening small packages of food by pulling the correct tabs on the packaging.  In the correct order.  To do otherwise is simply incorrect.  After being corrected constantly on tiny little ways I was doing things wrong, I started to go mad.  My initial reaction was wanting to rebel, to do things my own way.  I think this approach still has merit, if we have the right attitude towards it.</p>

<p>It helps to remind myself that there’s a structure in the culture for a reason, because it’s worked well for decades (or maybe centuries), and while there may be better ways, this way is the way this culture works best.  It’s pragmatic.  It may change over time, but for the moment this is the smoothest way for everything to harmonize.</p>

<p>But you aren’t part of that culture, so you may very well find more efficient ways to do things.  Perhaps you’ll bypass the tabs on the food packaging and take some scissors to the whole thing, ignoring the instructions.  I think that’s fine - finding a way that works for you.  Just don’t laugh at other folks for doing things differently.  Though conversely, the natives will probably laugh at you and try to constantly correct you.  I guess you’ll have to get used to it.</p>

<h3 id="your-options">Your Options</h3>

<p>As a foreigner you have a few options:</p>

<p>-adopt the ways of the culture and love it<br />
-adopt the ways of the culture, but secretly hate it and resent it<br />
-do things your own way, and tolerate the other ways<br />
-do things your own way, and secretly hate and resent the other ways</p>

<p>Which of these works best?  I guess you can experiment for yourself and draw your own conclusions!  Judge for yourself!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junk Food, Junk Politics, Junk TV, Junk Body, Junk Mind, Junk Truth]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-politics-tv-body-mind-truth/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-13T17:06:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2016/junk-food-politics-tv-body-mind-truth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We Americans believe we have a right to be the way we want to be, which includes being lazy physically and intellectually. Junk is more shiny and more entertaining than non-junk, after all, and we can’t be bothered to be bored with non-junk.  We now have many forms of poison that we unwittingly ingest in various ways.  We have created in many ways our own version of the gladiator games that the masses celebrated through the downfall of Rome.</p>

<p>We are attracted to politicians for their image over all else. Never mind the arguments, or the truth which all politicians unabashedly lay claim to.  Did they speak in a confident way at the last debate? That’s what I really care about.  Because confidence is what we really need in a leader, over all else. Did they provide nice entertaining zingers in rebuttal to their opponent?  Because those witty one-liners are what we need to lead the free world.</p>

<p>Did someone sniffle during the last debate? Did someone stumble over their words? Did someone physically stumble and need help getting into their van?  Did Mr. Funny Man With A Funny Name ask a question at the debate?  I forgot what question he asked, or what the answers were.  What brand was his sweater?  I’d like to wear it this Halloween so I can poke fun at people who don’t appear super polished on TV.  These are the things that really matter.</p>

<p>This is no doubt the era of image politics, not issue politics (arguably this has been happening since the Kennedy-Nixon debates…).</p>

<p>Just like junk image politics, junk TV is more entertaining than non-junk TV, and we are attracted to it like flies to garbage. Cable TV has become a cesspool, and not coincidentally. Networks have found what people are attracted to, and maximized its airing time in order to maximize viewers.  Create masses of junk, and people will flock to it.</p>

<p>And food!  We are attracted to junk food, and not just snacks - even junk added to our main meals. I would argue that the staple food of the US is now sugar. It’s in everything. We eat it with abandon and oftentimes unknowingly. Without regard for long-term effects and without regard for how it affects our bodies and minds.</p>

<p>Because we have a God-given American right to eat what we want, just like our forefathers intended.  George Washington would be proud that I ate a fruit rollup for breakfast, followed by two burgers for lunch.</p>

<p>And we defend our body images in all shapes and sizes, because we have a right to it, dammit.  And we are beautiful and healthy regardless of what anyone says. I have a right to live my life the way I want to, without regard for what anyone else says. That’s the American Way©, after all (copyrighted by North American Coca-Cola).</p>

<p>We defend our version of the truth, because we have a God-given right to it. I have a right to believe what I want to. It’s the American Way to live my life and believe what I want to.  If you question or challenge me, you are attacking my very way of life.  And that’s super unamerican.</p>

<p>We defend the position of our in-group, and anything said against that position is an attack on the in-group itself. We have a right to our position, and it’s more important to show confidence and unwavering commitment to that position than to show hesitancy and a wavering opinion.  And we like to blast our politicians for waffling on positions, never thinking that maybe it’s healthy to reassess beliefs over time.  I’m gonna stick to my guns on this one.</p>

<p>America is undoubtedly in a decline.</p>

<p>And we have a God-given right to be in decline, dammit!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The surprising benefits of going to the gym]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T21:40:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/the-surprising-benefits-of-going-to-the-gym</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s well into the new year, and I didn’t exactly start the new year off like everyone else, who I imagine all rushed daily into the gym in the first week or two, then apparently gave the habit up soon after.</p>

<p>Sometime in February I found out about a study being conducted at my workplace in conjunction with a university, to track the effects of exercise over the course of a month.  As an extra benefit, I get paid a decent chunk of virtual money into my Google wallet every time I visit a gym in the month of March, during the weekdays.</p>

<p>Now that the study is finally starting, I’m already in the habit of going to the gym and I actually look forward to it.  I actually feel good, and I love the feeling of comign out of the gym and feeling the cool air at night around campus.  For a few minutes I even enjoyed a little stream just outside the gym.</p>

<p>Never thought I’d much like the gym, but I like getting in the habit of going.  It always makes me feel good, and may be a bit of a ward against depression, or at least thoughts I can’t trust.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living as driftwood]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T21:52:23-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2015/living-as-driftwood</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the previous two photo posts I wanted to avoid this sort of heavy reflection New Year post.  But its time has finally come and it should be said, no matter how cheesy it may sound.</p>

<p>I have been living these last few years of my life as driftwood.  At least professionally.  I have all the makings of what should make me happy and successfully in my career, but it’s an illusion.  I am an imposter.  I am living a life as professional driftwood.</p>

<p>What I mean is this: previously I was very active in trying to establish my career as a web developer.  I read as much as I could, practiced as much as I could, and constantly tried to learn new things that would make me better.</p>

<p>I am living what society calls a good life, but I don’t know myself what a good life really is.  I’m sure it’s not this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The City Is A Medium, The Medium Is The Message]]></title>
    <link href="http://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T19:11:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://davidbcalhoun.com/2014/the-city-is-a-medium-the-medium-is-the-message</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% imgcap left half http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/kyoto-tanabata-%e4%b8%83%e5%a4%95-star-festival-kamogawa.jpg 1000 666 Vendors along Kamogawa River for the Tanabata (七夕) star festival in Kyoto (Photo by David Calhoun, 2011)  %}</p>

<p>I had always heard of Marshall McCluhan’s famous “the medium is the message”, but really only had a surface level understanding of it until recently, when I first read the essay.</p>

<p>It’s a somewhat eye-opening and challenging piece for various reasons, because it challenges some things I thought I had a good grasp of.  Particularly the repeated shooting-down in the essay of people who claim it’s how the medium is used that matters, not the medium itself.  McCluhan disagrees with this by constantly impressing upon the reader not only that the medium and content are inseparable and come as a whole package, but that there is really no distinction to be made between content and medium.  It’s one medium nicely packaged in another medium.  This is the meaning of “the medium is the message”.</p>

<p>And could we go on?  That one medium could be packaged in another, which is itself packaged in yet another medium?  This certainly doesn’t seem unreasonable, as at one point in the essay it’s argued that speech is a medium for writing, which is yet another medium: the medium for inner thoughts.  Record someone on television giving a speech and you add yet another level.  It’s really mediums all the way down.</p>

<p>The original essay was written on the cusp of the digital information age, and had a concern with the medium of writing getting surpassed by print, which in turn seemed to be getting surpassed by television, radio, and digital information.  Though at times it might seem luddite, anti-television or anti-new-mediums, especially towards the end of the essay, I don’t see that as the intent of the article.  The end of the article was just trying to hit home a point that these mediums have become human appendages, consciously and subconsciously, and they are inescapable.  For better or worse.  The point is that if the mediums are only subconscious, then they influence us and trap us in invisible prisons.  By making us conscious of mediums we can study them and at least try to understand them better than we could at the subconscious level.</p>

<p>More than fifty years after the article was written, we are well into the digital information age, and we are starting to see the Internet surpass television.  The timelessness of The Medium is The Message is that these same insights can be used to understand the pervasiveness of the Internet medium all around us today.  Another important message here was that these mediums pervade and influence culture - just as the printing press played a crucial role in the French Revolution.  And often times we don’t realize these mediums as playing such a pervasive role until after the fact.</p>

<p>Smart phones have just recently invaded our society in our public and personal lives.  Our societies have already been substantially changed and molded by this new medium, and yet only now do we start asking ourselves questions like “is it bad to use my phone too much?”, “is it bad manners to use a phone at the dinner table?”, “is it ok to give a phone to a kid?”.</p>

<p>I’d made assumptions before that the blog posts I write on my website are content-first, so I’ve made an effort to remove any designs or parts of this medium that is distracting to that content.  Hence the super minimalist design I have in place currently.  But I never considered that there are parts of this presentation medium that can’t be sidestepped and avoided.</p>

<p>I had thought that maybe some of my blog posts could be printed and still retain the same message.  However, according to McCluhan this would be impossible, since the medium is married to the message (not to mention that the message is actually just another medium).  On this view the reader’s experience of reading my blog post on their laptop or desktop is an entirely different experience from reading on their phone, in an altogether different environment and in different circumstances (e.g. at home versus riding the train).</p>

<p>{% imgcap left half http://davidbcalhoun.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/kyoto-downtown.jpg 1000 673 Kyoto’s downtown (Photo by David Calhoun, 2011)  %}</p>

<p>It seems that we can take this even further, to its natural extent.  It seems that every city has a different overall culture and a different feel.  In that sense a city and its people can be assumed to be a sort of very large medium.  A person reading a news article in one city could be reading the same article as a person in a different city.  It seems not unreasonable that their experiences could be very different because their very environment - their city - permeates their experiences.  A city itself as a medium can then help ideas flourish (in a zeitgeist sort of way) or can even stifle ideas.</p>

<p>A city can very well itself be a medium.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
